<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--
  ~ Copyright 2005-2014 The Kuali Foundation
  ~
  ~ Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  ~ you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~
  ~ http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php
  ~
  ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  ~ distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  ~ WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  ~ See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  ~ limitations under the License.
  -->
<chapter xml:id="security" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
  <title>Security</title>
  <section>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>The purpose of this functionality is to provide security within the request binding
      process and controller invocation.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Model Binding</title>
    <para>Request parameters are bound to model (form) properties based on property security levels.
      These levels indicate when a property can be updated.</para>
    <section>
      <title>Default Security Level - View</title>
      <para>The default security level for model properties is based on view metadata. That is, the
        property will only be updated if contained in view configuration that requires updating.
        This includes:<itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Input Field Property Name - If the property name is associated with an input
              field</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Quickfinder Field Conversion - If the property name is listed as a return field of
              a quickfinder, the value will be updated when returning from that lookup</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Action Additional Submit Data - If the property name is listed in the
              additionalSubmitData property for an action</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Data Field Additional Hiddens - If the property name is listed in the
              additionalHiddenPropertyNames property for Data Field</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>User Control Principal Id - Property name mapped to the user control principal id
              hidden</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Collection Group Property Name - If the property name is associated with a
              collection group, the collection items will be updated (add or delete). Individual
              properties in the collection item must meet one of the other requirements.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
      <para>Note in all these cases, the component must be rendered, not hidden, and not read-only
        (where applicable). These settings in turn can depend on code and KIM permissions.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Accessible Security Level</title>
      <para>Model properties may contain the annotation <emphasis role="bold"
          >@RequestAccessible</emphasis> to indicate their values can be updated by request
        parameters. This would allow updates regardless of view configuration. The annotation may be
        placed on a data object to grant access to all nested properties (unless they contain a
        request protected annotation).</para>
      <para>If a property is not within the view configuration (or in the view configuration but
        doesn't meet one of the conditions above), this annotation may be needed to allow binding.
        For example, the application may have custom script that pass request parameters which
        should update model (form) properties. <emphasis role="bold">In addition, since view post
          data is only available for POST requests, any properties that need binding on GET requests
          must have this annotation. </emphasis>The annotation may also include a <emphasis
          role="bold">method</emphasis> value that restricts access depending on the HTTP request
        method (for example GET).</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Protected Security Level</title>
      <para>Model properties may contain the annotation <emphasis role="bold"
          >@RequestProtected</emphasis> to indicate their values cannot be updated by request
        parameters. This would disallow updates regardless of view configuration. Note the
        annotation maybe be placed on a data object to deny access to all nested properties (unless
        they contain a request accessible annotation).</para>
      <para>If the property name is within the view configuration and meets one of the conditions
        above, this annotation will be needed to prevent updating. For example, you might have a
        hidden which is needed for script, but you don't want that value to be updated. </para>
      <note><title>Binding Access Errors</title>
        <para>When a request parameter is present for a property whose binding access is protected,
        the value will not be populated. In addition, a debug message will be written and the
        property name added to supressedFields in the binding result. The request will continue as
        usual, and applications can deal further with the binding result if needed.</para></note>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Example</emphasis>
        <programlisting>public class TravelForm extends UifFormBase {
 
  // view security level
  private String firstName;
 
  // view security level
  private String lastName;
 
  @RequestProtected
  private String travelSequenceId;
 
  @RequestAccessible
  private boolean updateFlag;
 
  @RequestProtected
  private TaxInfo taxInfo;
 
  @RequestAccessible(method=RequestMethod.GET)
  private boolean copy;
 
}</programlisting>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Controller Method Binding</title>
    <para>Security will be implemented within the UIF to verify the user has access to invoke the
      controller method requested. Method access will be granted based on the following.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Security Level - View</emphasis><itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Action Method To Call - If method is configured as the method to call for a view
            action</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Component Method To Call on Refresh - If method is configured as the method to call
            on refresh for a component</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist></para>
    <para>Note in all these cases, the component must be rendered, not hidden, and not read-only
      (where applicable). These settings in turn can depend on code and KIM permissions.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Accessible Security Level</emphasis></para>
    <para>Controller methods may contain the annotation <emphasis role="bold"
        >@MethodAccessible</emphasis> to indicate they can be invoked regardless of the view
      configuration.</para>
    <para>Since view actions only cover posts, all methods that can be invoked in a GET
      request must have the @MethodAccessible annotation. The default start method of
      UifControllerBase (and GET methods for other framework controllers) will have this annotation
      already. In addition, any methods invoked with custom script will need this annotation.</para>
    <para>Spring's RequestMapping annotation can sldo be used to restrict method access for Http
      request types (GET, POST) and other request attributes.</para>
    <note><title>Method Access Errors</title><para>When a controller method is requested whose access is protected,
      the request will end and the user will be redirected to the incident report page.</para></note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Use Screen</title>
    <para>Use Screen is a KIM permission template of the KNS that restricted controller access.
      Access is restricted for an entire module by just specifying the namespace (in permissions
      details), or a particular controller by specifying the action class. In KRAD, the default
      security level requires a valid action component (which can then depend on permissions). So
      this is only be needed to restrict access (based on user) for those controller methods
      annotated with <emphasis role="bold">@RequestAccessible</emphasis>. </para>
    <para>This permission differs from the Open View permission which can be used to restrict any
      view (or screen) since it prevents someone form invoking a controller method they should not
      have access to (which might indirectly prevent them from accessing a screen). </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Edit Modes</title>
    <para>Edit Modes is a type of security that uses the 'viewId' and an 'editMode' to control screen rendering and other aspects of the
      user interface.</para>
    <para>Each View object has an associated ViewPresentationController and ViewAuthorizer interface objects. During the apply model phase of the view
      life cycle these objects are used for permission checking. The ViewPresentationController is typically where a set of editModes are determined by looking
      at the state of the model. The ViewAuthorizer then checks this set of editModes against KIM looking to see if the user has the correct
      permission for that 'viewId' and 'editMode' combination. Here is a portion of the code from ViewLifecycleBuild class:
      <programlisting>
    protected void runApplyModelPhase() {
        ViewLifecycleProcessor processor = ViewLifecycle.getProcessor();

        View view = ViewLifecycle.getView();
        ViewHelperService helper = ViewLifecycle.getHelper();
        UifFormBase model = (UifFormBase) ViewLifecycle.getModel();

...

        // get action flag and edit modes from authorizer/presentation controller
        helper.retrieveEditModesAndActionFlags();

...

        processor.performPhase(LifecyclePhaseFactory.applyModel(view, model, "", refreshPaths));
    }        
      </programlisting>
      and this is from the ViewHelperServiceImpl class:
      <programlisting>
    public void retrieveEditModesAndActionFlags() {
        View view = ViewLifecycle.getView();
        UifFormBase model = (UifFormBase) ViewLifecycle.getModel();
        ViewPresentationController presentationController = view.getPresentationController();
        ViewAuthorizer authorizer = view.getAuthorizer();

        Set&lt;String> actionFlags = presentationController.getActionFlags(view, model);
        Set&lt;String> editModes = presentationController.getEditModes(view, model);

        // if user session is not established cannot invoke authorizer
        if (GlobalVariables.getUserSession() != null) {
            Person user = GlobalVariables.getUserSession().getPerson();

            actionFlags = authorizer.getActionFlags(view, model, user, actionFlags);
            editModes = authorizer.getEditModes(view, model, user, editModes);
        }

        view.setActionFlags(new BooleanMap(actionFlags));
        view.setEditModes(new BooleanMap(editModes));
    }      </programlisting>
      Here you can see the ViewPresentationController being called to get the editModes and then the ViewAuthorizer to check this set. Finally the editModes
      are set on the view itself.</para>
    <para>The ViewPresentationController getEditModes method is called with the view and model passed in as parameters. An application would implement this
      interface to return a set of application specific editMode strings.</para>
    <para>Here is an example of defining a component to use the application specific editMode of 'superUser' for the rendering of a Uif-VerticalBoxSection:
      <programlisting>
  &lt;bean id="View1" parent="Uif-FormView" p:enterKeyAction="@DEFAULT">
    &lt;property name="headerText" value="Sample View"/>
    &lt;property name="singlePageView" value="true"/>
    &lt;property name="page">
      &lt;bean parent="Uif-Page">
        &lt;property name="items">
          &lt;list>
            &lt;bean p:headerText="Section 1" parent="Uif-VerticalBoxSection" p:render="@{#editModes['superUser']}">
              &lt;property name="items">
                &lt;list>
                  &lt;bean parent="Uif-InputField" p:propertyName="inputField12" p:label="Field 1"/>
                  &lt;bean parent="Uif-InputField" p:propertyName="inputField13" p:label="Field 2"/>
                  &lt;bean parent="Uif-PrimaryActionButton" p:actionLabel="button 1" p:id="button1" p:actionScript="alert('button 1');"/>
                &lt;/list>
              &lt;/property>
            &lt;/bean>
      </programlisting>
    </para>
    <para>Once this is done a permission can be created using the 'KR-KRAD:Use View' template for this 'viewId' and 'editMode'. This permission is then
      added to a role which is then assigned to a user:
      <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD_Guide/editModePermission.png" align="center"></imagedata></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>
      Note that the absence of a permission with the corresponding 'viewId' and 'editMode' will result in a 'true' result.</para>
  </section>
  
</chapter>
