<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<chapter xml:id="UG_KEN" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>KEN</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Channels</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Notification Channel</title>
            <para>A notification channel is a communication stream used as a means to organize
                notifications by topic or audience. Users and groups can subscribe to a channel to
                receive the notifications that interest them.</para>
            <para>You can think of a notification channel as being like a television channel.
                Producers put messages on a channel, like producers at television stations air
                programs. Subscribers receive the messages, like television viewers watch the
                programs. Unlike a television program, a message sent on a channel will wait for you
                to read it; you do not need to be actively reading the channel to avoid missing a
                message.</para>
            <para>Each channel has the following attributes:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">ID</emphasis> – This numeric value is used in
                            various tables to identify the channel. Each channel must have a unique
                            ID, but there is no requirement for the IDs to be consecutive or to
                            start with a particular value. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Name</emphasis> – This is the text displayed to
                            the user in the user interface. Each channel must have a unique name.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis> – This is text which
                            further describes the channel. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Subscription Flag</emphasis> – This flag
                            identifies whether users can adjust their subscription status on the
                            channel. If “Yes”, users can see the channel in the “Channel
                            Subscriptions” form and change their subscription status. If “No”, a
                            user’s subscription to the channel is managed by other means (for
                            example, group membership). </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Producers</emphasis> – This is a list of users
                            who are authorized to send notifications on the channel. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Recipient List</emphasis> – This is a
                            list of users and groups who will receive notifications sent to the
                            channel, regardless of channel subscriptions or notification-specific
                            recipients. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Reviewers</emphasis> – This is a list of users
                            who are responsible for approving notifications sent to the channel.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Managing Channels</title>
            <para>There is no user interface page to manage channels at this time.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Notification Channel Subscriptions</title>
            <para>Subscribing to a notification channel causes all notifications sent on the channel
                to be delivered to the subscriber, regardless of the list of users or groups
                specified as recipients of the notification.</para>
            <para>Subscriptions are divided into two categories:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Subscribers</emphasis> – Users can subscribe to
                            any channel where the Subscription Flag is set to “Yes”. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Default Recipients</emphasis> – Each channel has
                            a list of users and groups that receive all channel notifications.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Managing Subscribers</title>
            <para>Users can manage their subscriptions to channels where the Subscription Flag is
                    <emphasis role="bold">Yes</emphasis> using the Channel Subscriptions form. On
                the Main Menu, click the <emphasis role="bold">Channel Subscriptions</emphasis> link
                in the <emphasis role="bold">Notification</emphasis> box:</para>
            <para><inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/channel_subscriptions.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
            <para>This displays the list of channels that allow the user to manage their
                subscriptions:</para>
            <para><inlinemediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/channel_subscriptions2.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </inlinemediaobject></para>
            <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Subscribe</emphasis> button for a channel to
                subscribe to a channel for which you are not already subscribed. Click the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Unsubscribe</emphasis> button to cancel your subscription to the
                channel.</para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
<!-- Word Doc had 'Topic Coming Soon' for these two sections     
    <sect1>
        <title>Content and Content Types</title>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Delivery</title>
    </sect1>
-->    
    <sect1>
        <title>Notification Priority</title>
        <para>The priority of a notification indicates its importance. It has no effect on how KEN
            processes the notification, but KEN can use it when delivering a message to determine
            how to present the notification.</para>
        <para>Each priority has these attributes:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">ID</emphasis> – This numeric value defines the order
                        that KEN displays the priorities in the user interface. The lowest ID is
                        displayed at the top of the selection field and is the default value. The
                        remaining priorities are listed in the selection field in ascending ID
                        order. Each priority must have a unique ID, but there is no requirement for
                        the IDs to be consecutive or to start with a particular value. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Name</emphasis> – This is the text displayed to the
                        user in the user interface. Each priority must have a unique name. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis> – This text further describes
                        the priority. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Order</emphasis> – This numeric value determines the
                        relative importance of the priority, with lower order numbers indicating a
                        higher importance. Although not required, each priority should have a unique
                        order value. There is no requirement for the order values to be consecutive
                        or to start with a particular value. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Version</emphasis> – This numeric value lets you
                        perform optimistic locking on the database row. It is initialized to one
                        when the row is created and should be incremented each time the row is
                        updated. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>By default, three priorities are defined in KEN:<table frame="none">
                <title/>
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>ID</entry>
                            <entry>Name</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>Order</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>1</entry>
                            <entry>Normal</entry>
                            <entry>Normal priority</entry>
                            <entry>2</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>2</entry>
                            <entry>Low</entry>
                            <entry>A low priority</entry>
                            <entry>3</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>3</entry>
                            <entry>High</entry>
                            <entry>A high priority</entry>
                            <entry>1</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table></para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Managing Priorities</title>
            <para>There is no user interface page to manage priorities, so changes to the list of
                priorities must be made by a programmer using SQL. See the KEN section of the
                Technical Reference Guide for further information on this topic.</para>
    </sect1>
<!-- Word Doc had 'Topic Coming Soon' for these two sections    
    <sect1>
        <title>Senders and Recipients</title>
    </sect1>
-->    
</chapter>