<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2013 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="UG_KIM" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
  <title>KIM</title>
  <section>
    <title>KIM Overview</title>

    <para>Kuali Identity Management (KIM) provides identity and access
    management services to Rice and other applications. All KIM services are
    available on the service bus with both SOAP endpoints. KIM provides a
    service layer and a set of GUIs that you can use to maintain the identity
    information.</para>
    <para>KIM is designed to be used with both Kuali and non-Kuali
    applications. The permissions and responsibilities it provides are defined
    by each user's Role or Roles in the system. Roles can be customized to
    handle permissions and responsibilities in a variety of ways based on your
    particular needs.</para>

    <figure>
      <title>KIM Architecture</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_architecture.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <section>
      <title>KIM Features</title>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>KIM provides a reference implementation of the services but
          allows for customization and/or replacement to facilitate
          integration with institutional services or other third party
          identity management solutions.</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>KIM allows you to override its core services. </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>KIM consists of these services, which encompass it's
          API:<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>AuthenticationService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>GroupService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>IdentityService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>PermissionService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>PersonService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>ResponsibilityService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>RoleService</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>KimTypeInfoService</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>KIM evaluates permissions through its permission service. KIM
          provides plug points for implementing custom logic for permission
          checking, such as permission checks based on hierarchical
          data.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>A more detailed picture of the KIM architecture:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Detailed KIM Achitecture</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_architecture_detailed.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Person</title>
    <section>
      <title>Person Lookup</title>

      <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen to
      quickly find basic information about Persons in Kuali Rice (Rice). (In
      Kuali, a Person is a set of information about a real person or something
      that stands for real people, like a job title.) From the Person Lookup
      screen, you can also link to screens where you can create new Persons
      and edit a Person's information if you have permission to do so.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Finding the Person Lookup Screen</title>

        <para>You can go to the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis>
        screen from many Kuali screens by clicking the field search button
        next to a Name-related field. How you get to the Person Lookup screen
        and your <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis> in Kuali determine what
        you see and what you can do there.</para>

        <para>If you have permission to use the Administration screens in
        Rice, you can go directly to the <emphasis role="bold">Person
        Lookup</emphasis> screen:<orderedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis>
              tab</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Look under <emphasis
              role="bold">Identity</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
          </orderedlist></para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Person Lookup Options</title>
        <section>
          <title>From the Field Search Button</title>

          <para>If you clicked the field search button on another Kuali page
          to get to the Person Lookup screen, your screen looks like
          this:</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Lookup</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_lookup.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>To find a Person, enter some information about that person in
          the appropriate fields and click the <emphasis
          role="bold">search</emphasis> button at the bottom of the
          screen.<itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>You can display a list of all Persons in KIM if you
                leave the search fields empty and set the <emphasis
                role="bold">Active Indicator</emphasis> to <emphasis
                role="bold">Both</emphasis>, then click the search
                button.</para>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>Rice displays a list of Persons who match your search
                information. The list is just below the search fields on the
                Person Lookup page:</para>

                <figure>
                  <title>Person Lookup: Results</title>

                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="../images/person_results.png"
                                 scale="85"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Click one of the underlined column titles on the search
                results list to sort the list by that column. Click it again
                to sort the list in the opposite order.</para>

                <para>You can also export the search results list in CSV,
                spreadsheet, or XML format. Click the appropriate link at the
                bottom of the search results list to do this.</para>

                <para>If you need to see more information about one of the
                Persons in the search results list, click one of the
                information fields for that Person. Kuali then displays the
                <emphasis role="bold">Person Document</emphasis> screen for
                that Person.</para>

                <figure>
                  <title>Person Document</title>

                  <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                      <imagedata fileref="../images/person_document.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                  </mediaobject>
                </figure>

                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Return Value</emphasis> column
                has a <emphasis role="bold">return value</emphasis> link for
                each person. Click this return value link for the Person whose
                information you need, and Kuali goes back to the screen you
                were on before and automatically enters the information about
                that person on the screen for you.</para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>From the Administration Tab</title>

          <para>If you come to the <emphasis role="bold">Person
          Lookup</emphasis> screen after clicking <emphasis
          role="bold">Person</emphasis> (under <emphasis
          role="bold">Identity</emphasis>) on the <emphasis
          role="bold">Administration</emphasis> tab, you may see a <emphasis
          role="bold">create new</emphasis> button in the upper right corner
          of your screen if the user logged in has permissions to create a
          Person, like this:</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Lookup: Create New Button</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_lookup_create_new.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para>You can click this create new button to go to the <emphasis
          role="bold">Person Document</emphasis> screen, where you can add a
          new Person as a Kuali user. For more information on adding a Person,
          see the <emphasis role="bold">Person Maintenance</emphasis> function
          section (next) in this User Guide.</para>

          <para>If you need to edit information for a Person in KIM, you first
          need to display that Person's information. Search for the Person
          (see search instructions above) from the <emphasis
          role="bold">Administration</emphasis> tab's link for <emphasis
          role="bold">Person</emphasis>. When Kuali displays the list of
          Persons that match your search, you'll notice one difference in the
          columns because you did your search from the Administration tab –
          there is an <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column on the
          left.</para>

          <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column has an
          <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> link for each person. Click
          this edit link to go to the <emphasis role="bold">Person
          Document</emphasis> screen where you can edit this Person's
          information. For more information on working with Person
          information, see the <emphasis role="bold">Person
          Maintenance</emphasis> section (next) in this User Guide.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Person Maintenance</title>

      <para>The Person Document allows you to identify and maintain each user
      in KIM. Each Person Document includes data about that user's
      relationship with your institution as well as the roles and groups to
      which the person belongs.</para>

      <para>In KIM, a Person is a unique combination of an <emphasis
      role="italic">Entity ID</emphasis> and a <emphasis
      role="italic">Principal ID</emphasis>. The Entity ID represents a Person
      with a unique number, and the Person Document associates the Entity ID
      with the user's Principal ID number and Principal Name (often referred
      to as a user name or user ID). When searching for or working with users
      in KIM, you usually use either the Principal ID or the Principal Name. A
      single Entity ID can have multiple Principals associated with it, but
      the base implementation of KIM assumes that each Entity ID has only a
      single Principal.</para>

      <note>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Person and HR Systems</emphasis>: Many
        institutions choose to override parts of the Person Document
        (especially the affiliation and contact information) with data from an
        HR system.</para>
      </note>
      <section>
        <title>Business Rules</title>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Each Person must have at least one Affiliation.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Each faculty or staff affiliation must have at least one
            Employment Information record associated with it.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>If a Person has any faculty or staff affiliations, then one
            Employment Information record must be marked as Primary.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Each Person must have a default Name record in the Contacts
            section.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Each affiliation must be associated with a Campus. </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Routing</title>

        <para>Only people with the appropriate role can initiate routing for
        Person documents.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Displaying the Person Lookup Screen</title>

      <para>On the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis> tab, click
      <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis> to display the <emphasis
      role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen. Do a lookup to see a list
      of Persons. Click any Person on the search results list to display his
      or her <emphasis role="bold">Person Document</emphasis> screen.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Document Layout</title>

        <para>The Person Document includes <emphasis role="bold">Document
        Overview, Overview, Contact, Privacy Preferences, Membership, Ad Hoc
        Recipients</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">Route Log</emphasis>
        tabs.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Person Document</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/person_document2.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Document Overview Tab</title>

        <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Document Overview</emphasis> tab
        combined with the Overview tab identifies the <emphasis
        role="bold">Person</emphasis> as a unique combination of Entity and
        Principal ID.</para>

        <para>Additional information on the <emphasis role="bold">Document
        Overview Tab</emphasis> can be found in the Common Features and
        Functions section of this User Guide.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Overview Tab</title>

        <para>The Overview tab identifies the <emphasis
        role="bold">Person</emphasis> as a unique combination of <emphasis
        role="bold">Entity ID</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">Principal
        ID</emphasis>. It also contains information about how this Person is
        affiliated with your institution. Two types of affiliations—<emphasis
        role="bold">Staff</emphasis> and <emphasis
        role="bold">Faculty</emphasis>—contain additional data fields to
        further define a person's relationship with your institution.</para>

        <para>The instructions below assume that you are manually entering
        this information. Many institutions either have this data fed from an
        existing Person database or simply override this information with
        existing Person data.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Person Document: Overview Section</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/person_overview_tab.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <section>
          <title>Overview Section</title>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes</title>
              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Entity Id</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. The unique ID number identifying this
                    Person in your database. An individual may have multiple
                    Principal IDs but only one Entity ID. The base
                    implementation assumes that each user has only one Entity
                    ID and one Principal ID. KIM automatically assigns an
                    Entity Id to a new Person when you save or submit a Person
                    Document.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Principal Id</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. The unique ID number identifying this
                    Principal. Whereas Entity Id represents a unique Person,
                    Principal Id represents a set of login information for
                    that Person. When selecting a Person, you ordinarily
                    reference his or her Principal Id. KIM automatically
                    assigns a Principal Id to a new Person when you save or
                    submit the Person Document.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Principal Name</entry>
                    <entry>Required. The user name for this Principal</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Tax Identification Number</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Enter the Individual Tax Identification
                    Number (ITIN) for this Principal ID</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Principal Password</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the password for this Principal
                    ID</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>
                    <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Principal ID is
                    Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this Principal ID
                    is Inactive.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button under <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> to
                    save the information you enter in this section.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Affiliations Section</title>

          <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Affiliations</emphasis> section
          of the <emphasis role="bold">Overview</emphasis> tab to add
          Affiliations for this Principal ID. Depending on the Affiliation
          type you select, you may need to complete additional fields.</para>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes,
              Affiliations</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Affiliation Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the Type of Affiliation from
                    the list. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Affiliate</emphasis>:
                          Users in your system who are neither employees nor
                          students</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Faculty</emphasis>: A
                          faculty employee</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Staff</emphasis>: A
                          non-faculty employee</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Student</emphasis>: A
                          non-employee identified as a student of your
                          institution</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist> <para> Affiliation types of Faculty and
                    Staff require additional information (see
                    below).</para></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Campus Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Select the Campus Code associated with
                    this Affiliation</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Default</entry>

                    <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Affiliation is
                    this Principal's default association with your
                    institution. Each Principal must have at least one default
                    Affiliation.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save the affiliation information.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>

          <para>If you select an Affiliation of Faculty or Staff, KIM displays
          additional fields to collect employment information:</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Document: Overview Tab, Affiliations Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/faculty_staff_affiliate_fields.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes, Affiliations
              Continued</title>
              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Employment ID</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. Enter the Employment ID number associated
                    with this Faculty or Staff affiliation. Ordinarily this
                    entry is the ID number identifying this Principal in your
                    HR system.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Primary</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Faculty or
                    Staff affiliation represents the Principal's primary job
                    with your institution. Each Principal with a Faculty or
                    Staff affiliation must have exactly one affiliation marked
                    as Primary.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Employee Status</entry>

                    <entry><para>Required. Select the current status of this
                    Faculty or Staff affiliation. Options:</para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Active</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Deceased</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>On Non-Pay Leave</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Status Not Yet Processed</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Processing</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Retired</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Terminated</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Employee Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Required. Select the type of employment for
                    this Affiliation. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Non-Professional</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Other</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Professional</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Base Salary Amount</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Enter the base annual salary for this
                    Faculty or Staff Affiliation.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Primary Department Code</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. Enter the code for the Department
                    associated with this Faculty or Staff affiliation.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Add</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this row of employment information.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Contact Tab</title>

        <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Contact</emphasis> tab records the
        names, addresses, phone numbers, and email addresses associated with
        this Person. Any Person record can store multiple contact information
        records of each type (name, address, phone number, and email address).
        You must select one value of each type as the default for that Person
        record.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Person Document: Contact Tab</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/person_contact_tab.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <section>
          <title>Names Section</title>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Names Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_names_section.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Names Section
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Name Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of name to be added
                    in this row. Options:</para><itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Other</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Preferred</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Primary</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Title</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the appropriate title for
                    the name being added in this row. Options:</para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Ms</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Mrs</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Mr</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Dr</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>First Name</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the first name for this
                    record.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Last Name</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the last name for this
                    record.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Suffix</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select a suffix for this name
                    record. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Jr</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Sr</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Mr</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>MD</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Default</entry>
                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Name record is
                    the default for this person. Each Person record must have
                    exactly one Name record identified as the default.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>
                    <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Name record is
                    Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this record
                    should be considered Inactive.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this Name record.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Addresses Section</title>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Addresses Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/addresses_section.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Address Section
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Address Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of address being
                    added on this row. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Home</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Other</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Work</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Line 1 to 3</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Use lines 1, 2, and 3 to enter the street
                    address for this row.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>City</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the city associated with this
                    address.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>State</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Select the state associated with this
                    address from the list.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Postal Code</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the postal code (zip code in the
                    U.S.) associated with this address.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Country</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Select the country associated with this
                    address.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Default</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate this address record
                    should be used as the Default. A Person record can have
                    only one Default Address record.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>
                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Address record
                    is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this record is
                    Inactive.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this Address record.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Phone Numbers Section</title>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Phone Numbers Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/phone_numbers_section.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Phone Numbers
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Phone Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of phone number
                    being added on this row. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Home</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Mobile</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Other</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Work</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Phone Number</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the area code and phone
                    number.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Extension</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the appropriate extension.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Country</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. Select the country associated with this
                    Phone Number record.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Default</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Phone Number
                    record should be used as the Default. A Person record can
                    have only one default Phone Number record.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Phone Number
                    record is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this
                    record is inactive.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this Phone Number record.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Email Addresses Section</title>

          <figure>
            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Email Addresses
            Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/email_addresses_section.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Email Address
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Email</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Enter the email address for this
                    record.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Type</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of email address on
                    this row. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Home</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Other</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                          <para>Work</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Default</entry>
                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Email Address
                    record should be used as the Default. A Person record can
                    have only one default Email Address record.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>
                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Email Address
                    record is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this
                    record is Inactive.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this Email Address record.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Privacy Preferences Tab</title>

        <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Privacy Preferences</emphasis> tab
        allows you to suppress the display of (hide) fields on the <emphasis
        role="bold">Contact</emphasis> Tab.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Person Document: Privacy Preferences Tab</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/privacy_preferences_tab.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
            <title>Person Document: Privacy Preferences Tab Attributes</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
              <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
              <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry>Field Name</entry>
                  <entry>Description</entry>
                </row>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry>Suppress Name</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display
                  this person's names.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Suppress Personal</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display
                  any of this person's personal data.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Suppress Phone</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display
                  this person's phone numbers.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Suppress Address</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display
                  this person's addresses.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Suppress Email</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display
                  this person's email addresses.</entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Membership Tab</title>

        <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Membership Tab</emphasis> allows you
        to associate a person with groups and roles and, by extension, with
        KIM permissions and responsibilities. Assigning a person to a role is
        the most direct way to give him or her KIM permissions and
        responsibilities.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Person Document: Memberships Tab</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/membership_tab.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The Membership tab is divided into two sections, one for
        managing assignments to <emphasis role="bold">Groups</emphasis> and
        another for <emphasis role="bold">Roles</emphasis>.</para>

        <section>
          <title>Groups Section</title>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Memeberships Tab, Groups
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Group</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. Enter the name of the KIM group you want
                    to assign this person to. You can also use the Group
                    lookup to search for and select a valid Group.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                    person to, KIM displays the namespace code associated with
                    the group you selected.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Name</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                    person to, KIM displays the name of that group.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Type</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                    person to, KIM displays the type of that group.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active From Date</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. If this user's assignment to this group
                    is to be effective as of a certain date, enter that date
                    here.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active To Date</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. If this user's assignment to this group
                    is to terminate as of a certain date, enter that date
                    here.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add this group assignment.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>

          <note>
            <para>There is no way to delete a person's assignment to a group.
            To remove a person from a group, use the Active To Date field to
            specify a date in the past.</para>
          </note>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Roles Section</title>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Person Document: Memeberships Tab, Roles
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Role</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. Use the Name lookup to search for and
                    select the role you want to assign this person to.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                    this Person record, KIM displays the namespace code
                    associated with that role.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Name</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                    this Person record, KIM displays the name associated with
                    that role.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Type</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                    this Person record, KIM displays the role type for the
                    selected role.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active From Date</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. If this user's assignment to this role is
                    to be effective as of a certain date, enter that date
                    here.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active To Date</entry>
                    <entry>Optional. If this user's assignment to this role is
                    to terminate as of a certain date, enter that date
                    here.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to save this role data.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>

          <note>
            <para>There is no way to delete a person's assignment to a role.
            To remove a person from a role, use the Active To Date field to
            specify a date in the past.</para>
          </note>

          <para>When assigning some roles, you may need to supply additional
          qualifying information that further defines this person's
          assignment. For more information on Roles see the Role Maintenance
          section in this User Guide.</para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Ad Hoc Recipients Tab</title>

      <para>Ad Hoc Recipients tab information can be found in the Common
      Features and Functions section of this User Guide.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Route Log Tab</title>

      <para>Route Log tab information can be found in the Common Features and
      Functions section of this User Guide.</para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Group</title>
    <section>
      <title>Group Lookup Screen</title>
      <para>The Group Lookup function provides a quick reference to key Group
      information.</para>

      <para>You get to this screen by clicking the <emphasis
      role="bold">Group</emphasis> option in the <emphasis
      role="bold">Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis
      role="bold">Administration</emphasis> screen.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Identity Channel: Group Link</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/select_group.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <figure>
        <title>Group Lookup</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/group_lookup.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>On the <emphasis role="bold">Group Lookup</emphasis> screen, click
      the <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button to go to the
      <emphasis role="bold">Group Maintenance</emphasis> screen, where you can
      create a new Group in Rice.</para>

      <para>Conducting a search from the Group Lookup screen returns a list
      similar to this:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Group Lookup: Results</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/group_lookup_results.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>For information on any of the fields above, please refer to the
      <emphasis role="bold">Group Maintenance</emphasis> section below.</para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Group Inquiry Screen</title>

      <para>This screen provides high-level information about a Group and
      shows who is assigned to it.</para>

      <para>Click a <emphasis role="bold">Group Request</emphasis> value on
      the <emphasis role="bold">Action List</emphasis> screen to display the
      <emphasis role="bold">Group Inquiry</emphasis> page for that
      Group:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Group Inquiry</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/group_inquiry.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <section>
        <title>Overview Tab</title>

        <para>For information on these fields please refer to the <emphasis
        role="bold">Group Maintenance</emphasis> section that follows.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Assignees Tab</title>

        <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
            <title>Group Inquiry: Assignees Attributes</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
              <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
              <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry>Field</entry>
                  <entry>Description</entry>
                </row>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry>Type Code</entry>
                  <entry>The code for the type of this Group member</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Member Identifier</entry>
                  <entry>The user ID for the Member</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Name</entry>
                  <entry>The user name for the Member</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Active From Dt</entry>

                  <entry>The effective date of membership in this Group for
                  this member; if it is blank, membership is valid as soon as
                  the member is assigned This field is useful when you want to
                  add a Person, Role, or Group to a Group before he/she/they
                  should be active in the Group. This might happen, for
                  example, when you add a new employee before their start
                  date.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Active To Dt</entry>

                  <entry>The termination date of membership for this member;
                  if blank, the membership does not terminate</entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Group Maintenance Document</title>

      <para>The Group document allows you to associate Persons, Roles, or
      other Groups with each other so you can assign the same role to all
      Group members.</para>

      <para>Groups have no inherent permissions or responsibilities of their
      own. Only by associating a Group with a role do the members of that
      Group become associated with permissions and responsibilities.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Creating New Groups</title>

        <para>If you are creating a new Group and have clicked the <emphasis
        role="bold">Create New</emphasis> button on the Group Lookup screen,
        you will be redirected to the Group creation page. One of the first
        things to do, if wanting to create a group with a non-default Group
        Type, is to use the kim type lookup to select a different group type.
        Once clicked you will redirected to a screen like the
        following:</para>

        <figure>
          <title>KIM Type Lookup</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
            <title>KIM Type Lookup Search Attributes</title>
            <tgroup cols="2">
              <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
              <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
              <thead>
                <row>
                  <entry>Field</entry>
                  <entry>Description</entry>
                </row>
              </thead>
              <tbody>
                <row>
                  <entry>Namespace Code</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Select the code for the application and
                  module to which this KIM Type pertains.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Type Name</entry>
                  <entry>Optional. Enter the name for this KIM Type.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Type Identifier</entry>

                  <entry>Optional. Enter the unique system-assigned Identifier
                  for this KIM Type.</entry>
                </row>
                <row>
                  <entry>Active Indicator</entry>

                  <entry>Required (defaults to Yes). Change the default
                  selection to view KIM types that are inactive or to see all
                  Types (active and inactive).</entry>
                </row>
              </tbody>
            </tgroup>
          </table></para>

        <para><emphasis role="bold">The search results list includes the same
        fields as the Lookup screen. </emphasis>The search results are
        displayed below the search fields on the Lookup screen.</para>

        <para>To select the Type you want to use for your new Group, click the
        return value link for that Type. KIM will copy the Type information to
        use in creating your new Group.</para>
      </section>
      <section>
        <title>Group Maintenance Document: Layout</title>
        <para>The Group document includes these tabs:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Document Overview</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Overview</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Assignees</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Ad Hoc Recipients</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>Route Log</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>

        <para>The Overview and Assignees tabs are described below. Information
        on the others can be found in the Common Features and Functions
        section of this User Guide.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Group Maintenance Document</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/group_maintenance_document.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <section>
          <title>Overview Tab</title>

          <para>This tab identifies the Group with a unique system-assigned ID
          number, a namespace, and a name. Each Group also has a Type that
          specifies any qualifiers that this Group might require.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Group Maintenance Document: Group Overview</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/group_overview.png" scale="85"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Group Maintenance Document: Group Overview
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Group ID</entry>
                    <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                    that identifies this Group; Rice completes this field when
                    you submit the document.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Type Name</entry>

                    <entry><para>Required. The type of attributes that are
                    associated with this Group. Some Group types, such as the
                    Default Type, do not require attributes.</para>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>When creating
                    a new Group, you must select the Type before Rice can
                    generate the document. See the Creating New Groups section
                    of this document</para></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Group Namespace</entry>

                    <entry>Required. An indicator that associates the Group
                    with a particular application and module</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Group Name</entry>
                    <entry>Required. The common descriptive name by which this
                    Group is known</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Group is
                    active and is a valid choice for assigning to roles.
                    Uncheck the box to indicate that this Group is inactive
                    (it is no longer valid when making role
                    assignments).</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Assignees Tab</title>

          <para>This tab displays the members who belong to this Group. You
          can also use this tab to add new members or to edit the fields for
          existing members.</para>

          <para>Note that for members not added to the group on this
          maintenance document, the "delete" button to remove that member is
          inactive. If a member's association with a group is past, users
          should set the "Active To Date" field to the end of the membership;
          the member will not be an active member of the group after that
          date.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Group Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/assignees_tab.png" scale="85"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Group Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Type Code</entry>
                    <entry>Required. Select the Type of the member you are
                    adding to this Group. Group members can be Principals (as
                    defined on the Person document), Roles, or other
                    Groups.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Enter the ID that identifies the member
                    you are adding, or use the lookup to search for and select
                    a valid Member ID. The lookup directs you to the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Principal</emphasis>, <emphasis
                    role="bold">Group</emphasis>, or <emphasis
                    role="bold">Role</emphasis> lookup, based on your
                    <emphasis role="bold">Member Type Code</emphasis>
                    selection.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active From Date</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. To specify the earliest date on which
                    this member is to be considered a valid member of this
                    Group, enter a date in this field.</entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Active To Date</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. To specify a date on which this
                    member is no longer to be considered a valid member of
                    this Group, enter a date in this field. As of this date,
                    the Member will no longer be considered a member of this
                    Group.</para> <para><emphasis role="bold">Note:
                    </emphasis>You cannot delete or inactivate Group members.
                    To remove a member from a Group, enter an Active To
                    Date.</para></entry>
                  </row>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add this member to the Group.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Role</title>
    <section>
      <title>Role Lookup Screen</title>

      <para>This screen provides detailed information relating to the
      Permissions assigned to a <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis> in
      KIM.</para>

      <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis> screen is
      accessible directly off the Rice <emphasis
      role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu by clicking <emphasis
      role="bold">Role</emphasis> in the Identity section.</para>

      <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Granted to Roles</emphasis> field
      on the <emphasis role="bold">Document Configuration</emphasis> screen to
      display the <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis> screen. You can
      also access the Role Lookup screen by clicking a <emphasis
      role="bold">Granted to Roles</emphasis> value in any list where it
      appears.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Role Lookup</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/role_lookup.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <section>
        <title>Document Layout</title>

        <para>This screen may have three or four tabs of information,
        depending on the Role. The first three tabs are <emphasis
        role="bold">Overview</emphasis>, <emphasis
        role="bold">Permissions</emphasis>, and <emphasis
        role="bold">Responsibilities</emphasis>. KIM only displays the fourth
        tab, <emphasis role="bold">Assignees</emphasis>, when Assignee
        information is associated with this <emphasis
        role="bold">Role</emphasis>.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Role Maintenance Document</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/role_maintenance_document.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Information on the fields in all of these tabs can be found in
        the <emphasis role="bold">Role Maintenance</emphasis> section of this
        user guide.</para>
      </section>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Role Maintenance Document</title>

      <para>The Role Maintenance Document allows you to create a new KIM Role
      and edit existing Roles. Each Role collects a specific set of
      Permissions and Responsibilities and allows you to assign members to
      it.</para>

      <para>The purpose of each Role is defined by its associated Permissions
      and Responsibilities. Roles are classified by <emphasis
      role="bold">Types</emphasis> that generally indicate with which
      Permissions and Responsibilities they are associated.</para>

      <note>
        <para>The process of creating a new Type for Roles requires technical
        assistance.</para>
      </note>

      <para>To access the <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis>
      screen:<orderedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Do a <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis>.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Find the Role you want to change in the list of search
            results.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Edit</emphasis> for the row that
            has the Role that you need to change.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist></para>

      <section>
        <title>Role Maintenance Document</title>

        <para>The Role document includes eight tabs:<itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>Document Overview</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Overview</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Permissions</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Responsibilities</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Assignees</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Delegations</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Ad Hoc Recipients</para>
            </listitem>

            <listitem>
              <para>Route Log</para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist></para>

        <para>Those contains unique information are addressed below. For more
        information about the Document Overview, Ad Hoc Recipients and Route
        Log tabs, please see the <emphasis role="bold">Common Features and
        Functions</emphasis> document.</para>

        <figure>
          <title>Role Maintenance Document: Tabs</title>

          <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="../images/role_tabs.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <section>
          <title>Overview Tab</title>

          <para>This tab gives the Role a unique system-assigned ID number, a
          Namespace, and a Name. Each Role also has a Type that usually
          matches the kinds of Permissions and Responsibilities associated
          with it.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Overview Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_overview.png" scale="90"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Overview Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Role Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The unique, system-assigned ID number
                    that identifies this Role</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Type Name</entry>

                    <entry><para>Display-only. The Type Name usually
                    identifies the general kinds of Permissions and
                    Responsibilities associated with this Role.</para>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis> When
                    creating a new Role, you must select its Type before you
                    can display a new Role document. See Creating New Roles
                    below.</para></entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Role Namespace</entry>

                    <entry>Required. An indicator that associates the Role
                    with a particular application and module</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Role Name</entry>

                    <entry>Required. The common descriptive name by which this
                    Role is known</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Role is Active
                    and is, therefore, to be included by KIM when it evaluates
                    Permissions and Responsibilities. Uncheck the Active box
                    to indicate that this Role is inactive.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Creating New Roles</title>

          <para>You must search for and select an existing Type for KIM to
          generate a new Role document. When you click the Create New button,
          KIM displays the <emphasis role="bold">KIM Type Lookup</emphasis>
          screen:</para>

          <figure>
            <title>KIM Type Lookup</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <note>
            <para>While you use the KIM Type Lookup screen both for creating
            new Groups and new Roles, not all KIM Types are valid for both
            Groups and Roles. When using this Lookup, you may see different
            results depending on the KIM Types that are appropriate for your
            task.</para>
          </note>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Permissions Tab</title>

          <para>This tab identifies the Permissions associated with this Role.
          Permissions authorize specific actions in the system with which they
          are associated. A Role can have any number of Permissions (including
          no Permissions) associated with it.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_permissions.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Add Permission ID</entry>

                    <entry>To add a Permission to this Role, enter the
                    appropriate Permission ID, or search for and select a
                    value using the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Permission</emphasis> lookup</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Add</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add the selected Permission to this Role
                    document.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>

          <para>After you add a Permission to the document, KIM displays
          additional information about the Permission:</para>

          <note>
            <para>You <emphasis role="italic">cannot</emphasis> edit
            Permissions from the <emphasis role="bold">Role Maintenance
            Document</emphasis>.</para>
          </note>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tab, Add
            Permissions</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_add_permission.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tabb, Add
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Permission Namespace</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The Namespace identifies the
                    application and module associated with this
                    Permission.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Permission Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                    for this Permission</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Permission Name</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The descriptive name of this
                    Permission. This often tells you, in general terms, what
                    the Permission authorizes.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Permission Detail Values</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The document Types, tabs, and/or
                    fields that this Permission authorizes the holder to see
                    or use. Not all Permissions have Detail Values.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active Indicator</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. Indicator showing whether this
                    Permission is active in KIM</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry><para>Click the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Delete</emphasis> button to remove this
                    Permission from this Role.</para> <para><emphasis
                    role="bold">Warning: </emphasis>You may delete a
                    Permission from a Role only if it has not yet been saved.
                    (In other words, you can delete a Permission from a Role
                    only if you added it to this Role, but have not yet
                    submitted the document.)</para></entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Responsibilities Tab</title>

          <para>This tab identifies the Responsibilities associated with this
          Role. Responsibilities define the workflow actions that will be
          requested of the Role. A Role can have any number of
          Responsibilities (including none) associated with it.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibilities Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibilities.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Add Responsibility ID</entry>

                    <entry>To add a Responsibility to this Role, enter the
                    Responsibility ID, or search for and select a value using
                    the Responsibility lookup .</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Add button</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add the selected Responsibility to this Role
                    document.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>

          <para>After you add a Responsibility to the document, KIM displays
          additional information about this Responsibility.</para>

          <note>
            <para>In general, you cannot edit Responsibilities using the Role
            document, but some Responsibilities have associated attributes
            that you must define at the Role level.</para>
          </note>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility, Added
            Responsibility</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibility_added.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility, Add
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Responsibility Namespace</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The Namespace tells you the
                    application and module associated with this
                    Responsibility.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Responsibility Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                    for this Responsibility</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Responsibility Name</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The descriptive name of this
                    Responsibility. For most Responsibilities, the name is
                    <emphasis role="bold">Review</emphasis>.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Responsibility Detail Values</entry>

                    <entry><para>Display-only. This gives you more specific
                    information about the Responsibility. Responsibility
                    Detail Values are formatted in a standard way with these
                    attributes, separated by commas:</para> <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Route Node</emphasis>:
                          The location where this Responsibility is invoked in
                          Workflow.</para>
                        </listitem>

                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Document
                          Type</emphasis>: The Document Type for which this
                          Responsibility generates workflow requests.</para>
                        </listitem>

                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Action Details at Role
                          Member Level</emphasis>: When this field is True,
                          action details are kept for each Member of this
                          Role. When this field is False, action details are
                          only kept at the Responsibility level for this Role.
                          (see Assigning Action Detail Values, below).</para>
                        </listitem>

                        <listitem>
                          <para><emphasis role="bold">Required</emphasis>:
                          Indicates if the routing represented by this
                          Responsibility should be required. If this is set to
                          True and the Responsibility fails to generate an
                          Action Request (perhaps because no one is assigned
                          to the associated Role), then the document will go
                          into Exception status. If this routing is optional,
                          this will be False and the document will simply skip
                          this Responsibility if no requests are
                          generated.</para>
                        </listitem>
                      </itemizedlist></entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active Indicator</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. Indicator showing whether this
                    Responsibility is active within the system</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry><para>Click the Delete button to remove this
                    Responsibility from this Role.</para> <para><emphasis
                    role="bold">Warning: </emphasis>You can delete a
                    Responsibility only if it has not yet been saved to the
                    database (in other words, you can only delete it if you
                    have added it to this Role but have not yet submitted the
                    document).</para></entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Assigning Action Detail Values</title>

          <para>When you add a Responsibility with an <emphasis
          role="bold">Action Detail Values at Role Member Level</emphasis>
          value of <emphasis role="bold">False</emphasis>, you must complete
          additional fields in a Responsibility Action sub-section. KIM
          automatically displays this sub-section immediately beneath the
          Responsibility you've just added.</para>

          <para>The fields in this sub-section define the type of Action
          Requests generated for, and the general workflow behavior associated
          with, this Responsibility. Entries in these fields cause KIM to
          generate the same Type of Action Requests for all members of this
          Role and handle actions by all members of this Role in the same
          way.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility Tab, Action
            Section</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibility_action.png"
                           scale="90"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility Tab, Action
              Section Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Name</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The namespace and name of the
                    Responsibility associated with these action
                    details</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Action Type Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. The Type of Action Request that KIM
                    generates for this Responsibility. Action Type Codes are:
                    Approve, FYI, and Acknowledge.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Priority Number</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. If multiple requests are generated at the
                    route node specified on this Responsibility, this
                    determines the order in which KIM generates these
                    requests. KIM processes requests with lower priority
                    numbers before processing requests with higher numbers.
                    Requests with no number are treated as a priority
                    1.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Action Policy Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. This determines what happens if multiple
                    members of this Role receive the same Action Request and
                    one of them takes the action. For example, if a Role has a
                    Group with three members assigned, all of these members
                    receive the Action Request defined here; this code then
                    determines what KIM does when one of them takes action on
                    the document. A value of <emphasis
                    role="italic">FIRST</emphasis> indicates that the first
                    Group member to take action on the document causes KIM to
                    clear all the requests for this Responsibility that may be
                    in other Group member's action lists. A value of <emphasis
                    role="italic">ALL</emphasis> indicates that each Group
                    member must take individual action to clear his or her own
                    requests.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Force Action</entry>

                    <entry>Check this box to indicate that each user must take
                    action for this request, even if the user has previously
                    taken action on this document. Leaving the box unchecked
                    allows a request to be immediately fulfilled if the Role
                    member has previously taken action on this specific
                    document.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Assignees Tab</title>

          <para>This tab displays all members who belong to this Role. You may
          also use the tab to add new members and to edit the values
          associated with existing members.</para>

          <para>Just as with group, role members not added by the specific
          maintenance document will have their "delete" buttons inactivated.
          To end that member's active association with the group, set the
          "Active To Date" field to the end of the membership.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_assignees.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Type Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Role members can be Principals (as
                    defined on the Person document), Groups, or other Roles.
                    Select the Type of member you want to add to this
                    Role.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Enter the ID of the member you want to
                    add, or use the lookup to search for and select a Member.
                    The lookup icon displays the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Principal</emphasis>, <emphasis
                    role="bold">Group</emphasis>, or <emphasis
                    role="bold">Role</emphasis> Lookup screen based on the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Type Code you selected for this Role
                    member</emphasis>.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Namespace Cd</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. Identifies the namespace code
                    associated with this Role member. Note that only Groups
                    and Roles display a namespace code.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Name</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. Identifies the name of the member you
                    are assigning to this Role</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active From Dt</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. Enter a <emphasis role="bold">Active
                    From</emphasis> date to define the earliest date on which
                    this member is a valid member of this Role.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active To Dt</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Allows you to deactivate a member's
                    association with a Role on a specific date. Enter the date
                    the user is no longer a member of this Role.</para>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You cannot
                    delete or inactivate Role members. To remove a member from
                    a Role, enter an <emphasis role="bold">Active To
                    Dt.</emphasis></para></entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add this member to the Role.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>

        <section>
          <title>Delegations Tab</title>

          <para>This tab defines and identifies Delegates associated with this
          Role. Delegates are users that a member of this Role has authorized
          to have the same Permissions and take the same actions as that
          member is authorized to take. For example, a manager may make
          someone a Delegate for his or her actions in a particular
          Role.</para>

          <para>The Assignees Tab dealing with Delegates is slightly
          different, as shown in the following table. Note that if the members
          of a Role require qualifying values, the delegation requires these
          values as well. In most cases, Delegates must have the same
          qualifiers as the Role member with which they are associated.</para>

          <para>Just as with Group and Role Associations, delegations added
          outside of the current maintenance document have inactive "delete"
          buttons and must have the "Active To Date" field set to end the
          delegation.</para>

          <figure>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Delegations Tab</title>

            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_delegations.png"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>

          <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
              <title>Role Maintenance Document: Delegations Tab
              Attributes</title>

              <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

                <thead>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Field Name</entry>

                    <entry>Description</entry>
                  </row>
                </thead>

                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry>Role Member</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Use the lookup to search for, and return,
                    the Member of this Role for whom you wish to create a
                    Delegate.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Type Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Select the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Type</emphasis> of Delegate you want to add to
                    this Role. Delegates may be Principals (as defined on the
                    Person document), Groups, or other Roles.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Identifier</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Enter the ID that identifies the Delegate
                    you want to add, or use the lookup to search for and
                    select a Delegate. Note that the lookup takes you to the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Principal</emphasis>, <emphasis
                    role="bold">Group</emphasis>, or<emphasis role="bold">
                    Role Lookup</emphasis> screen, depending on the Member
                    Type Code you selected.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Namespace Code</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The namespace of this Delegate. Note
                    that only delegations to Groups or Roles display a Member
                    Namespace Code.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Member Name</entry>

                    <entry>Display-only. The name of the selected
                    Delegate</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active From Date</entry>

                    <entry>Optional. You may choose to qualify this Delegate's
                    association with this Role by date. Entering an <emphasis
                    role="bold">Active From Date</emphasis> is the earliest
                    date on which this Delegate is valid for this
                    Role.</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Active To Date</entry>

                    <entry><para>Optional. Allows you to deactivate a
                    Delegate's association with a Role on a specific date. The
                    date you enter is the date on which this user is no longer
                    a Delegate for this Role.</para> <para><emphasis
                    role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You <emphasis
                    role="italic">cannot</emphasis> delete or deactivate
                    Delegates. To remove a Delegate from a Role, enter an
                    <emphasis role="bold">Active To
                    Date</emphasis>.</para></entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Delegation Type Code</entry>

                    <entry>Required. Select <emphasis
                    role="italic">Secondary</emphasis> or <emphasis
                    role="italic">Primary</emphasis>. Note that this selection
                    only applies to Responsibilities associated with the Role.
                    This indicates whether the Delegate automatically receives
                    documents directly in their Action List (<emphasis
                    role="italic">Primary</emphasis>) or if the Delegate may
                    only choose to view documents in their Action List using
                    the <emphasis role="bold">Secondary Delegate</emphasis>
                    dropdown (<emphasis
                    role="italic">Secondary</emphasis>).</entry>
                  </row>

                  <row>
                    <entry>Actions</entry>

                    <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis>
                    button to add this Delegate to this Role.</entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table></para>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>KIM Type</title>

    <section>
      <title>KIM Type Lookup</title>

      <para>Use this lookup when you create a new group in KIM to find the KIM
      Type for the new group.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>KIM Type Lookup</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>You may enter information in one or more of the search fields to
      find the correct Type for your new group:</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>KIM Type Lookup Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Namespace Code</entry>

                <entry>Optional. Select the code of the application and module
                for this KIM Type.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Type Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. Enter the name for this KIM Type.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Type Identifier</entry>

                <entry>Optional. Enter the unique system-assigned Identifier
                for this KIM Type.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Active Indicator</entry>

                <entry>Required. Defaults to Yes (Yes means display only
                Active Types). Change the default selection to view KIM Types
                that are Inactive or Types that are both Active and
                Inactive.</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>

      <figure>
        <title>KIM Type Lookup: Results Example</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/kim_type_lookup_results.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The search results list for this screen has the same fields as the
      <emphasis role="bold">Lookup</emphasis> screen. To select the Type you
      want to use for your new group, click the <emphasis role="bold">return
      value</emphasis> link for it in the search results list.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>KIM Type Inquiry</title>

      <para>The KIM Type Inquiry screen provides details about a KIM Type data
      element.</para>

      <para>To access this screen, from the <emphasis role="bold">Role
      Lookup</emphasis> screen, click a <emphasis role="bold">Role Type
      Name</emphasis> in your search results list.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>KIM Type Inquiry</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/kim_type.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>All fields are defined above in <emphasis role="italic">KIM Type
      Lookup</emphasis> except these:</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>KIM Type Inquiry Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Service Name</entry>

                <entry>Display-only. The name of the service associated with
                this KIM Type</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Namespace Code</entry>

                <entry>Display-only. The namespace code associated with the
                selected KIM Type</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Responsibility</title>

    <section>
      <title>Responsibility Lookup</title>

      <para>Similar to the Permission Lookup, you can use the Responsibility
      Lookup to search for and view existing responsibilities in KIM. You can
      view summarized information about the responsibility detail values as
      well as the roles with which the responsibility is currently
      associated.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Identity Channel: Responsibility Link</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_responsibility.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>To display this screen, from the <emphasis
      role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu, click <emphasis
      role="bold">Responsibility</emphasis> in the Identify section of the
      menu.</para>

      <note>
        <para>This table is display-only. Technical assistance is required to
        modify responsibilities.</para>
      </note>

      <figure>
        <title>Responsibility Lookup</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_lookup.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>To find information about a Responsibility, enter information in
      one or more of the fields on the Lookup page and then click the Search
      button.</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>Responsibility Lookup Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Template Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The code identifying the application and
                module the template pertains to. Because responsibilities
                pertain to workflow, most responsibility templates are
                associated with the KR-WKFLW (Kuali Rice-Workflow)
                namespace.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Template Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The template the responsibility is based on.
                A template usually defines, in a broad sense, what the
                responsibility is. Since responsibilities normally are
                associated with action requests for user review, most
                responsibilities have a template name of "Review."</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Responsibility Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The code designating the application and
                module this responsibility is associated with. This code
                usually corresponds to the namespace of the document type for
                which the responsibility generates action requests.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Responsibility Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The name of this responsibility. In most
                cases, the responsibility name is the same as the associated
                template name ("Review"). Like permission names,
                responsibility names are not unique.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Role Namespace</entry>

                <entry>An indicator that associates the Role with a particular
                application and module. To search for a responsibility based
                on the namespace of the role to which it is assigned, enter
                the name of that namespace.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Role Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The name by which a Role is known in the
                system. To search for a responsibility based on the Role to
                which it is assigned, enter that Role name.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Principal Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. One of the principals that currently have
                this responsibility through their association with a
                role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Group Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The namespace of groups that have this
                responsibility through the group's association with a
                role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Group Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The name of a group that has this
                responsibility through its association with a role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Attribute Value</entry>

                <entry>Optional. A specific responsibility detail value
                associated with a responsibility</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>

      <figure>
        <title>Responsibility Look: Results</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_results.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>Responsibility Lookup: Resutls Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Responsibility Detail Values</entry>

                <entry><para>Display-only. Detailed information that
                defines:</para> <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                      <para>What document this responsibility generates action
                      requests for</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para>When the requests are generated</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para>How the requests are handled by workflow</para>
                    </listitem>
                  </itemizedlist><para>Unlike permissions, which sometimes
                have different detail values, responsibility detail values
                generally contain these elements:</para> <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">routeNodeName</emphasis>:
                      The point in a document's workflow routing at which this
                      responsibility generates requests.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">documentTypeName</emphasis>:
                      The name of the document type for which this
                      responsibility generates action requests. This value may
                      also be a parent document type, which indicates that
                      this responsibility applies to all child
                      documents.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis
                      role="bold">actionDetailsAtRoleMemberLevel</emphasis>: A
                      True or False indicator that defines where the system
                      collects details of this workflow action request. If the
                      value is True, the system collects action details when
                      members are assigned to the role. If the value is False,
                      the system collects action details when this
                      responsibility is assigned to a role.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">Required</emphasis>: A True
                      or False value that indicates whether the system is
                      required to generate an action request for this document
                      type. If the value is True and the document generates no
                      requests associated with this responsibility, then the
                      document will go into exception status. If the value is
                      False and the responsibility generates no action
                      requests, then the document continues to route as
                      normal.</para>
                    </listitem>
                  </itemizedlist></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Granted to Roles</entry>

                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Display-only</emphasis>. Lists
                the namespace and name of roles that have this responsibility.
                Click a linked name to view the Role Inquiry for that role
                name.</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Responsibility Inquiry</title>

      <para>To view the <emphasis role="bold">Responsibility
      Inquiry</emphasis> screen for a responsibility, click its <emphasis
      role="bold">Responsibility Name</emphasis> in the search results list
      displayed when you do a Responsibility Lookup. The Responsibility
      Inquiry screen contains the same information displayed in the search
      results, but in a slightly different format:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Responsibility Inquiry</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_inquiry.png"
                       scale="90"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The fields on this screen are documented in the Responsibility
      Lookup section above.</para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section>
    <title>Permission</title>

    <section>
      <title>Permission Lookup</title>

      <para>The Permission Lookup screen allows you to search for and view
      existing permissions. It displays summarized information about the
      permission detail values as well as the roles that are currently
      associated with this permission.</para>

      <note>
        <para>This table is display-only. Technical assistance is required to
        modify permissions.</para>
      </note>

      <para>You get to this screen by clicking <emphasis
      role="bold">Permissions</emphasis> in the <emphasis
      role="bold">Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis
      role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Permission Lookup</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_lookup.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Enter information in one or more fields on the <emphasis
      role="bold">Permission Lookup</emphasis> screen and then click the
      <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button to display permissions
      that match your information.</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>Permission Lookup Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Template Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The code identifying the application and
                module the template pertains to. Because templates tend to be
                general categories, they are often associated with
                system-level namespaces.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Template Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The template the permission is based on. A
                template usually defines, in a broad sense, what the
                permission controls. Similar types of permissions use the same
                template.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Permission Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The code designating the application and
                module this permission is associated with.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Permission Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The name of this permission. In most cases,
                the permission name is the same as its associated template
                name.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Role Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. An indicator that associates the role with a
                particular application and module.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Role Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The common descriptive name by which this
                role is known.</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Principal Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The principals that currently have this
                permission through their association with a role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Group Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The namespace of groups that have this
                permission through the groups' association with a role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Group Name</entry>

                <entry>Optional. The name of a group that has this permission
                through its association with a role</entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>Permission Detail Values</entry>

                <entry><para>Optional. Detailed information that, in
                combination with the permission name, defines the permission's
                function For example, if the permission name is <emphasis
                role="bold">Initiate Document</emphasis>, the <emphasis
                role="bold">Permission Detail Values</emphasis> field
                indicates the specific type of document the initiate
                permission pertains to. Permission detail values can include
                many different types of data. Some common permission
                details:</para> <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">documentTypeName</emphasis>:
                      The name of the document Type associated with this
                      permission.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">routeNodeName</emphasis>:
                      The point in a document's workflow routing at which this
                      permission becomes relevant.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">routeStatusCode</emphasis>:
                      The routing status that a document must be in for this
                      permission to apply.</para>
                    </listitem>

                    <listitem>
                      <para><emphasis role="bold">propertyName</emphasis>: A
                      field or document element that the permission pertains
                      to.</para>
                    </listitem>
                  </itemizedlist></entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>

      <para>When you click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button
      for a Permission Lookup, KIM displays your search results in a table
      like this:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Permission Lookup: Results Example</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_lookup_results.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The information in the search results table is display-only and is
      defined above. New field:</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>Permission Lookup: Results Attributes</title>

          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="0.5*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Field Name</entry>

                <entry>Description</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Granted to Roles</entry>

                <entry>Lists the namespace and name of roles that have this
                permission. Click on a linked name to view its Role Inquiry
                screen.</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Permission Inquiry</title>

      <para>To view the <emphasis role="bold">Permission Inquiry</emphasis>
      screen for a Permission, click the <emphasis role="bold">Permission
      Name</emphasis> in the search results from a Permission Lookup. The
      Permission Inquiry screen contains the same information as the
      Permission Lookup search results, but in a slightly different
      format:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Permission Inquiry</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_inquiry.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The fields on this screen are documented above in the <emphasis
      role="bold">Permission Lookup</emphasis> section.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Permission Template Inquiry</title>

      <para>This screen provides detailed information about a <emphasis
      role="bold">Template Namespace</emphasis>. To display it, click a
      <emphasis role="bold">Template Name</emphasis> on the <emphasis
      role="bold">Document Configuration</emphasis> screen or the <emphasis
      role="bold">Permission Inquiry</emphasis> screen.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Permission Template Inquiry</title>

        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_template_inquiry.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Information related to the fields on this screen can be found
      above, in the <emphasis role="bold">Permission Lookup</emphasis> section
      of this document.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Delivered Permission Templates</title>

      <para>Rice is delivered with a number of permission templates. Below is
      a listing of each along with a brief description of their use.</para>

      <para><table frame="none" tabstyle="striped">
          <title>Delivered Permission Templates</title>

          <tgroup cols="5">
            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="1.0*"/>

            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Template ID</entry>

                <entry>Template Namespace</entry>

                <entry>Template Name</entry>

                <entry>Permission Template Description</entry>

                <entry>Permission Details</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>

            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>1</entry>

                <entry>KUALI</entry>

                <entry>Default</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>2</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Copy Document</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>3</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Administer Routing for Document</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>4</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Blanket Approve Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to bypass specified approval route
                nodes</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>5</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Route Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to route a doucment from their action
                list</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>8</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Take Requested Action</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to take applicable actions (approve,
                disapprove, acknowledge, etc.) on documents in their action
                list.</entry>

                <entry><code>actionRequestCd=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>9</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Ad Hoc Review Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to review a doucment that has been sent
                to them via an Ad Hoc Request</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>10</entry>

                <entry>KR-SYS</entry>

                <entry>Initiate Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to create a new document</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>14</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Cancel Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes users to cancel a document prior to it being
                submitted for routing.</entry>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>documentTypeName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>routeNodeName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>15</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Save Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to save a document that has been
                initiated or routed to them for action back to their action
                list</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>16</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Edit Document</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>documentTypeName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>routeStatusCode=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>routeNodeName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>23</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Look Up Records</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>namespaceCode=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>componentName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>24</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Inquire Into Records</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>namespaceCode=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>componentName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>25</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>View Inquiry or Maintenance Document Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>26</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Modify Maintenance Document Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>27</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Full Unmask Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>propertyName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>componentName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>28</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Partial Unmask Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>29</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Use Screen</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>actionClass=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>namespaceCode=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>30</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Perform Custom Maintenance Document Function</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>31</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Use Transactional Document</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>32</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Modify Batch Job</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>33</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Upload Batch Input File(s)</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>34</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Maintain System Parameter</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>35</entry>

                <entry>KR-IDM</entry>

                <entry>Assign Role</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>36</entry>

                <entry>KR-IDM</entry>

                <entry>Grant Permission</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>37</entry>

                <entry>KR-IDM</entry>

                <entry>Grant Responsibility</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>38</entry>

                <entry>KR-IDM</entry>

                <entry>Populate Group</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>40</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Open Document</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>42</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Create / Maintain Record(s)</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>43</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>View Inquiry or Maintenance Document Section</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>44</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Modify Maintenance Document Section</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>45</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Add Note / Attachment</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to add a note / attachment to a
                document</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>46</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>View Note / Attachment</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to view notes and download
                attachments that have been added to a document</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>47</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Delete Note / Attachment</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to remove notes and attachments that
                have been added to a document</entry>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>documentTypeName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>createdBySelfOnly</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>49</entry>

                <entry>KR-NS</entry>

                <entry>Send Ad Hoc Request</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to create an action reques to user(s)
                outside the normal route chain</entry>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>actionRequestCd=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>documentTypeName=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>51</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Add Message to Route Log</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to add annotations to a document that
                appear in the Route Log of a document</entry>

                <entry><code>documentTypeName=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>52</entry>

                <entry>KR-RULE</entry>

                <entry>KRMS Agenda Permission</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes user to view and edit KRMS agendas</entry>

                <entry><code>namespaceCode=</code></entry>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>53</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Open View</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>54</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit View</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>55</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Use View</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>56</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>View Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>57</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit Field</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>58</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>View Group</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>59</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit Group</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>60</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>View Widget</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>61</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit Widget</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>62</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Perform Action</entry>

                <entry/>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>63</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>View Line</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to view the lines in a
                collection</entry>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>64</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit Line</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to edit the lines in a
                collection</entry>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>65</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>View Line Field</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to view the individual fields in the
                lines of a collection</entry>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>66</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Edit Line Field</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to edit the individual fields in the
                lines of a collection</entry>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>67</entry>

                <entry>KR-KRAD</entry>

                <entry>Perform Line Action</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to take actions (add, delete, edit,
                etc.) to the lines of a collection</entry>

                <entry/>
              </row>

              <row>
                <entry>68</entry>

                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>

                <entry>Recall Document</entry>

                <entry>Authorizes a user to recall a submitted document to
                their action list for edit and resubmission or
                cancellation</entry>

                <entry><para>
                     

                    <code>documentTypeName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>routeNodeName=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>routeStatusCode=</code>

                     
                  </para> <para>
                     

                    <code>appDocStatus=</code>

                     
                  </para></entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table></para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
