<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2012 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="UG_KIM" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>KIM</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>KIM Overview</title>
        <para>Kuali Identity Management (KIM) provides identity and access management services to
            Rice and other applications. All KIM services are available on the service bus with both
            SOAP and Java serialization endpoints. KIM provides a service layer and a set of GUIs
            that you can use to maintain the identity information. </para>
        <para>KIM is designed to be used with both Kuali and non-Kuali applications. The permissions
            and responsibilities it provides are defined by each user’s Role or Roles in the system.
            Roles can be customized to handle permissions and responsibilities in a variety of ways
            based on your particular needs.</para>
        <figure>
            <title>KIM Architecture</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_architecture.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject></figure>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Features</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KIM provides a reference implementation of the services but allows for
                        customization and/or replacement to facilitate integration with
                        institutional services or other third party identity management
                        solutions.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KIM allows you to override one or more of its core services. For example,
                        you could override the Identity Service, but not the Role Service.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KIM consists of these services, which encompass it’s API:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>AuthenticationService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>GroupService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>GroupUpdateService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>IdentityCacheService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>IdentityService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>IdentityUpdateService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>PermissionService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>PersonService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>ResponsibilityService </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>RoleService </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>KIM evaluates permissions through its permission service. KIM provides
                        plug points for implementing custom logic for permission checking, such as
                        permission checks based on hierarchical data.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>A more detailed picture of the KIM architecture:</para>
            <figure><title>Detailed KIM Achitecture</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_architecture_detailed.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>    
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Person</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Person Lookup</title>
            <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen to quickly find
                basic information about Persons in Kuali Rice (Rice). (In Kuali, a Person is a set
                of information about a real person or something that stands for real people, like a
                job title.) From the Person Lookup screen, you can also link to screens where you
                can create new Persons and edit a Person’s information if you have permission to do
                so. </para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Finding the Person Lookup Screen</title>
                <para>You can go to the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen from
                    many Kuali screens by clicking the field search button next to a Name-related
                    field. How you get to the Person Lookup screen and your <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Role</emphasis> in Kuali determine what you see and what you can do
                    there.</para>
                <para>If you have permission to use the Administration screens in Rice, you can go
                    directly to the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis>
                                tab</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Look under <emphasis role="bold">Identity</emphasis>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis>
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Person Lookup Options</title>
                <sect4>
                    <title>From the Field Search Button </title>
                    <para>If you clicked the field search button on another Kuali page to get to the
                    Person Lookup screen, your screen looks like this:</para>
                    <figure><title>Person Lookup</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_lookup.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>    
                    <para>To find a Person, enter some information about that person in the
                        appropriate fields and click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis>
                        button at the bottom of the screen.<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>You can display a list of all Persons in KIM if you leave the
                                    search fields empty and set the <emphasis role="bold">Active
                                        Indicator</emphasis> to <emphasis role="bold"
                                        >Both</emphasis>, then click the search button.</para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Rice displays a list of Persons who match your search
                                    information. The list is just below the search fields on the
                                    Person Lookup page:</para>
                                <figure><title>Person Lookup: Results</title>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_results.png"
                                                scale="85"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </figure>    
                                <para>Click one of the underlined column titles on the search
                                    results list to sort the list by that column. Click it again to
                                    sort the list in the opposite order.</para>
                                <para>You can also export the search results list in CSV,
                                    spreadsheet, or XML format. Click the appropriate link at the
                                    bottom of the search results list to do this.</para>
                                <para>If you need to see more information about one of the Persons
                                    in the search results list, click one of the information fields
                                    for that Person. Kuali then displays the <emphasis role="bold"
                                        >Person Document</emphasis> screen for that Person.</para>
                                <figure><title>Person Document</title>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_document.png"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </figure>
                                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Return Value</emphasis> column has a
                                        <emphasis role="bold">return value</emphasis> link for each
                                    person. Click this return value link for the Person whose
                                    information you need, and Kuali goes back to the screen you were
                                    on before and automatically enters the information about that
                                    person on the screen for you.</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>From the Administration Tab</title>
                    <para>If you come to the <emphasis role="bold">Person Lookup</emphasis> screen
                        after clicking <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis> (under <emphasis
                            role="bold">Identity</emphasis>) on the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >Administration</emphasis> tab, you see a <emphasis role="bold">create
                            new</emphasis> button in the upper right corner of your screen, like
                        this:</para>
                    <figure><title>Person Lookup: Create New Button</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_lookup_create_new.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>You can click this create new button to go to the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >Person Document</emphasis> screen, where you can add a new Person as a
                        Kuali user. For more information on adding a Person, see the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Person Maintenance</emphasis> function section (next) in
                        this User Guide.</para>
                    <para>If you need to edit information for a Person in KIM, you first need to
                        display that Person’s information. Search for the Person (see search
                        instructions above) from the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis>
                        tab’s link for <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis>. When Kuali displays
                        the list of Persons that match your search, you’ll notice one difference in
                        the columns because you did your search from the Administration tab – there
                        is an <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column on the left.</para>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column has an <emphasis
                            role="bold">edit</emphasis> link for each person. Click this edit link
                        to go to the <emphasis role="bold">Person Document</emphasis> screen where
                        you can edit this Person’s information. For more information on working with
                        Person information, see the <emphasis role="bold">Person
                            Maintenance</emphasis> section (next) in this User Guide.</para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
       </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Person Maintenance</title>
            <para>The Person Document allows you to identify and maintain each user in KIM. Each
                Person Document includes data about that user’s relationship with your
                institution as well as the roles and groups to which the person belongs.</para>
            <para>In KIM, a Person is a unique combination of an <emphasis role="italic">Entity
                    ID</emphasis> and a <emphasis role="italic">Principal ID</emphasis>. The
                Entity ID represents a Person with a unique number, and the Person Document
                associates the Entity ID with the user’s Principal ID number and Principal Name
                (often referred to as a user name or user ID). When searching for or working
                with users in KIM, you usually use either the Principal ID or the Principal
                Name. A single Entity ID can have multiple Principals associated with it, but
                the base implementation of KIM assumes that each Entity ID has only a single
                Principal. </para>
            <note>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Person and HR Systems</emphasis>: Many institutions
                    choose to override parts of the Person Document (especially the affiliation
                    and contact information) with data from an HR system.</para>  
            </note>
            <sect3>
                <title>Business Rules</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Each Person must have at least one Affiliation. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Each faculty or staff affiliation must have at least one Employment
                            Information record associated with it. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If a Person has any faculty or staff affiliations, then one Employment
                            Information record must be marked as Primary. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Each Person must have a default Name record in the Contacts section.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Each affiliation must be associated with a Campus. • Each type of
                            contact information can have only one record marked as the default.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Routing</title>
                <para>Only people with the appropriate role can initiate routing for Person
                    documents. </para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Displaying the Person Lookup Screen</title>
            <para>On the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis> tab, click <emphasis
                    role="bold">Person</emphasis> to display the <emphasis role="bold">Person
                    Lookup</emphasis> screen. Do a lookup to see a list of Persons. Click any Person
                on the search results list to display his or her <emphasis role="bold">Person
                    Document</emphasis> screen.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Layout</title>
                <para>The Person Document includes <emphasis role="bold">Document Overview,
                        Overview, Contact, Privacy Preferences, Membership, Ad Hoc
                        Recipients</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">Route Log</emphasis> tabs. </para>
                <figure><title>Person Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_document2.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Overview Tab</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Document Overview</emphasis> tab combined with the
                    Overview tab identifies the <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis> as a unique
                    combination of Entity and Principal ID. </para>
                <para>Additional information on the <emphasis role="bold">Document Overview
                        Tab</emphasis> can be found in the Common Features and Functions section of
                    this User Guide.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Overview Tab</title>
                <para>The Overview tab identifies the <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis> as a
                    unique combination of <emphasis role="bold">Entity ID</emphasis> and <emphasis
                        role="bold">Principal ID</emphasis>. It also contains information about how
                    this Person is affiliated with your institution. Two types of
                        affiliations—<emphasis role="bold">Staff</emphasis> and <emphasis
                        role="bold">Faculty</emphasis>—contain additional data fields to further
                    define a person’s relationship with your institution. </para>
                <para>The instructions below assume that you are manually entering this information.
                    Many institutions either have this data fed from an existing Person database or
                    simply override this information with existing Person data.</para>
                <figure><title>Person Document: Overview Section</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_overview_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Overview Section</title>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Entity Id</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique ID number identifying this
                                            Person in your database. An individual may have multiple
                                            Principal IDs but only one Entity ID. The base
                                            implementation assumes that each user has only one Entity ID
                                            and one Principal ID. KIM automatically assigns an Entity Id
                                            to a new Person when you save or submit a Person Document.
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Principal Id</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique ID number identifying this
                                            Principal. Whereas Entity Id represents a unique Person,
                                            Principal Id represents a set of login information for that
                                            Person. When selecting a Person, you ordinarily reference
                                            his or her Principal Id. KIM automatically assigns a
                                            Principal Id to a new Person when you save or submit the
                                            Person Document. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Principal Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The user name for this Principal</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Tax Identification Number</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Enter the Individual Tax Identification Number
                                            (ITIN) for this Principal ID</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Principal Password</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the password for this Principal
                                            ID</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Principal ID is
                                            Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this Principal ID
                                            is Inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            under <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> to save the
                                            information you enter in this section.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Affiliations Section</title>
                    <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Affiliations</emphasis> section of the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Overview</emphasis> tab to add Affiliations for this Principal
                        ID. Depending on the Affiliation type you select, you may need to complete
                        additional fields.</para>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes, Affiliations</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Affiliation Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the Type of Affiliation from the list. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Affiliate</emphasis>:
                                                      Users in your system who are neither employees nor
                                                      students </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Faculty</emphasis>: A
                                                      faculty employee </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Staff</emphasis>: A
                                                      non-faculty employee </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Student</emphasis>: A
                                                      non-employee identified as a student of your
                                                      institution </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist>
                                            <para>
                                          Affiliation types of Faculty and Staff require additional information (see below).</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Select the Campus Code associated with this
                                            Affiliation</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Default</entry>
                                        <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Affiliation is this
                                            Principal’s default association with your institution. Each
                                            Principal must have at least one default Affiliation. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button to
                                            save the affiliation information.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                    <para>If you select an Affiliation of Faculty or Staff, KIM displays additional
                        fields to collect employment information: </para>
                    <figure><title>Person Document: Overview Tab, Affiliations Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/faculty_staff_affiliate_fields.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Overview Attributes, Affiliations
                                Continued</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry/>
                                        <entry/>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Employment ID</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the Employment ID number associated with
                                            this Faculty or Staff affiliation. Ordinarily this entry is
                                            the ID number identifying this Principal in your HR
                                            system.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Primary</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Faculty or Staff
                                            affiliation represents the Principal’s primary job with your
                                            institution. Each Principal with a Faculty or Staff
                                            affiliation must have exactly one affiliation marked as
                                            Primary. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Employee Status</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Required. Select the current status of this Faculty or Staff affiliation. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Active </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Deceased </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>On Non-Pay Leave </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Status Not Yet Processed </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Processing </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Retired </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Terminated </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Employee Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Required. Select the type of employment for this Affiliation. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para> Non-Professional </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Other </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                    <para>Professional </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Base Salary Amount</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Enter the base annual salary for this Faculty
                                            or Staff Affiliation. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Primary Department Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the code for the Department associated
                                            with this Faculty or Staff affiliation.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Add</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button to
                                            save this row of employment information.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>    
            <sect3>
                <title>Contact Tab</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Contact</emphasis> tab records the names, addresses,
                    phone numbers, and email addresses associated with this Person. Any Person
                    record can store multiple contact information records of each type (name,
                    address, phone number, and email address). You must select one value of each
                    type as the default for that Person record.</para>
                <figure><title>Person Document: Contact Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_contact_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Names Section</title>
                    <figure><title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Names Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/person_names_section.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Names Section Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Name Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of name to be added in this
                                            row. Options:</para><itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Other </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Preferred </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Primary </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Title</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the appropriate title for the name
                                        being added in this row. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Ms </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Mrs </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Mr </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Dr </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>First Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the first name for this
                                            record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Last Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the last name for this
                                            record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Suffix</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select a suffix for this name record. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Jr </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Sr </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Mr </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>MD</para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Default</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Name record is
                                            the default for this person. Each Person record must
                                            have exactly one Name record identified as the default.
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check the box to indicate that this Name record is
                                            Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this record
                                            should be considered Inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to save this Name record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Addresses Section</title>
                    <figure><title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Addresses Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/addresses_section.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document:  Contact Tab, Address Section Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Address Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of address being added on
                                        this row. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Home </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Other </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Work </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Line 1 to 3</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Use lines 1, 2, and 3 to enter the street
                                            address for this row.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>City</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the city associated with this
                                            address.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>State</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Select the state associated with this
                                            address from the list.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Postal Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the postal code (zip code in the
                                            U.S.) associated with this address.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Select the country associated with this
                                            address.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Default</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate this address record should
                                            be used as the Default. A Person record can have only
                                            one Default Address record. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Address record
                                            is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this record
                                            is Inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to save this Address record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Phone Numbers Section</title>
                    <figure><title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Phone Numbers Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/phone_numbers_section.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Phone Numbers Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Phone Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of phone number being added on this row. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Home </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Mobile </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Other </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Work </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Phone Number</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the area code and phone
                                            number.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Extension</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the appropriate extension.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Select the country associated with this
                                            Phone Number record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Default</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Phone Number
                                            record should be used as the Default. A Person record
                                            can have only one default Phone Number record. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Phone Number
                                            record is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this
                                            record is inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to save this Phone Number record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Email Addresses Section</title>
                    <figure><title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Email Addresses Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/email_addresses_section.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Contact Tab, Email Address Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Email</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the email address for this
                                            record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Select the type of email address on this row. Options:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Home </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Other </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>Work </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Default</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Email Address
                                            record should be used as the Default. A Person record
                                            can have only one default Email Address record. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Email Address
                                            record is Active. Uncheck the box to indicate that this
                                            record is Inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to save this Email Address record.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Privacy Preferences Tab</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Privacy Preferences</emphasis> tab allows you to
                    suppress the display of (hide) fields on the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Contact</emphasis> Tab. </para>
                <figure><title>Person Document: Privacy Preferences Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/privacy_preferences_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Person Document: Privacy Preferences Tab Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Suppress Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display this
                                        person’s names.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Suppress Personal</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display any of
                                        this person’s personal data.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Suppress Phone</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display this
                                        person’s phone numbers.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Suppress Address</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display this
                                        person’s addresses.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Suppress Email</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Check this box to specify NOT to display this
                                        person’s email addresses.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Membership Tab</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Membership Tab</emphasis> allows you to associate a
                    person with groups and roles and, by extension, with KIM permissions and
                    responsibilities. Assigning a person to a role is the most direct way to give
                    him or her KIM permissions and responsibilities.</para>
                <figure><title>Person Document: Memberships Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/membership_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The Membership tab is divided into two sections, one for managing assignments
                    to <emphasis role="bold">Groups</emphasis> and another for <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Roles</emphasis>.</para>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Groups Section</title>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Memeberships Tab, Groups Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Group</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter the name of the KIM group you want to
                                            assign this person to. You can also use the Group lookup
                                            to search for and select a valid Group. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                                            person to, KIM displays the namespace code associated
                                            with the group you selected.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                                            person to, KIM displays the name of that group. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a group to add this
                                            person to, KIM displays the type of that group.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active From Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. If this user’s assignment to this group is
                                            to be effective as of a certain date, enter that date
                                            here.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active To Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. If this user’s assignment to this group is
                                            to terminate as of a certain date, enter that date
                                            here.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add this group assignment.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                    <note><para>There is no way to delete a person’s assignment to a group. To remove a
                        person from a group, use the Active To Date field to specify a date in the
                        past.</para></note>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Roles Section</title>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Person Document: Memeberships Tab, Roles Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Role</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Use the Name lookup to search for and
                                            select the role you want to assign this person
                                            to.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                                            this Person record, KIM displays the namespace code
                                            associated with that role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                                            this Person record, KIM displays the name associated
                                            with that role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. After you select a role to assign to
                                            this Person record, KIM displays the role type for the
                                            selected role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active From Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. If this user’s assignment to this role is
                                            to be effective as of a certain date, enter that date
                                            here.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active To Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. If this user’s assignment to this role is
                                            to terminate as of a certain date, enter that date
                                            here.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to save this role data.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>                    
                    <note><para>There is no way to delete a person’s assignment to a role. To remove a
                        person from a role, use the Active To Date field to specify a date in the
                        past.</para></note>
                    <para>When assigning some roles, you may need to supply additional qualifying
                        information that further defines this person’s assignment. For more
                        information on Roles see the Role Maintenance section in this User
                        Guide.</para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Ad Hoc Recipients Tab</title>
            <para>Ad Hoc Recipients tab information can be found in the Common Features and
                Functions section of this User Guide.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Route Log Tab</title>
            <para>Route Log tab information can be found in the Common Features and Functions
                section of this User Guide.</para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Group</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Group Lookup Screen</title>
            <para>The Group Lookup function provides a quick reference to key Group
                information.</para>
            <para>You get to this screen by clicking the <emphasis role="bold">Group</emphasis>
                option in the <emphasis role="bold">Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Administration</emphasis> screen.</para>
            <figure><title>Identity Channel: Group Link</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/select_group.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <figure><title>Group Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/group_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>On the <emphasis role="bold">Group Lookup</emphasis> screen, click the <emphasis
                    role="bold">create new</emphasis> button to go to the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Group Maintenance</emphasis> screen, where you can create a new Group in Rice. </para>
            <para>Conducting a search from the Group Lookup screen returns a list similar to
                this:</para>
            <figure><title>Group Lookup: Results</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/group_lookup_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>For information on any of the fields above, please refer to the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Group Maintenance</emphasis> section below.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Group Inquiry Screen</title>
            <para>This screen provides high-level information about a Group and shows who is
                assigned to it.</para>
            <para>Click a <emphasis role="bold">Group Request</emphasis> value on the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Action List</emphasis> screen to display the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Group Inquiry</emphasis> page for that Group:</para>
            <figure><title>Group Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/group_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <sect3>
                <title>Overview Tab</title>
                <para>For information on these fields please refer to the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Group Maintenance</emphasis> section that follows.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Assignees Tab</title>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Group Inquiry: Assignees Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Type Code</entry>
                                    <entry>The code for the type of this Group member</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Member Identifier</entry>
                                    <entry>The user ID for the Member</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry>The user name for the Member</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active From Dt</entry>
                                    <entry>The effective date of membership in this Group for this
                                        member; if it is blank, membership is valid as soon as the
                                        member is assigned This field is useful when you want to add
                                        a Person, Role, or Group to a Group before he/she/they
                                        should be active in the Group. This might happen, for
                                        example, when you add a new employee before their start
                                        date. </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active To Dt</entry>
                                    <entry>The termination date of membership for this member; if
                                        blank, the membership does not terminate</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Group Maintenance Document</title>
            <para>The Group document allows you to associate Persons, Roles, or other Groups with
                each other so you can assign the same role to all Group members. </para>
            <para>Groups have no inherent permissions or responsibilities of their own. Only by
                associating a Group with a role do the members of that Group become associated with
                permissions and responsibilities.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Creating New Groups</title>
                <para>If you are creating a new Group and have clicked the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Create New</emphasis> button on the Group Lookup screen, Rice displays the
                        <emphasis role="bold">KIM Type Lookup</emphasis> screen. Before Rice can
                    generate a new Group document, you must search for and select an existing Type
                    for the new Group.</para>
                <figure><title>KIM Type Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject></figure>
                <note>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Always use this KIM Type Lookup screen when you create a
                            new Group or Role.</emphasis>
                    </para>
                    <para>If you search for a Type using the <emphasis role="bold">Group
                            Lookup</emphasis> screen, the search results list doesn’t have <emphasis
                            role="bold">return value</emphasis> links, so you can’t use the Group Lookup
                        screen when you want to create a new Group or Role.</para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>KIM Type Lookup Search Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Select the code for the application and module
                                        to which this KIM Type pertains.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Type Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Enter the name for this KIM Type. </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Type Identifier</entry>
                                    <entry>Optional. Enter the unique system-assigned Identifier for
                                        this KIM Type.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                    <entry>Required (defaults to Yes). Change the default selection
                                        to view KIM types that are inactive or to see all Types
                                        (active and inactive). </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">The search results list includes the same fields as the
                        Lookup screen. </emphasis>The search results are displayed below the search
                    fields on the Lookup screen.</para>
                <para>To select the Type you want to use for your new Group, click the return value
                    link for that Type. KIM will copy the Type information to use in creating your
                    new Group.</para>
                <para>The KIM Type Lookup screen displaying a search result:</para>
                <figure><title>Kim Type Lookup: Results Set</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/kim_type_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Group Maintenance Document: Layout</title>
                <para>The Group document includes these tabs:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Document Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Assignees </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Route Log </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>The Overview and Assignees tabs are described below. Information on the others
                    can be found in the Common Features and Functions section of this User
                    Guide.</para>
                <figure><title>Group Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/group_maintenance_document.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Overview Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab identifies the Group with a unique system-assigned ID number, a
                        namespace, and a name. Each Group also has a Type that specifies any
                        qualifiers that this Group might require. </para>
                    <figure><title>Group Maintenance Document: Group Overview</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/group_overview.png" scale="85"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject></figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Group Maintenance Document: Group Overview Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Group ID</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                                            that identifies this Group; Rice completes this field
                                            when you submit the document.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type Name</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Required. The type of attributes that are associated
                                            with this Group. Some Group types, such as the Default
                                            Type, do not require attributes.</para>
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>When creating a new Group, you must select the Type before Rice can generate the document.  See the Creating New Groups section of this document</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Group Namespace</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. An indicator that associates the Group with
                                            a particular application and module</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Group Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The common descriptive name by which this
                                            Group is known</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Group is active
                                            and is a valid choice for assigning to roles. Uncheck
                                            the box to indicate that this Group is inactive (it is
                                            no longer valid when making role assignments).</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Assignees Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab displays the members who belong to this Group. You can also use
                        this tab to add new members or to edit the fields for existing members. </para>
                    <para>Note that for members not added to the group on this maintenance document,
                        the “delete” button to remove that member is inactive. If a member’s
                        association with a group is past, users should set the “Active To Date”
                        field to the end of the membership; the member will not be an active member
                        of the group after that date.</para>
                    <figure><title>Group Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/assignees_tab.png" scale="85"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Group Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry/>
                                        <entry/>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Type Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Select the Type of the member you are
                                            adding to this Group. Group members can be Principals
                                            (as defined on the Person document), Roles, or other
                                            Groups.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Enter the ID that identifies the member you
                                            are adding, or use the lookup to search for and select a
                                            valid Member ID. The lookup directs you to the <emphasis
                                                role="bold">Principal</emphasis>, <emphasis
                                                role="bold">Group</emphasis>, or <emphasis
                                                role="bold">Role</emphasis> lookup, based on your
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Member Type Code</emphasis>
                                            selection.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active From Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. To specify the earliest date on which this
                                            member is to be considered a valid member of this Group,
                                            enter a date in this field.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active To Date</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. To specify a date on which this member is
                                            no longer to be considered a valid member of this Group,
                                            enter a date in this field. As of this date, the Member
                                            will no longer be considered a member of this
                                            Group.</para>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You cannot delete or inactivate Group members. To remove a member from a Group, enter an
                                                  Active To Date.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add this member to the Group.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Role</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Role Lookup Screen</title>
            <para>This screen provides detailed information relating to the Permissions assigned to
                a <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis> in KIM.</para>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis> screen is accessible directly off
                the Rice <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu by clicking <emphasis
                    role="bold">Role</emphasis> in the Identity section.</para>
            <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Granted to Roles</emphasis> field on the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Document Configuration</emphasis> screen to display the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis> screen. You can also access the Role Lookup
                screen by clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Granted to Roles</emphasis> value in any
                list where it appears.</para>
            <figure><title>Role Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/role_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Layout</title>
                <para>This screen may have three or four tabs of information, depending on the Role.
                    The first three tabs are <emphasis role="bold">Overview</emphasis>, <emphasis
                        role="bold">Permissions</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Responsibilities</emphasis>. KIM only displays the fourth tab, <emphasis
                        role="bold">Assignees</emphasis>, when Assignee information is associated
                    with this <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis>.</para>
                <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/role_maintenance_document.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Information on the fields in all of these tabs can be found in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Role Maintenance</emphasis> section of this user guide.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Role Maintenance Document</title>
            <para>The Role Maintenance Document allows you to create a new KIM Role and edit
                existing Roles. Each Role collects a specific set of Permissions and
                Responsibilities and allows you to assign members to it. </para>
            <para>The purpose of each Role is defined by its associated Permissions and
                Responsibilities. Roles are classified by <emphasis role="bold">Types</emphasis>
                that generally indicate with which Permissions and Responsibilities they are
                associated. </para>
            <note><para>The process of creating a new Type for Roles requires technical assistance. </para></note>
            <para>To access the <emphasis role="bold">Role</emphasis> screen:<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Do a <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis>. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Find the Role you want to change in the list of search results.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Edit</emphasis> for the row that has the
                            Role that you need to change. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Role Maintenance Document</title>
                <para>The Role document includes eight tabs:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Document Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Permissions </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Responsibilities </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Assignees </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Delegations </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Route Log </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>Those contains unique information are addressed below. For more information
                    about the Document Overview, Ad Hoc Recipients and Route Log tabs, please see
                    the <emphasis role="bold">Common Features and Functions</emphasis>
                    document.</para>
                <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Tabs</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_tabs.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Overview Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab gives the Role a unique system-assigned ID number, a Namespace,
                        and a Name. Each Role also has a Type that usually matches the kinds of
                        Permissions and Responsibilities associated with it. </para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Overview Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_overview.png" scale="90"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Doucment: Overview Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Role Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique, system-assigned ID number
                                            that identifies this Role</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type Name</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Display-only. The Type Name usually identifies the
                                            general kinds of Permissions and Responsibilities
                                            associated with this Role.</para>
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis> When creating a new Role, you must select its Type before you can display a new Role
                                                  document. See Creating New Roles below.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Role Namespace</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. An indicator that associates the Role with
                                            a particular application and module</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Role Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The common descriptive name by which this
                                            Role is known</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that this Role is Active
                                            and is, therefore, to be included by KIM when it
                                            evaluates Permissions and Responsibilities. Uncheck the
                                            Active box to indicate that this Role is
                                            inactive.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Creating New Roles</title>
                    <para>You must search for and select an existing Type for KIM to generate a new
                        Role document. When you click the Create New button, KIM displays the
                            <emphasis role="bold">KIM Type Lookup</emphasis> screen:</para>
                    <figure><title>KIM Type Lookup</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <note><para>While you use the KIM Type Lookup screen both for creating new Groups and
                        new Roles, not all KIM Types are valid for both Groups and Roles. When using
                        this Lookup, you may see different results depending on the KIM Types that
                        are appropriate for your task. </para></note>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Permissions Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab identifies the Permissions associated with this Role. Permissions
                        authorize specific actions in the system with which they are associated. A
                        Role can have any number of Permissions (including no Permissions)
                        associated with it. </para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_permissions.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Add Permission ID</entry>
                                        <entry>To add a Permission to this Role, enter the
                                            appropriate Permission ID, or search for and select a
                                            value using the <emphasis role="bold"
                                                >Permission</emphasis> lookup </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Add</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add the selected Permission to this Role
                                            document.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                    <para>After you add a Permission to the document, KIM displays additional
                        information about the Permission:</para>
                    <note><para>You <emphasis role="italic">cannot</emphasis> edit Permissions from the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Role Maintenance Document</emphasis>.</para>
                    </note>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tab, Add Permissions</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_add_permission.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Permissions Tabb, Add
                                Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Permission Namespace</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The Namespace identifies the
                                            application and module associated with this
                                            Permission.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Permission Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                                            for this Permission </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Permission Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The descriptive name of this
                                            Permission. This often tells you, in general terms, what
                                            the Permission authorizes.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Permission Detail Values</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The document Types, tabs, and/or fields
                                            that this Permission authorizes the holder to see or
                                            use. Not all Permissions have Detail Values.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. Indicator showing whether this
                                            Permission is active in KIM</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Delete</emphasis>
                                           button to remove this Permission from this Role.</para>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">Warning: </emphasis>You may delete a Permission from a Role only if it has not yet been saved. (In other words,
                                                  you can delete a Permission from a Role only if
                                                  you added it to this Role, but have not yet
                                                  submitted the document.)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Responsibilities Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab identifies the Responsibilities associated with this Role.
                        Responsibilities define the workflow actions that will be requested of the
                        Role. A Role can have any number of Responsibilities (including none)
                        associated with it.</para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibilities Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibilities.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Add Responsibility ID</entry>
                                        <entry>To add a Responsibility to this Role, enter the
                                            Responsibility ID, or search for and select a value
                                            using the Responsibility lookup .</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Add button</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add the selected Responsibility to this Role
                                            document.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                    <para>After you add a Responsibility to the document, KIM displays additional
                        information about this Responsibility. </para>
                    <note><para>In general, you cannot edit Responsibilities using the Role document, but
                        some Responsibilities have associated attributes that you must define at the
                        Role level.</para></note>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility, Added Responsibility</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibility_added.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility, Add Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Responsibility Namespace</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The Namespace tells you the application
                                            and module associated with this Responsibility.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Responsibility Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The unique system-assigned ID number
                                            for this Responsibility</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Responsibility Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The descriptive name of this
                                            Responsibility. For most Responsibilities, the name is
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Review</emphasis>.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Responsibility Detail Values</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Display-only. This gives you more specific
                                            information about the Responsibility. Responsibility
                                            Detail Values are formatted in a standard way with these
                                            attributes, separated by commas:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para><emphasis role="bold">Route Node</emphasis>:
                                                  The location where this Responsibility is invoked
                                                  in Workflow. </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para><emphasis role="bold">Document
                                                  Type</emphasis>: The Document Type for which this
                                                  Responsibility generates workflow requests.
                                                  </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para><emphasis role="bold">Action Details at Role
                                                  Member Level</emphasis>: When this field is True,
                                                  action details are kept for each Member of this
                                                  Role. When this field is False, action details are
                                                  only kept at the Responsibility level for this
                                                  Role. (see Assigning Action Detail Values, below).
                                                  </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para><emphasis role="bold">Required</emphasis>:
                                                  Indicates if the routing represented by this
                                                  Responsibility should be required. If this is set
                                                  to True and the Responsibility fails to generate
                                                  an Action Request (perhaps because no one is
                                                  assigned to the associated Role), then the
                                                  document will go into Exception status. If this
                                                  routing is optional, this will be False and the
                                                  document will simply skip this Responsibility if
                                                  no requests are generated. </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. Indicator showing whether this
                                            Responsibility is active within the system</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Click the Delete button to remove this Responsibility from this Role.</para> 
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Warning: </emphasis>You can delete a Responsibility only if it has not yet been saved to the database (in other
                                                  words, you can only delete it if you have added it
                                                  to this Role but have not yet submitted the
                                                  document).</para></entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Assigning Action Detail Values</title>
                    <para>When you add a Responsibility with an <emphasis role="bold">Action Detail
                            Values at Role Member Level</emphasis> value of <emphasis role="bold"
                            >False</emphasis>, you must complete additional fields in a
                        Responsibility Action sub-section. KIM automatically displays this
                        sub-section immediately beneath the Responsibility you’ve just added.</para>
                    <para>The fields in this sub-section define the type of Action Requests
                        generated for, and the general workflow behavior associated with, this
                        Responsibility. Entries in these fields cause KIM to generate the same Type
                        of Action Requests for all members of this Role and handle actions by all
                        members of this Role in the same way.</para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility Tab, Action Section</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_responsibility_action.png"
                                    scale="90"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Responsibility Tab, Action Section
                                Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The namespace and name of the
                                            Responsibility associated with these action
                                            details</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Action Type Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The Type of Action Request that KIM
                                            generates for this Responsibility. Action Type Codes
                                            are: Approve, FYI, and Acknowledge.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Priority Number</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. If multiple requests are generated at the
                                            route node specified on this Responsibility, this
                                            determines the order in which KIM generates these
                                            requests. KIM processes requests with lower priority
                                            numbers before processing requests with higher numbers.
                                            Requests with no number are treated as a priority
                                            1.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Action Policy Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. This determines what happens if multiple
                                            members of this Role receive the same Action Request and
                                            one of them takes the action. For example, if a Role has
                                            a Group with three members assigned, all of these
                                            members receive the Action Request defined here; this
                                            code then determines what KIM does when one of them
                                            takes action on the document. A value of <emphasis
                                                role="italic">FIRST</emphasis> indicates that the
                                            first Group member to take action on the document causes
                                            KIM to clear all the requests for this Responsibility
                                            that may be in other Group member’s action lists. A
                                            value of <emphasis role="italic">ALL</emphasis>
                                            indicates that each Group member must take individual
                                            action to clear his or her own requests. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Force Action</entry>
                                        <entry>Check this box to indicate that each user must take
                                            action for this request, even if the user has previously
                                            taken action on this document. Leaving the box unchecked
                                            allows a request to be immediately fulfilled if the Role
                                            member has previously taken action on this specific
                                            document.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Assignees Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab displays all members who belong to this Role. You may also use
                        the tab to add new members and to edit the values associated with existing
                        members.</para>
                    <para>Just as with group, role members not added by the specific maintenance
                        document will have their “delete” buttons inactivated. To end that member’s
                        active association with the group, set the “Active To Date” field to the end
                        of the membership.</para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_assignees.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Assignees Tab Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Type Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Role members can be Principals (as defined
                                            on the Person document), Groups, or other Roles. Select
                                            the Type of member you want to add to this Role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Enter the ID of the member you want to add,
                                            or use the lookup to search for and select a Member. The
                                            lookup icon displays the <emphasis role="bold"
                                                >Principal</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold"
                                                >Group</emphasis>, or <emphasis role="bold"
                                                >Role</emphasis> Lookup screen based on the
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Type Code you selected for
                                                this Role member</emphasis>.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Namespace Cd</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. Identifies the namespace code
                                            associated with this Role member. Note that only Groups
                                            and Roles display a namespace code.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. Identifies the name of the member you
                                            are assigning to this Role</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active From Dt</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Enter a <emphasis role="bold">Active
                                                From</emphasis> date to define the earliest date on
                                            which this member is a valid member of this
                                            Role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active To Dt</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Allows you to deactivate a member’s
                                            association with a Role on a specific date. Enter the
                                            date the user is no longer a member of this
                                            Role.</para>
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You cannot delete or inactivate Role members. To remove a member from a Role, enter an
                                                  <emphasis role="bold">Active To
                                                  Dt.</emphasis></para></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add this member to the Role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Delegations Tab</title>
                    <para>This tab defines and identifies Delegates associated with this Role.
                        Delegates are users that a member of this Role has authorized to have the
                        same Permissions and take the same actions as that member is authorized to
                        take. For example, a manager may make someone a Delegate for his or her
                        actions in a particular Role.</para>
                    <para>The Assignees Tab dealing with Delegates is slightly different, as shown
                        in the following table. Note that if the members of a Role require
                        qualifying values, the delegation requires these values as well. In most
                        cases, Delegates must have the same qualifiers as the Role member with which
                        they are associated.</para>
                    <para>Just as with Group and Role Associations, delegations added outside of the
                        current maintenance document have inactive “delete” buttons and must have
                        the “Active To Date” field set to end the delegation.</para>
                    <figure><title>Role Maintenance Document: Delegations Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/role_delegations.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Role Maintenance Document: Delegations Tab Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Role Member</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Use the lookup to search for, and return,
                                            the Member of this Role for whom you wish to create a
                                            Delegate.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Type Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Select the <emphasis role="bold"
                                                >Type</emphasis> of Delegate you want to add to this
                                            Role. Delegates may be Principals (as defined on the
                                            Person document), Groups, or other Roles.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Identifier</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Enter the ID that identifies the Delegate
                                            you want to add, or use the lookup to search for and
                                            select a Delegate. Note that the lookup takes you to the
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Principal</emphasis>,
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Group</emphasis>, or<emphasis
                                                role="bold"> Role Lookup</emphasis> screen,
                                            depending on the Member Type Code you selected.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Namespace Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The namespace of this Delegate. Note
                                            that only delegations to Groups or Roles display a
                                            Member Namespace Code.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Member Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Display-only. The name of the selected
                                            Delegate</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active From Date</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. You may choose to qualify this Delegate’s
                                            association with this Role by date. Entering an
                                                <emphasis role="bold">Active From Date</emphasis> is
                                            the earliest date on which this Delegate is valid for
                                            this Role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active To Date</entry>
                                        <entry><para>Optional. Allows you to deactivate a Delegate’s
                                            association with a Role on a specific date. The date you
                                            enter is the date on which this user is no longer a
                                            Delegate for this Role.</para>
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You <emphasis role="italic">cannot</emphasis> delete or deactivate Delegates. To remove a
                                                  Delegate from a Role, enter an <emphasis
                                                  role="bold">Active To Date</emphasis>.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Delegation Type Code</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Select <emphasis role="italic"
                                                >Secondary</emphasis> or <emphasis role="italic"
                                                >Primary</emphasis>. Note that this selection only
                                            applies to Responsibilities associated with the Role.
                                            This indicates whether the Delegate automatically
                                            receives documents directly in their Action List
                                                (<emphasis role="italic">Primary</emphasis>) or if
                                            the Delegate may only choose to view documents in their
                                            Action List using the <emphasis role="bold">Secondary
                                                Delegate</emphasis> dropdown (<emphasis
                                                role="italic">Secondary</emphasis>). </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Actions</entry>
                                        <entry>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Add</emphasis> button
                                            to add this Delegate to this Role.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>KIM Type</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Type Lookup</title>
            <para>Use this lookup when you create a new group in KIM to find the KIM Type for the
                new group. </para>
            <figure><title>KIM Type Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/Kim_type_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>You may enter information in one or more of the search fields to find the correct
                Type for your new group:</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>KIM Type Lookup Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. Select the code of the application and module for
                                    this KIM Type. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Type Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. Enter the name for this KIM Type. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Type Identifier</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. Enter the unique system-assigned Identifier for
                                    this KIM Type.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                <entry>Required. Defaults to Yes (Yes means display only Active
                                    Types). Change the default selection to view KIM Types that are
                                    Inactive or Types that are both Active and Inactive. </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
            <figure><title>KIM Type Lookup: Results Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/kim_type_lookup_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The search results list for this screen has the same fields as the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Lookup</emphasis> screen. To select the Type you want to use for
                your new group, click the <emphasis role="bold">return value</emphasis> link for it
                in the search results list.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Type Inquiry</title>
            <para>The KIM Type Inquiry screen provides details about a KIM Type data element.</para>
            <para>To access this screen, from the <emphasis role="bold">Role Lookup</emphasis>
                screen, click a <emphasis role="bold">Role Type Name</emphasis> in your search
                results list.</para>
            <figure><title>KIM Type Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/kim_type.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>All fields are defined above in <emphasis role="italic">KIM Type Lookup</emphasis>
                except these:</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>KIM Type Inquiry Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Service Name</entry>
                                <entry>Display-only. The name of the service associated with this
                                    KIM Type</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Namespace Code</entry>
                                <entry>Display-only. The namespace code associated with the selected
                                    KIM Type</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Responsibility</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Responsibility Lookup</title>
            <para>Similar to the Permission Lookup, you can use the Responsibility Lookup to search
                for and view existing responsibilities in KIM. You can view summarized information
                about the responsibility detail values as well as the roles with which the
                responsibility is currently associated. </para>
            <figure><title>Identity Channel: Responsibility Link</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/KIM_responsibility.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>To display this screen, from the <emphasis role="bold">Administration</emphasis>
                menu, click <emphasis role="bold">Responsibility</emphasis> in the Identify section
                of the menu.</para>
            <note><para>This table is display-only. Technical assistance is required to modify
                    responsibilities.</para></note>
            <figure><title>Responsibility Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>To find information about a Responsibility, enter information in one or more of
                the fields on the Lookup page and then click the Search button.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Responsibility Lookup Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Template Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The code identifying the application and module the
                                    template pertains to. Because responsibilities pertain to
                                    workflow, most responsibility templates are associated with the
                                    KR-WKFLW (Kuali Rice-Workflow) namespace.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Template Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The template the responsibility is based on. A
                                    template usually defines, in a broad sense, what the
                                    responsibility is. Since responsibilities normally are
                                    associated with action requests for user review, most
                                    responsibilities have a template name of “Review.”</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Responsibility Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The code designating the application and module
                                    this responsibility is associated with. This code usually
                                    corresponds to the namespace of the document type for which the
                                    responsibility generates action requests.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Responsibility Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The name of this responsibility. In most cases, the
                                    responsibility name is the same as the associated template name
                                    (“Review”). Like permission names, responsibility names are not
                                    unique. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Role Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>An indicator that associates the Role with a particular
                                    application and module. To search for a responsibility based on
                                    the namespace of the role to which it is assigned, enter the
                                    name of that namespace. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Role Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The name by which a Role is known in the system. To
                                    search for a responsibility based on the Role to which it is
                                    assigned, enter that Role name. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Principal Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. One of the principals that currently have this
                                    responsibility through their association with a role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Group Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The namespace of groups that have this
                                    responsibility through the group’s association with a
                                    role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Group Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The name of a group that has this responsibility
                                    through its association with a role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Attribute Value</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. A specific responsibility detail value associated
                                    with a responsibility</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
            <figure><title>Responsibility Look: Results</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Responsibility Lookup: Resutls Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Responsibility Detail Values</entry>
                                <entry><para>Display-only. Detailed information that defines:</para>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>What document this responsibility generates action
                                                requests for </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>When the requests are generated </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>How the requests are handled by workflow </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist><para>Unlike permissions, which sometimes have
                                    different detail values, responsibility detail values generally
                                    contain these elements:</para> 
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">routeNodeName</emphasis>:
                                                The point in a document’s workflow routing at which
                                                this responsibility generates requests. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">documentTypeName</emphasis>:
                                                The name of the document type for which this
                                                responsibility generates action requests. This value
                                                may also be a parent document type, which indicates
                                                that this responsibility applies to all child
                                                documents. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold"
                                                  >actionDetailsAtRoleMemberLevel</emphasis>: A True
                                                or False indicator that defines where the system
                                                collects details of this workflow action request. If
                                                the value is True, the system collects action
                                                details when members are assigned to the role. If
                                                the value is False, the system collects action
                                                details when this responsibility is assigned to a
                                                role. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">Required</emphasis>: A True
                                                or False value that indicates whether the system is
                                                required to generate an action request for this
                                                document type. If the value is True and the document
                                                generates no requests associated with this
                                                responsibility, then the document will go into
                                                exception status. If the value is False and the
                                                responsibility generates no action requests, then
                                                the document continues to route as normal. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Granted to Roles</entry>
                                <entry><emphasis role="bold">Display-only</emphasis>. Lists the
                                    namespace and name of roles that have this responsibility. Click
                                    a linked name to view the Role Inquiry for that role
                                    name.</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Responsibility Inquiry</title>
            <para>To view the <emphasis role="bold">Responsibility Inquiry</emphasis> screen for a
                responsibility, click its <emphasis role="bold">Responsibility Name</emphasis> in
                the search results list displayed when you do a Responsibility Lookup. The
                Responsibility Inquiry screen contains the same information displayed in the search
                results, but in a slightly different format:</para>
            <figure><title>Responsibility Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/responsibility_inquiry.png" scale="90"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The fields on this screen are documented in the Responsibility Lookup section
                above.</para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Permission</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Permission Lookup</title>
            <para>The Permission Lookup screen allows you to search for and view existing
                permissions. It displays summarized information about the permission detail values
                as well as the roles that are currently associated with this permission. </para>
            <note><para>This table is display-only. Technical assistance is required to modify permissions.</para></note>
            <para>You get to this screen by clicking <emphasis role="bold">Permissions</emphasis> in
                the <emphasis role="bold">Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Administration</emphasis> menu.</para>
            <figure><title>Permission Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Enter information in one or more fields on the <emphasis role="bold">Permission
                    Lookup</emphasis> screen and then click the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >search</emphasis> button to display permissions that match your
                information.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Permission Lookup Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Template Namespace </entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The code identifying the application and module the
                                    template pertains to. Because templates tend to be general
                                    categories, they are often associated with system-level
                                    namespaces.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Template Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The template the permission is based on. A template
                                    usually defines, in a broad sense, what the permission controls.
                                    Similar types of permissions use the same template.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Permission Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The code designating the application and module
                                    this permission is associated with.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Permission Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The name of this permission. In most cases, the
                                    permission name is the same as its associated template
                                    name.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Role Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. An indicator that associates the role with a
                                    particular application and module.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Role Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The common descriptive name by which this role is
                                    known.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Principal Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The principals that currently have this permission
                                    through their association with a role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Group Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The namespace of groups that have this permission
                                    through the groups’ association with a role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Group Name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. The name of a group that has this permission
                                    through its association with a role</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Permission Detail Values</entry>
                                <entry><para>Optional. Detailed information that, in combination with the
                                    permission name, defines the permission’s function For example,
                                    if the permission name is <emphasis role="bold">Initiate
                                        Document</emphasis>, the <emphasis role="bold">Permission
                                        Detail Values</emphasis> field indicates the specific type
                                    of document the initiate permission pertains to. Permission
                                    detail values can include many different types of data. Some
                                    common permission details:</para> 
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">documentTypeName</emphasis>:
                                                The name of the document Type associated with this
                                                permission. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">routeNodeName</emphasis>:
                                                The point in a document’s workflow routing at which
                                                this permission becomes relevant. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">routeStatusCode</emphasis>:
                                                The routing status that a document must be in for
                                                this permission to apply. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para><emphasis role="bold">propertyName</emphasis>: A
                                                field or document element that the permission
                                                pertains to. </para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
            <para>When you click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button for a Permission
                Lookup, KIM displays your search results in a table like this:</para>
            <figure><title>Permission Lookup: Results Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_lookup_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The information in the search results table is display-only and is defined above.
                New field:</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Permission Lookup: Results Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Granted to Roles</entry>
                                <entry>Lists the namespace and name of roles that have this
                                    permission. Click on a linked name to view its Role Inquiry
                                    screen.</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Permission Inquiry</title>
            <para>To view the <emphasis role="bold">Permission Inquiry</emphasis> screen for a
                Permission, click the <emphasis role="bold">Permission Name</emphasis> in the search
                results from a Permission Lookup. The Permission Inquiry screen contains the same
                information as the Permission Lookup search results, but in a slightly different
                format:</para>
            <figure><title>Permission Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The fields on this screen are documented above in the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Permission Lookup</emphasis> section.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Permission Template Inquiry</title>
            <para>This screen provides detailed information about a <emphasis role="bold">Template
                    Namespace</emphasis>. To display it, click a <emphasis role="bold">Template
                    Name</emphasis> on the <emphasis role="bold">Document Configuration</emphasis>
                screen or the <emphasis role="bold">Permission Inquiry</emphasis> screen.</para>
            <figure><title>Permission Template Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/permission_template_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Information related to the fields on this screen can be found above, in the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Permission Lookup</emphasis> section of this
                document.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Delivered Permission Templates</title>
            <para>Rice is delivered with a number of permission templates.  Below is a listing of each
            along with a brief description of their use.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Delivered Permission Templates</title>
                    <tgroup cols="5">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c4" colnum="4" colwidth="1.0*"/>  
                        <colspec colname="c5" colnum="5" colwidth="1.0*"/>                        
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Template ID</entry>
                                <entry>Template Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>Template Name</entry>
                                <entry>Permission Template Description</entry>
                                <entry>Permission Detailas</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>1</entry>
                                <entry>KUALI</entry>
                                <entry>Default</entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>2</entry>
                                <entry>KR-NS</entry>
                                <entry>Copy Document</entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>3</entry>
                                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>
                                <entry>Administer Routing for Document</entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>4</entry>
                                <entry>KR-WKFLW</entry>
                                <entry>Blanket Approve Document</entry>
                                <entry>Authorizes user to bypass specified approval route nodes</entry>
                                <entry></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Locations</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Campus</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Lookup</title>
                <para>The Campus Lookup screen provides detailed information about the campuses
                    defined in your system.</para>
                <figure><title>Identity Channel: Campus Link</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/select_campus.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>To get to the Campus Lookup function, click <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Campus</emphasis> on the Rice <emphasis role="bold">Administration
                        Menu</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>This takes you to the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Lookup</emphasis> screen
                    where you have the option to create a new Campus by clicking the <emphasis
                        role="bold">create new</emphasis> button in the upper right corner under the
                    Login box or to perform a search of campuses already defined in Rice. If you
                    choose to create a new Campus, KIM displays the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >CampusMaintenanceDocument</emphasis>, which is discussed in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Campus Maintenance</emphasis> section below.</para>
                <figure><title>Campus Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Another way to get to the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Lookup</emphasis>
                    screen is to click the Field Lookup button next to the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Campus Code</emphasis> field on any screen where it appears. If you do
                    this, you see the Campus Lookup screen without the <emphasis role="bold">create
                        new</emphasis> button.</para>
                <para>Enter information in one or more of the fields on the Campus Lookup screen and
                    then click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button to see a list of
                    Campuses that fit your search.</para>
                <note><para>Leave all of the search fields blank to get a list of all Campuses.</para></note>
                <para>If you did NOT begin your Campus Lookup from the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> menu, your list of search results looks like
                    this:</para>
                <figure><title>Campus Lookup: Results Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>If you did begin your search from the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> menu, you see <emphasis role="bold"
                        >edit</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">copy</emphasis> as links for each
                    Campus instead of <emphasis role="bold">return value</emphasis>. These options
                    are explained in the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Maintenance</emphasis> section
                    below.</para>
                <para>Click one of the underlined column titles on the search results list to sort
                    the list by that column. Click it again to sort the list in the opposite
                    order.</para>
                <para>You can also export the search results list in CSV, spreadsheet, or XML
                    format. Click the appropriate link at the bottom of the search results list to
                    do this.</para>
                <para>If you did NOT begin your Campus Lookup from the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> menu, the <emphasis role="bold">Return
                        Value</emphasis> column has a <emphasis role="bold">return value</emphasis>
                    link for each campus. Click this return value link for the Campus Code for which
                    you need information and Rice goes back to the screen you were on before and
                    automatically enters the information about that campus on the screen for
                    you.</para>
                <para>You can find information about the fields on this screen under Edit Campus Tab
                    in the Campus Maintenance section of this User Guide.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Inquiry</title>
                <para>Display this screen by clicking <emphasis role="bold">Campus Code</emphasis>
                    in the search results list after you do a <emphasis role="bold">Campus
                        Lookup</emphasis>:</para>
                <figure><title>Campus Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>You can find information about the fields on this screen in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Edit Campus Tab</emphasis> section under <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Campus Maintenance</emphasis>, below.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Maintenance</title>
                <para>Use a <emphasis role="bold">Campus</emphasis> document for each of the
                    different fiscal and physical operating entities of an institution. A campus may
                    be identified as a fiscal entity, a physical entity, or both. </para>
                <sect4>
                    <title>To create a new Campus</title>
                    <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">Campus</emphasis> on the Rice <emphasis
                            role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu for KIM to display the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Campus Lookup</emphasis> screen, then click the
                            <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button. KIM displays the
                            <emphasis role="bold">CampusMaintenanceDocument</emphasis>. </para>
                    <figure><title>Campue Maintenance Document</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/CampusMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The fields on this document are described in the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >Document Layout</emphasis> section below. Enter information in all
                        required fields and other fields appropriate to this campus, then click the
                            <emphasis role="bold">save</emphasis> button to create your new
                        Campus.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>To edit Campus information</title>
                    <para>If you want to edit information about an existing Campus: <orderedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Begin at the Administration menu and do a Campus Lookup to
                                    find the campus you need to edit. </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>On the list of search results, click edit for that Campus.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>KIM displays the CampusMaintenanceDocument for that campus:</para>
                                <figure><title>Campus Maintenane Document: Expanded</title>
                                    <mediaobject>
                                        <imageobject>
                                            <imagedata
                                                fileref="../images/CampusMaintenanceDocument2.png"
                                                scale="90"/>
                                        </imageobject>
                                    </mediaobject>
                                </figure>
                            </listitem>
                        <listitem><para>Change the information in the fields that you need to edit, then click the save button at the
                                    bottom of the document.</para></listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>The Campus Maintenance Document has five sections: <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Document Overview </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Edit Campus </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Notes and Attachments </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Route Log</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                    <para>You can find documentation on all of the tabs in this document except
                            <emphasis role="bold">Edit Campus</emphasis> in the Common Features and
                        Functions section of the <emphasis role="bold">User Guide</emphasis>.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit Campus Tab</title>
                    <figure><title>Campus Maintenance Document: Edit Campus Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_campus.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>In edit mode, the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Campus Tab</emphasis>
                        presents a display-only set of fields on the left and editable fields on the
                        right in which you may enter changes. When this tab is displayed in the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Create New</emphasis> process, only the editable
                        fields are displayed.</para>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Campus Maintenance Document: Edit Campus Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field Name</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Code </entry>
                                        <entry>The unique identifying code assigned to a
                                            campus.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The familiar name for a specific university
                                            campus.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Short Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. An abbreviated name for a specific campus;
                                            used in reports in which space is limited.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Type Code </entry>
                                        <entry><para>Required. Indicates the type of campus. Valid values are:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>B - Both </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>F - Fiscal </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>P - Physical </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Type Lookup</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type</emphasis> Lookup function displays
                    detailed information about specific <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type
                        Codes</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>To display this screen:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Go to the Campus Lookup screen. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Select a valid Campus Type Code from the dropdown list. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click the Field Lookup button next to the Campus Type Code field.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                <figure><title>Campus Type Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_type_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>There are two ways to search for information using this screen:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Enter information in one or more fields on the <emphasis
                                    role="bold">Campus Type Lookup</emphasis> screen and then click
                                the <emphasis role="bold">Search</emphasis> button. This displays a
                                list of campus types that match the information you entered, similar
                                to the list in the screen print just below. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Leave the fields on the Campus Type Lookup screen blank and click
                                the Search button. This displays a list of all available campus
                                types, similar to this: </para>
                            <figure><title>Campue Type Lookup: Results Example</title>
                                <mediaobject>
                                    <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata
                                            fileref="../images/campus_type_lookup_results.png"
                                            scale="90"/>
                                    </imageobject>
                                </mediaobject>
                            </figure>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>You can export the search results list in CSV, spreadsheet, or XML format.
                    Click the appropriate link at the bottom of the search results list to do
                    this.</para>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Return Value</emphasis> column has a <emphasis
                        role="bold">return value</emphasis> link for each Campus Type Code. Click
                    this return value link for the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type Code
                    </emphasis>you need, and Kuali goes back to the screen you were on before and
                    automatically enters the information about that Campus Type Code on the screen
                    for you.</para>
                <para>Field information on this screen can be found in the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Edit Campus Tab</emphasis> section above.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Type Inquiry</title>
                <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type Inquiry</emphasis> screen to see the
                    Campus Type Code and Name and the Active Indicator for a particular
                    campus.</para>
                <para>To display this screen:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Go to the Campus Lookup screen. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Select a valid Campus Type Code from the dropdown list. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click the Inquiry button next to the Campus Type Code field.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
                <figure><title>Campus Type Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_type_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Field information on this screen can be found in the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Edit Campus Tab</emphasis> section above.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Campus Type Maintenance</title>
                <figure><title>Identity Channel: Campus Type Link</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_type_maintenance.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>To create or perform maintenance on a Campus Type, click <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Campus Type</emphasis> on the <emphasis role="bold">Administration
                        Menu</emphasis>.</para>
                <figure><title>Campus Type Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_type_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>From the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type Lookup</emphasis> screen, you may
                    either create a new <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type</emphasis> or search for
                    an existing one. </para>
                <note><para>If you don’t have a <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button in the
                    top right corner of the <emphasis role="bold">Campus Type Lookup</emphasis>
                    screen, you did not open the screen from the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> menu.</para></note>
                <para>When you search for and find an existing Campus Type (see instructions above),
                    you have the option to edit or copy it. After you click the <emphasis
                        role="bold">create new</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis>, or
                        <emphasis role="bold">copy</emphasis> button, KIM displays the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Campus Type Maintenance</emphasis> document. This document lets
                    you add and update Campus Types.</para>
                <figure><title>Campus Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/CampusMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">CampusTypeMaintenance</emphasis> document
                        contains four standard tabs and the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Campus
                            Type</emphasis> tab. The standard tabs are documented in the Common
                        Features and Functions section of this User Guide. The Edit Campus Type tab
                        is described below.</para>
                    <figure><title>Campus Maintenance Document: Overview Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/campus_maintenance_overview.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit Campus Type Tab</title>
                    <para>The Edit Campus Type tab displays the fields that are unique to each
                        Campus Type.</para>
                    <figure><title>Campus Maintenance Document: Edit Campus Type Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_campus_type.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Campus Maintenance Document: Edit Campus Type Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Type Code </entry>
                                        <entry><para>Required. The code used by Rice to identify this type of Campus. Valid values are:</para>
                                            <itemizedlist>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>B - Both </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>F - Fiscal </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                                <listitem>
                                                  <para>P - Physical </para>
                                                </listitem>
                                            </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Campus Type Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The descriptive name for this Campus
                                            Type</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Indicates whether the Campus Code is active
                                            or inactive. Remove the checkmark to deactivate a Campus
                                            Type. Removing the checkmark will also remove this
                                            Campus Type from the dropdown list on Campus
                                            documents.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Postal Code</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>Postal Code Lookup</title>
                <para>The Postal Code Lookup screen provides detailed information about the postal
                    codes (zip codes) defined in KIM.</para>
                <para>You access the <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code Lookup</emphasis> screen by
                    clicking <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code</emphasis> in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> menu.</para>
                <figure><title>Identity Channel: Postal Code Link</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/postal_code.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <figure><title>Postal Code Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/postal_code_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>A search produces a list similar to the example below.</para>
                <figure><title>Postal Code Lookup: Results Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/postal_code_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <note><para>You may also enter a city and state to search for the associated zip
                    code(s).</para></note>
                <para>Descriptions of the fields in this list can be found in the Postal Code
                    Maintenance section below.</para>
                <para>Clicking <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> takes you to the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Postal Code Maintenance</emphasis> screen.</para>
                <para>Clicking <emphasis role="bold">copy</emphasis> also takes you to the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Postal Code Maintenance</emphasis> screen and populates some of
                    the fields in the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Postal Codes</emphasis> tab with
                    information from the item you copied.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis> from the list takes
                    you to the <emphasis role="bold">Country Code Inquiry</emphasis> screen.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code</emphasis> from the list takes
                    you to the <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code Inquiry</emphasis> screen.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">State Code</emphasis> from the list takes you
                    to the <emphasis role="bold">State Code Inquiry</emphasis> screen.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Postal Code Inquiry</title>
                <figure><title>Postal Code Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/postal_code_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Information about these fields can be found in the Postal Code Maintenance
                    section below.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Postal Code Maintenance</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code Maintenance Document</emphasis> defines
                    the postal (zip) code by city and state. When you click the Postal Code option
                    on the Administration screen, KIM displays the <emphasis role="bold">Postal Code
                        Lookup</emphasis> screen. At this point you can perform a lookup and select
                    a postal code to edit or click the <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis>
                    button, KIM displays the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >PostalCodeMaintenanceDocument</emphasis> screen. </para>
                <figure><title>Postal Code Manintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/PostalCodeMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>To create a new Postal Code, enter information in the required fields in the
                        <emphasis role="bold">Document Overview</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Edit Postal Codes</emphasis> tabs, then click the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >submit</emphasis> button at the bottom of the screen.</para>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>All of the tabs on this screen are standard, except the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Edit Postal Codes</emphasis> tab. You can find information
                        on standard tabs in the Common Features and Functions section of this
                            <emphasis role="bold">User Guide</emphasis>.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit Postal Codes tab</title>
                    <para>In edit mode, the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Postal Codes</emphasis> tab
                        presents a display-only set of fields on the left and editable fields on the
                        right, in which you may enter changes. The tab looks like this:</para>
                    <figure><title>Postal Code Manintenance Document: Edit Postal Codes Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_postal_codes.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject></figure>
                    <para>In create mode, the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Postal Codes</emphasis> tab
                        presents only a set of fields in which you may enter information. </para>
                    <figure><title>Postal Code Manintenance Document: Create Postal Codes</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/create_postal_code.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Postal Code Maintenance Document: Create Postal Codes
                                Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Code </entry>
                                        <entry>The country code for the country associated with the
                                            zip (postal) code</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Postal Code </entry>
                                        <entry>A Postal Service zip code</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>State </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The state associated with the postal (zip)
                                            code</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>County Code </entry>
                                        <entry>The KIM identifying code for the county associated
                                            with the postal (zip) code</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>City Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The name of the city associated with the
                                            postal (zip) code</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Indicates whether the postal code is active or
                                            inactive. Remove the checkmark to deactivate this postal
                                            code.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>County</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>County Lookup</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">County Lookup</emphasis> screen provides information
                    on counties defined in KIM.</para>
                <para>Access the <emphasis role="bold">County Code Lookup</emphasis> screen by
                    clicking <emphasis role="bold">County</emphasis> in the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Identity</emphasis> section of the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >Administration</emphasis> Menu.</para>
                <figure><title>Identity Channel: County Lin</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/county.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <figure><title>County Code Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/county_code_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button to go to the
                        <emphasis role="bold">County Maintenance</emphasis> function, where you can
                    create a new County in Rice. </para>
                <para>Conducting a search from this screen returns a list similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>County Code Lookup: Results Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/county_code_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Clicking the <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                        >copy</emphasis> link in the Action column allows you to edit the county
                    information you selected or to create a new county in Rice, beginning with a
                    copy of the information from this county. This link takes you to the <emphasis
                        role="bold">County Maintenance Document</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis> takes you to the
                        <emphasis role="bold">Country Inquiry</emphasis> function for that
                    code.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">County Code</emphasis> takes you to the
                        <emphasis role="bold">County Inquiry</emphasis> function for that
                    code.</para>
                <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">State</emphasis> code takes you to the
                        <emphasis role="bold">State Inquiry</emphasis> function for that
                    code.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>County Inquiry</title>
                <para>This screen provides a snapshot of the important information about a <emphasis
                        role="bold">County</emphasis>:</para>
                <figure><title>County Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/county_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>You can find information about the fields on this screen in the <emphasis
                        role="bold">County Maintenance</emphasis> section below.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>County Maintenance</title>
                <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">County Maintenance</emphasis> document to assign
                    specific identifying codes to county names. When you click the County option on
                    the Administration screen, KIM displays the <emphasis role="bold">County
                        Lookup</emphasis> screen. After you select to edit a county or click the
                        <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button, KIM displays the
                        <emphasis role="bold">CountyMaintenanceDocument</emphasis> screen:</para>
                <figure><title>County Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/CountyMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>To create a new County, enter valid information in the required fields in
                        the<emphasis role="bold"> Document Overview</emphasis> and <emphasis
                        role="bold">Edit Counties</emphasis> tabs, then click the <emphasis
                        role="bold">Submit</emphasis> button at the bottom of the screen.</para>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>All of the tabs on this screen are standard, except the <emphasis
                            role="bold">Edit Counties</emphasis> tab. Information on standard tabs
                        can be found in the Common Features and Functions section of this User
                        Guide.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit Counties Tab</title>
                    <para>In edit mode, the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Counties</emphasis> tab
                        presents a display-only set of fields on the left and editable fields on the
                        right, in which you may enter changes. The tab looks like this:</para>
                    <figure><title>County Mainteance Document: Edit Counties Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_counties.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>In create mode, the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Counties</emphasis> tab
                        presents only a set of fields in which you may enter information. </para>
                    <figure><title>County Maintenance Document: Create County</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/create_county.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>County Maintenance Document: Create County Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Code </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The country code for the country in which
                                            this county is located. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>County Code </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. A unique identifying code assigned to this
                                            county.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>State</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The state abbreviation assigned by the U.S.
                                            Postal Service to the state in which this county is
                                            located. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>County Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The actual name of this county.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Indicates whether the county code is
                                                <emphasis role="italic">active</emphasis> or
                                                <emphasis role="italic">inactive</emphasis>. Remove
                                            the check mark to deactivate this county code. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>State</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>State Code Lookup</title>
                <para>The State Code Lookup function provides a convenient way to find key
                    information pertaining to states that are defined in Rice.</para>
                <para>You can display the <emphasis role="bold">State Code Lookup</emphasis> screen
                    by clicking <emphasis role="bold">State</emphasis> on the Rice <emphasis
                        role="bold">Administration</emphasis> menu.</para>
                <figure><title>Identity Channel: State Link</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/state.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <figure><title>State Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/state_code_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Enter information in one or more of the fields on the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >State Code Lookup</emphasis> screen and then click the <emphasis
                        role="bold">search</emphasis> button to see a list of States that fit your
                    criteria.</para>
                <note><para>Leave all of the search fields blank to display a list of all States.</para></note>
                <figure><title>State Lookup: Results Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/state_code_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                        >copy</emphasis> in the <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column to
                    go to the <emphasis role="bold">StateMaintenanceDocument</emphasis> screen,
                    where you can edit the existing <emphasis role="bold">State</emphasis> or use a
                    copy of it as a base for establishing a new <emphasis role="bold"
                        >State</emphasis> in KIM.</para>
                <para>Click an underlined <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis> to go to the
                        <emphasis role="bold">Country Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that <emphasis
                        role="bold">Country Code</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>You can also export the search results list in CSV, spreadsheet, or XML
                    format. Click the appropriate link at the bottom of the search results list to
                    do this.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>State Inquiry</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">State Inquiry</emphasis> screen provides a snapshot
                    of the most important information defined in Rice for a <emphasis role="bold"
                        >State</emphasis>.</para>
                <figure><title>State Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/state_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>State Maintenance</title>
                <para>The State document defines the U.S. Postal Service codes used to identify
                    states. When you choose the State option on the Administration menu, KIM
                    displays the <emphasis role="bold">State Code Lookup</emphasis> screen. After
                    you click <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> for a State or click the
                        <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button, KIM displays the
                        <emphasis role="bold">StateMaintenanceDocument</emphasis>.</para>
                <figure><title>State Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/StateMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>This screen contains five tabs:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Document Overview </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Edit States </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Notes and Attachments </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>Route Log </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                    <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Edit States</emphasis> tab is unique to this
                        screen and is described below. The other four tabs are described in the
                        Common Features and Functions section of this User Guide.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit States Tab</title>
                    <para>The Edit States tab can be displayed with two different sets of fields.
                        Which you see depends on whether you are creating a new State or editing an
                        existing State.</para>
                    <figure><title>State Maintenance Document: Add State</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/create_state.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The version of the tab above is displayed when you are creating a new
                        State.</para>
                    <figure><title>State Maintenance Document: Edit States Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_states.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Pictured above in <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> mode, the
                            <emphasis role="bold">Edit States</emphasis> tab presents a display-only
                        set of fields on the left and editable fields on the right, in which you may
                        enter changes. </para>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>States Maintenance Document: Edit States Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Code </entry>
                                        <entry>A unique identifying code assigned to a country
                                            Required for a new State Display-only when editing a
                                            State </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>State Abbreviation</entry>
                                        <entry>The state abbreviation assigned by the U.S. Postal
                                            Service Required for a new State Display-only when
                                            editing a State </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>State Name </entry>
                                        <entry>The full name of the state Required for a new State
                                            When editing, this field can be modified but not
                                            deleted. </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Optional. Indicates whether the State code is active
                                            or inactive. Remove the checkmark to deactivate the
                                            State code.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Country</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>Country Lookup</title>
                <para>This screen provides information about <emphasis role="bold">Country
                        Codes</emphasis> and is accessed directly off the Administration menu. </para>
                <figure><title>Country Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/country_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Performing a search on a <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis>
                    produces results similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Country Lookup: Results Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/county_code_lookup_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Selecting <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                        >copy</emphasis> in the <emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis> column
                    takes you to the <emphasis role="bold">Country Maintenance Document</emphasis>
                    screen, where you can edit the existing <emphasis role="bold">Country
                        Code</emphasis> or use a copy of it as a base for establishing a new
                        <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>Selecting an underlined <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis> takes
                    you to the <emphasis role="bold">Country Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that
                        <emphasis role="bold">Country Code</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>You can also export the search results list in CSV, spreadsheet, or XML
                    format. Click the appropriate link at the bottom of the search results list to
                    do this.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Country Inquiry</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Country Inquiry</emphasis> screen displays details
                    about a Country in Rice. You get to this screen by clicking a <emphasis
                        role="bold">Country Code</emphasis> in the list of search results after you
                    do a <emphasis role="bold">Country Lookup</emphasis>. </para>
                <figure><title>Country Inquiry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/country_inquiry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Country Maintenance</title>
                <para>The Country document is used to assign specific identifying codes to country
                    names. </para>
                <para>When you choose the Country option on the Administration menu, KIM displays
                    the <emphasis role="bold">Country Lookup</emphasis> screen. After you select a
                    country or click the <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button, KIM
                    presents the <emphasis role="bold">CountryMaintenanceDocument</emphasis> screen. </para>
                <figure><title>Country Maintenance Document</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/CountryMaintenanceDocument.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Document Layout</title>
                    <para>All of the tabs in the <emphasis role="bold">CountryMaintenanceDocument</emphasis> are standard with the exception
                        of the <emphasis role="bold">Edit Country</emphasis> tab. Documentation on
                        standard tabs can be found in the Common Features and Functions section of
                        the User Guide.</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Edit Country tab</title>
                    <figure><title>Country Maintenance Document: Edit Country Tab</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
                                <imagedata fileref="../images/edit_country.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <table frame="none">
                            <title>Country Maintenance Document: Edit Country Attributes</title>
                            <tgroup cols="2">
                                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                                <thead>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Field</entry>
                                        <entry>Description</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Code </entry>
                                        <entry>A unique identifying code assigned to a
                                            country.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Name </entry>
                                        <entry>Required. The actual name of a specific
                                            country.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Country Restricted Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Required. Check the box to indicate if the country is
                                            restricted from use in procurement. Clear the check box
                                            if it is not restricted.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row>
                                        <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                        <entry>Indicates whether this country code is active or
                                            inactive in Rice. Remove the checkmark to deactivate
                                            this country code.</entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
</chapter>
