<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2011 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="UG_KEW" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>KEW</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Kuali Enterprise Workflow: Overview</title>
        <para>Kuali Enterprise Workflow, or KEW, is a module of Kuali Rice. KEW provides useful
            features for automatically sending documents to people for approval or action using
            workflows, managing the documents you receive through these workflows, searching for
            documents, and checking information about documents that have been in a workflow. KEW is
            built by and for higher education institutions and is especially designed for
            automatically routing work across departmental boundaries.</para>
        <para>Using KEW you can:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Automatically send (route) documents to individuals, groups, or roles
                        (people who do a particular function) using workflows </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Create rules to automatically route documents based on the content of the
                        document</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Change routing rules, and the documents affected by your changes are
                        rerouted immediately </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Attach notes and other files to documents in workflows </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Build forms easily and use them in workflows </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Search for documents based on workflow information and some content in the
                        document </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Check the history of documents and the people who took part in the
                        workflow for each document </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Delegate items in a workflow to another person • Create and update groups
                        for workflows </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Customize the email messages that are sent when someone needs to take an
                        action for a workflow </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Choose whether or not you receive an email message when you have a new
                        action item from a workflow </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Integrate KEW with the Kuali Service Bus (KSB) for routing documents
                    </para>
                </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>Your institution may use some or all of these KEW features. Your institution may also
            use some of these KEW features and combine them with other non-Kuali applications, such
            as an application that manages users and/or groups, or an application that manages notes
            or attachments.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Information Sources</emphasis>: <link
                xlink:href="http://kew.kuali.org/">http://kew.kuali.org/</link></para>
        <sect2>
            <title>What is KEW?</title>
            <para>Kuali Enterprise Workflow provides a common routing and approval engine that
                facilitates the automation of electronic processes across the enterprise. The
                workflow product was built by and for higher education, so it is particularly well
                suited to route mediated transactions across departmental boundaries. Workflow
                facilitates distribution of processes out into the organizations to eliminate paper
                processes and shadow feeder systems. In addition to facilitating routing and
                approval, workflow can also automate process to process related flows. Each process
                instance is assigned a unique identifier that is global across the organization.
                Workflow keeps a permanent record of all processes and their participants.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KEW Features</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Flexible Workflow Engine</emphasis> - Support for
                        sequential, parallel and dynamic routing paths. Extensible architecture
                        allows for easy customization. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Content-Based Routing</emphasis> - Routing decisions
                        can be made based on XML document content. XPath and other XML tools can be
                        used to determine routing without writing code.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Pluggable Components</emphasis> - Components can be
                        deployed to the system at runtime using Plugins. Hot deployable class
                        loading space provides a robust enterprise ready deployment environment for
                        workflow code. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">People in the Routing Process</emphasis> - Documents
                        can be routed to individuals, groups or roles. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Action List</emphasis> - Displays a list of each
                        user's pending items which require his/her attention, such as documents
                        which are awaiting approval. Users can configure whether they receive emails
                        when the document enters their Action List. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Document Search and Route Log</emphasis> - Allows
                        users to search for documents and see an audit trail of what has happened to
                        the document during its life cycle. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Document Search Customization</emphasis> - Document
                        based content can be associated with workflow data and searched on using our
                        Document Search screens. Have a single place for all of your workflow
                        document searches. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">EDocLite</emphasis> - EDocLite allows quick document
                        building and integration with workflow using only XML. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Rules System</emphasis> - Provides a mechanism for
                        defining business rules which govern how a document routes. Rule screens
                        give functional users ability to maintain the business rules for their
                        applications. Documents affected by rule changes are re-routed real time.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Notes and Attachments</emphasis> - Notes and
                        Attachments can be attached to documents using KEW's notes and attachments
                        services out of the box. Institution based attachment and note services can
                        be used by overriding our default services. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Person Services</emphasis> - Maintains users of the
                        system. You can use the Out-of-the-Box service or override with your
                        institution's user services. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Group Services</emphasis> - Maintains groups of
                        users. You can use the Out-of-the-Box service or override with your
                        institution's group services. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Transactions</emphasis> - All transactions and
                        documents route in a JTA transaction. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Web Service API</emphasis> - All system functions
                        are available through Web Service APIs. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Security</emphasis> - Web service calls can be
                        authorized using digital signatures. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Scalability</emphasis> - Can be clustered and run on
                        multiple machines to allow for horizontal scalability. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Embeddable Engine</emphasis> - Workflow engine can
                        be embedded in an application as well as ran as a standalone service.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Embeddable Web Application</emphasis> - Web portion
                        can be embedded in an application as a Struts module. Run the Action List,
                        Document Search, Route Log, Rules System and more from within your
                        application with minimal effort. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Service Bus Integration</emphasis> - Integration
                        with the Kuali Service Bus (KSB). Override any service from within workflow
                        by having workflow grab the service from the bus or use workflow's pluggable
                        components to deploy bus enabled services. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">JMX Support</emphasis> - A set of management
                        functions are exposed through JMX. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Spring Based Integration</emphasis> - KEW is
                        designed with Spring based integration in mind. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Why Use KEW?</title>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Provides a single action list for the constituents of the organization
                            to see work that requires their attention</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Establishes a configurable way for service providers to define their
                            processes, allowing them to alter those processes over time to reflect
                            organizational change</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Promotes transparency of processes to the institution so that people
                            can seamlessly see the status, actors, and the history of any
                            institutional process which leverages KEW as its workflow engine</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>PeopleFlow - a new KEW feature</title>
        <para>PeopleFlow is our Kuali Rice instantiation of the "maps" concept included in the
            original Coeus. For all intents and purposes it's a prioritized list of people to send
            requests to.   Essentially, it's like a mini people-based workflow that doesn't require
            you to specify a KEW node in the document type for each individual who might need to
            approve or be notified. You can define "Stops" in a PeopleFlow, where everything in the
            same stop proceeds in parallel, but all must be done within the stop before proceeding
            to the next stop. </para>
        <para>You can call/execute a PeopleFlow from within a KEW workflow node directly, or you can
            invoke the Kuali Rules Managment System (KRMS) engine from an application and any
            PeopleFlows that get selected during rule execution, defined in a KRMS agenda, will be
            called. In this way, you can integrate business rules across applications and workflows. </para>
        <para>The same PeopleFlow that defines a routing order among a set of persons, groups or
            roles can be called by KRMS rules, with the KRMS rules defining which type of  request
            to pass to the PeopleFlow (for example, an "approval" routing action or a
            "notification").   </para>
        <para>KRMS is also a new feature in Rice 2.0.  See the KRMS Users' Guide for more
            information on KRMS.  </para>
        <para>You can define a PeopleFlow (simple workflow) via a maintenance document.  In the
            Kuali Rice portal on the main tab there is a Workflow category, and PeopleFlow is in
            that category.  Select it:  </para>
        <para><inlinemediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KEW---PeopleFlow-on-main-tab-in-portal.png"
                        scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject></para>
        <para>You can search for a PeopleFlow to copy from and modify (be sure to give it a new
            unique name) or can create a new one (see the top right of the lookup screen).</para>
        <para><inlinemediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KEW-PeopleFlow-lookup.png" scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject></para>
        <para>(We will add screen captures of the PeopleFlow creation screens, in early January -
            doing styling refinements now.)</para>
    </sect1>    
    <sect1>
        <title>Actions</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action List Guide</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Action List</emphasis> page includes your: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Action List </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Outbox </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Action List Filter </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Preferences </para>
                    </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>In the Kuali Rice portal, the Action List button is available in the upper
                left hand corner of the screen on most pages.</para>
            <para>Your institution may have KEW links inside other applications, such as Kuali
                Financial Systems (KFS). KFS may display an Action List button at the top left
                of the KFS page like this:</para>
            <figure><title>Kuali Portal: Action List Button</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/kfs_kew.png" scale="75"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Clicking an Action List link or button displays your <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Action List</emphasis> page. This is a sample KEW Action List; your
                institution’s may look somewhat different:</para>
            <para>On your Action List page is the list of documents on which you need to take an
                action, such as Approve, Disapprove, or Acknowledge, and those which you have
                already completed. These are your action requests. Action requests that someone
                has delegated to you are also listed on your Action List page. Note: You can
                only see the Action List for the person who is logged into KEW or another Kuali
                application.</para>
            <para>You can click the title at the top of a column to sort all of your action
                requests by the information in that column. For example, if you click the column
                title, Type, KEW sorts your action requests by their Type.</para>
            <para>On your Action List, you can see this information about the documents on which
                you need to take action:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Id</emphasis>: A unique, system-generated ID
                            for each document <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>When you click a Document Id, KEW displays the actions
                                        you can take on this document, such as Blanket Approve,
                                        Complete, Approve, Disapprove, and Cancel. The actions
                                        you can take are determined by the document’s Type.
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Based on your institution’s setup, you may see a Show
                                        button in the Document Id column. Click the Show button
                                        to see a summary of the document. </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Type</emphasis>: The document’s type
                            determines the actions you can take on it. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Title</emphasis>: The title that the
                            initiator gives to the document. Your institution may have standards
                            for document titles that give you specific information about that
                            document. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Status</emphasis>: The current location of
                            the document in its routing path. The Status may be: <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Approved</emphasis>: These
                                        documents have been approved by all required reviewers
                                        and are waiting for additional post-processing. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Cancelled</emphasis>: These
                                        documents have been stopped. The document’s initiator
                                        can Cancel it before routing begins, or a reviewer of
                                        the document can cancel it after routing begins. When a
                                        document is cancelled, routing stops; it is not sent to
                                        another Action List. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Disapproved</emphasis>: These
                                        documents have been disapproved by at least one
                                        reviewer. Routing has stopped for these documents.
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Enroute</emphasis>: Routing is
                                        in progress on these documents and an action request is
                                        waiting for someone to take action. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Exception</emphasis>: A routing
                                        exception has occurred on this document. Someone with
                                        the appropriate KIM Permission (or someone from the
                                        Exception Group for this Document Type, although this
                                        feature is deprecated) must take action on this
                                        document, and it has been sent to the Action List of
                                        this workgroup. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Initiated</emphasis>: A user or
                                        a process has created this document, but it has not yet
                                        been routed to anyone’s Action List. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Processed</emphasis>: These
                                        documents have been approved by all required users, and
                                        their post-processing is completed. They may be waiting
                                        for Acknowledgements. No further action is needed on
                                        these documents. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Saved</emphasis>: These
                                        documents have been saved for later work. An author
                                        (initiator) can save a document before routing begins,
                                        or a reviewer can save a document before he or she takes
                                        action on it. When someone saves a document, the
                                        document goes on that person’s Action List. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Final</emphasis>: All required
                                        approvals and all acknowledgements have been received on
                                        these documents. No changes are allowed to a document
                                        that is in Final status. </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Action Requested</emphasis>: The action that
                            you have been asked to take on a document, such as to Approve it.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Initiator</emphasis>: The person who created
                            this document in KEW. Click the initiator’s name to see information
                            about the initiator, including (depending on the initiator's privacy
                            preferences): <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Principal Id and Name </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Entity Id </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Affiliations </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Names </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Phone Numbers </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Email Addresses </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Group and Role memberships </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Delegator</emphasis>: If someone else has
                            given authority in KEW for you to take action on their action
                            requests, their name appears in this column. KEW displays both
                            primary and secondary delegates this way on your Action List.
                            There are two types of delegate in KEW, you may be a Primary
                            Delegate or a Secondary Delegate: <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Primary Delegate</emphasis>: The
                                        delegator turns over his or her full authority to a
                                        primary delegate. The Action Requests for the delegator
                                        only appear in the Action List of the primary delegate.
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Secondary Delegate</emphasis>:
                                        The secondary delegate acts as a temporary backup and
                                        has the same authority as the delegator when the
                                        delegator is not available to take action. Documents
                                        appear in the Action Lists of both the delegator and the
                                        delegate. When either acts on the document, it
                                        disappears from both Action Lists. People often have a
                                        secondary delegate who takes care of their action
                                        requests when they are out of the office. </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Date Created</emphasis>: The date and time
                            the document for this action request was created. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Group Request</emphasis>: When you receive
                            an action request because you are part of a group, KEW displays the
                            name of the group in this column. Only one member of a group is
                            required to complete an action request. Click the group name on your
                            Action List to see more details, including:  <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Group Id </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Group Name </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Group Active Indicator </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Group Members and their user names</para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis>: For documents that you
                            receive only for your information (they don’t require that you take
                            any further action), there is a dropdown menu in the Actions column.
                            You can use this menu to agree that you’ve received the document for
                            information purposes: Select FYI, then click the Take Actions button
                            at the bottom of the page. </para>
                        <figure><title>Action List</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list.png" scale="85"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Log</emphasis>: (also known as the Route
                            Log) Click the paper/magnifying glass icon in the Log column to
                            display the Route Log page. This page has details about the routing
                            path and Actions Taken on this document. Learn more about this
                            information in the Route Log Guide. A sample Route Log page:</para>
                        <figure><title>Route Log</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/route_log.png"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>If enabled for a particular document, messages can also be logged through
                the route log tab (or page). This allows users to add a deferral message or
                other message that will be reflected in the routing without taking an action on
                the document.</para>
            <para>This function is enabled by KIM permissions. These permissions have template
                'Add Message to Route Log' which takes a document type name as a detail. The
                bootstrap dataset contains one permission with this template and document type
                detail 'KualiDocument', however this permission is not granted to any role. This
                means the functionality will be disabled until the permission is assigned or
                another permission record with this template and for another document type is
                created and assigned. When matching permissions for a particular document type
                the document type hierarchy is considered. Permission records for children
                document types will override any permission record for its parents.</para>
            <para>For example, if we wanted to enable the feature on all KualiDocuments except
                document type 'Foo', we would first grant the permission with document type
                detail 'KualiDocument' to a role. Then we would create an additional permission
                with template 'Add Message to Route Log' and document type detail 'Foo'. For the
                second permission we do not assign any roles. </para>
            <para>By granting these permission(s) to one of the derived workflow roles we can
                enable this feature to users who have active routing requests. Examples of such
                roles are KR-WKFLW Approve Request Recipient and KR-WKFLW Acknowledge Request
                Recipient.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action List Preferences</title>
            <para>You can customize the appearance and features of your Action List using the
                Action List Preferences page on KEW. To display this page, click the Preferences
                button at the top of the Action List page or click the User Preferences link in
                the Workflow pane of the Main Menu tab. Action List page:</para>
            <figure><title>Action List: Preferences Button</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_page.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>This displays the Action List Preferences page, where you can make choices
                about how KEW displays and refreshes (updates) your Action List and about how
                and when you receive email reminders about your new action requests:</para>
            <figure><title>Action List Preference Page</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_preferences.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The Action List Preferences page has four sections:</para>
            <sect3><title>Action List Preferences: General Section</title>
            <figure>
                <title>Action List Preferences: General section</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_preferences_general.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>In the General section of the Action List Preferences page, you
                            can set the Automatic Refresh Rate for your Action List. Your action
                            requests come in from the server and your Actions Taken are sent to
                            the server each time KEW refreshes (updates) your Action List page.
                            You only see changes to your Action List when KEW refreshes it.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Depending on the network and computers at your workplace, your
                            computer may or may not slow down when KEW refreshes your Action
                            List. If a refresh slows down your computer, you may decide to set
                            the Automatic Refresh Rate for a longer period, such as 10 or 15
                            minutes. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The Action List Page Size tells KEW how many action requests to
                            display at once on your Action List page. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The Delegator Filter field lets you decide where to show action
                            requests for which you are a secondary delegate. You can choose to
                            have KEW display these action requests on your Action List page or
                            not, using this dropdown menu. If you do not display action requests
                            on which you are the Secondary Delegate on your Action List page,
                            you can only see them on a Filter Page (see Filter, below).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3><title>Action List Preferences: Fields Displayed</title>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Action List Preferences: Fields Displayed section</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata
                                        fileref="../images/fields_displayed_in_action_list.png"
                                        scale="85"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject></figure>
                    <itemizedlist>
                       <listitem>
                        <para>You determine which fields are displayed on your Action List page
                            using this section of the Action List Preferences page. Place a
                            checkmark in the box next to fields that you want to display on your
                            Action List page. (Click the box to checkmark it and click it again
                            to un-checkmark it, and vice versa.)</para>
                       </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
            </sect3>
            <sect3><title>Action List Preferences: Document Route Status Colors</title>
                        <figure>
                            <title>Action List Preferences: Document Route Status Colors Section</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/document_route_status_colors.png"
                                        scale="85"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                        <para>In this section of the Action List Preferences page, you can
                            choose a color for each different Status of action requests. This
                            can help you quickly find action requests on which you need to take
                            action.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
            <para>For example, if you set these colors for these routing status levels: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Green for Saved status </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Red for Approved status </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Blue for Exception status </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Your Action List Preferences page looks like this: </para>
            <figure><title>Action List Preferences: Document Route Status Colors Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_preferences2.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Click the Save button at the bottom of the page to make these changes in your
                Action List.</para>
            <para>Action Lists your color changes by Status:</para>
            <figure><title>Action List Preferences: Document Route Status Colors Action List Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/document_route_status_colors_exp.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3><title>Action List Preferences: Email Notifications</title>
            <figure><title>Action List Preferences: Email Notifications Preferences</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_prefs_email_settings.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>            
            <para>The fields used to maintain email preferences are located in a new “Email 
                Notification Preferences” section at the bottom of the Workflow Preferences 
                screen.
                
                The “Email Notification Preferences” section accommodates two new options and 
                allows selection of how and when to receive reminder emails on items sent to the 
                Action List.</para>
            
            <para>In this section, one can select whether or not to receive emails as the Primary 
                Delegate, as the Secondary Delegate, and also set the Default Email Notification 
                preference (None, Daily, Weekly, or Immediate). If you are NOT a Primary or Secondary Delegate, 
                you can leave those fields as unchecked.</para>
            
                <para>You can choose to get email reminders on one of these Default Email
                Notification schedules: <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">None</emphasis> (KEW won’t send you any email
                            reminders for your Action List.) </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Daily</emphasis> (If you have any new action
                            requests, KEW sends you an email reminder once a day.) </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Weekly</emphasis> (If you have any new action
                            requests, KEW sends you an email reminder once a week.) </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Immediately</emphasis> (KEW sends you an email
                            reminder as soon as you receive a new action request on a document. This
                            is the default – the setting when you start to use KEW.) </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            
            <para>The first new option allows overriding of the ‘Default Email Notification’ preference 
                and setting of different frequencies to receive notifications based on the document type 
                of the action request (Timesheet, EPTO, Hire Employee eDoc, Create Additional Pay eDoc, 
                Requisition, etc.).</para>
            <para>The parameters set for the default email notification and document-type notification work 
                together to determine when a given action item is included in the immediate, daily, or 
                weekly email reminders.</para>  
            <para>If one sets a ‘Default Email Notification’ without any ‘Document Type Notifications,’ 
                then emails are sent (or not sent), based on the default selection.</para>
            <para>The second new option allows one to turn notifications on or off based on the request 
                type (Complete, Approve, Acknowledge, or FYI) when “Immediate” is set as the ‘Default 
                Email Notification.’</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Action List Preferences: Document Type Notifications</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/document_type_notifications.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>    
            <para>However, adding a ‘Document Type Notification’ that is different from 
                the ‘Default Email Notification,’ forces the document-type notification to take 
                precedence. This allows users to customize by document- type for email reminders. 
                For example:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>If ‘Immediate’ is set as the ‘Default Email Notification,’ but a 
                        document-type rule is set to ’None’ for the Maintain Time Assignment eDoc; 
                        then no email notifications are sent for that specific document.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem><para>If ‘Daily’ is the ‘Default Email Notification,’ and a document-type rule 
                        is added to receive ‘Weekly notifications for the Hire Employee eDoc; then for that document, 
                        the only action request email received is a Weekly reminder.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem><para>If ‘None’ is set as the ‘Default Email Notification,’ and a document-type rule 
                        is added to receive “Daily” notifications for EPIC Purchase Orders; then for that document, 
                        the only action request email received is a Daily reminder.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>In addition, when the ‘Default Email Notification’ is set to “Immediate” one can use the Send Email 
                Notifications For option to decide whether or not to receive notifications by request-type.</para>
            <para>All four of the request-types are already “checked” by default in your Workflow Preferences screen.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>Action List Preferences: Action Requested Email Notification</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/action_requested_email_notification.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure> 
            <para>When an action request is received, and the preference is set to receive an immediate reminder, the system 
                checks to ensure that the request-type checkbox is turned-on (checked) before an email is sent.</para>
            <para>This allows these checkboxes to be used as a switch to ‘turn-on or turn-off’ the “immediate” email 
                reminders for a given request type. For example:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>To stop the receipt of Acknowledgement emails when your preference is set to 
                    receive “Immediate” reminders, just uncheck the “Acknowledge” checkbox.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Remember, all of these preferences and settings are on your Action List
            Preferences page.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2><title>Action List Refresh and Filter</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>Refresh</title>
                <para>As described above, you can use the Action List Preferences page to tell
                    KEW to automatically update (refresh) the information on your Action List on
                    a regular schedule, such as every 15 minutes. You can also click the Refresh
                    button near the top of your Action List page to update the page at any time.
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Filter</title>
                <para>If you have a large Action List, the Filter function can help you by
                    displaying only action requests of certain types. To use the Filter
                    function, click the Filter button in the top right corner of your Action
                    List page:</para>
                <para>This displays the <emphasis role="bold">Action List Filter</emphasis>
                    page: </para>
                <figure><title>Action List Filter Page</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_filter.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Keys to using the Action List Filter:</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Each of the fields on the Action List Filter page is called a
                            criteria. You can choose to display only the action requests that
                            are the same as one or more criteria, or you can choose to display
                            all action requests except those that are the same as one or more
                            criteria. You can also use some criteria to display action requests
                            and some to not display action requests. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If you want the filter to display action requests that meet one or
                            more criteria, then just enter those criteria in the appropriate
                            fields (field descriptions are below). Leave the Exclude? checkboxes
                            blank for these criteria. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If you want the filter to display only the action requests that
                            don’t match one or more criteria, then checkmark the Exclude?
                            checkbox for each of these criteria. This tells KEW not to display
                            action requests that match these criteria. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When you’ve selected the criteria you want to use in your filter,
                            click the Filter button at the bottom of the Action List Filter
                            page. KEW displays your Action List filtered in the way you
                            requested. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>To display all action requests on your Action List page again,
                            click the Clear button at the bottom of the Action List Filter page
                            or the Clear Filter button at the top of your Action List page.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>To undo your most recent filter criteria, click the Reset button
                            at the bottom of the Action List Filter page. This returns you to
                            the list of Action Requests that met your previous set of filter
                            criteria. </para>
                    </listitem>                        
                </itemizedlist>
                <note><para>Note: The filter is case sensitive – use upper and lower case
                    (capital letters and small letters) exactly the same as the item
                    you’re filtering. For example, if an actual document title is Travel
                    Doc 2, then you must type this in the Document Title field with a
                    capital letter at the beginning of each word, exactly like the real
                    document title. If you type it as travel doc 2, then the filter
                    won’t recognize this document because the capitalization is
                    different. </para></note>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Filter Criteria:</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Document Title</emphasis>: The title given
                            to the document when it was created. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Document Route Status</emphasis>: The
                            current routing Status of the document. You may filter for documents
                            with these routing statuses: <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">All</emphasis>: Selecting All
                                        causes KEW to display all documents that have been
                                        submitted for routing. If you select All and Exclude
                                        (for the Document Route Status criteria), then KEW
                                        displays only documents that are in Initiated status. </para>
                                    <note><para>Documents that are in Initiated Status have not yet
                                        been submitted for routing.</para></note>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Approved</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Disapproved</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Enroute</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Exception</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Processed</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Saved</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Action Requested</emphasis>: The action you
                            need to take on a document. You may filter your action requests by
                            these Action Requests: <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">All</emphasis>: matches all
                                        Action Requested types </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Acknowledge</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Approve</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">Complete</emphasis></para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para><emphasis role="bold">FYI</emphasis>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Action Requested Group</emphasis>: You may
                            filter your action requests by the group to which the action
                            requests were sent. For example, if you are a member of two groups,
                            you might use this filter to display only the action requests you’ve
                            received as part of one of those groups.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Document Type</emphasis>: Use this to filter
                            based on Document Type. <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>The document’s type tells KEW who needs to take what
                                        action on that document. This determines where KEW
                                        routes the document. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>You can use the Type filter to display only documents
                                        of one type, or to display all of your documents except
                                        one type. Click the checkbox next to <emphasis
                                            role="bold">Exclude?</emphasis> if you do NOT want
                                        to display the selected Type. </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>To choose a Type for your filter, click the magnifying
                                        glass icon on the Type row. This takes you to the
                                            <emphasis role="bold">Document Type
                                            Lookup</emphasis> page. </para>
                                    <para>Enter information in one or more of these fields to
                                        find the Document Type you need for your filter, then
                                        click the Search button. This displays a list of
                                        document Types that match your search. Find the one you
                                        need, and click return value for that Type. This returns
                                        you to the previous page and automatically enters it in
                                        the Type field. For example, in the screenshot below you
                                        searched for a Type with maintenance in the Name. If you
                                        want to use the first one in the list, KIM Principal
                                        Maintenance Document, click return value in the row for
                                        KIM Principal Maintenance Document. </para>
                                    <figure><title>Document Type Lookup</title>
                                        <mediaobject>
                                            <imageobject>
                                                <imagedata
                                                  fileref="../images/document_type_lookup.png"
                                                  scale="85"/>
                                            </imageobject>
                                        </mediaobject>
                                    </figure>
                                    <note><para>If you do not find the Type that you need, you can
                                        either do another search or click the link for return
                                        with no value to return to the Action List Filter page
                                        without a Type.</para></note>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Date Created</emphasis>: Use this filter
                            criteria to select only action requests for documents that were (or
                            were not) created between dates that you choose. You must enter each
                            date in this format: MM/DD/YYYY, e.g., 12/25/2000 for December 25,
                            2000. Instead of typing the date in the field, you can click the
                            small Calendar icon next to the date field and then click the date
                            you need from the calendar. When you click a date on the calendar,
                            the small calendar disappears and that date is automatically entered
                            in the date field. Use the small arrowheads on either side of the
                            month’s name to display other months. A single arrowhead moves the
                            calendar one month forward or back. A double arrowhead moves the
                            calendar to the same month a year ahead or back. </para>
                        <para>For example, if you could click the single arrowhead to the left
                            of “April” on this calendar, the month displayed would change to
                            March 2009. If you could click the double arrowhead to the right of
                            “April”, the month would change to April 2010.</para>
                        <figure><title>Date Widget</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata fileref="../images/date_created.png" scale="85"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Date Last Assigned</emphasis>: Use this
                            filter criteria to select only action requests for documents that
                            were (or were not) assigned to someone between dates that you
                            choose. You must enter each date in this format: MM/DD/YYYY. For
                            more detail on entering or selecting dates, see Date Created
                            above.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Clear Filter</title>
                <para>When you have used a filter on your Action List, you can see a Clear
                    Filter button at the top of your page:</para>
                <figure><title>Action List: Clear Filter Button</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/action_list_old.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Click this button to display all of your action requests again. </para>
                <note><para>If your Action List is not filtered, you cannot see the Clear Filter
                    button.</para></note>
                <para>Remember, you can click the Filter button at the top of your Action List
                    page to return to the Filter page and change or Reset your filters.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Action Requests and Actions Guide </title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <para>Action Requests are one of the core functions of the Kuali Enterprise Workflow
                (KEW) system. An Action Request is a call from KEW to a person or group to take
                action on a document. Action Requests are created when the system or a person routes
                (sends) a document to another user and ask that user to do something with the
                document. You might ask someone to approve an expense, for example, or to
                acknowledge that he or she received a copy of an expense report. </para>
            <para>Once an Action Request has been created in KEW, the associated document is sent to
                the appropriate users’ action lists. A user can open his or her Action List and from
                there, view information about the document, open the document, and/or take the
                requested action. If a user takes an action, for example, approves or disapproves a
                document, that is called an Action Taken.</para>
            <para>The path that the document takes from its starting point to final approval is
                called its route. Each point along that path where a person needs to do something
                with the document (approve, acknowledge, etc.) is called a node on the route.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Types of Action Requests</title>
            <para>Each action request has one row on your Action List. There are five types of
                Action Requests:</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Types of Action Requests</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.79*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.69*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Action Requested </entry>
                                <entry>Description </entry>
                                <entry>Stops Document Until Action is Taken? </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Complete </entry>
                                <entry><para>You need to Complete the document.</para>
                                <para>You may cancel a document when you have a Complete action
                                        request on it.</para></entry>
                                <entry>Yes</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Approve </entry>
                                <entry><para>You should verify the document and either Approve or Disapprove it. </para>
                                <para>You may cancel a document when you have an Approve action
                                        request on it.</para></entry>
                                <entry>Yes</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Acknowledge </entry>
                                <entry>You need to acknowledge (agree) that you have seen the
                                    document </entry>
                                <entry><para>No</para>
                                <para>If there are no other requests, the document changes to
                                        Processed status even if there are outstanding Acknowledge
                                        requests. </para></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FYI </entry>
                                <entry>You have been told about this document and you need to Clear
                                    the FYI on it</entry>
                                <entry><para>No</para>
                                <para>If there are no other requests, the document changes to Final
                                        status even if there are outstanding FYI requests.</para></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Print</entry>
                                <entry>You need to print this document and take some action with it,
                                    such as mailing it to a vendor.</entry>
                                <entry/>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>You can only Disapprove or Cancel a document if you have a Complete or
                            Approve request. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Complete and Approve are essentially the same: A Complete action
                            satisfies an Approve request, and an Approve action satisfies a Complete
                            request. </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When you Clear an FYI request, that action is not recorded on the
                            Route Log (history of where the document has been and what has been done
                            on it) for that document. </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>There are other actions that you can take in addition to Action Requests. We will
                look at those in the Action Taken section below.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action Request Recipients</title>
            <para>Every action request has a recipient. The recipient is the individual or group of
                individuals whose action is requested on the document. There are three types of recipients:<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Person: An individual </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Group: A group of users who are members of a KIM Group </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Role: A group of users who are members of a KIM Role </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
            <para>Roles are groups of users or KIM Groups associated with a document. </para>
            <para>The first user in a Group to take action on a request satisfies (completes) that
                request. Role requests can be set up to work the same way as Group requests or to
                require that everyone in that Role approves the document before the request is
                satisfied.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action Request Hierarchies</title>
            <para>In certain situations, you can use roles for action requests and you can delegate
                action requests. You can think of these as trees or as a parent action request that
                has children action requests.</para>
            <para>Roles are groups of Principals or Groups that KEW creates based on rules your
                institution sets up. Since KEW can only create an action request for a single person
                or group but a role may have several people or groups in it, KEW creates an action
                request for the role (a parent request), and that action request creates child
                action requests that go to each person or group in that role. </para>
            <para>The parent role request can have any number of children requests that are each
                either a user request or a group request.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Action Request Delegation</title>
                <para>In KEW, you may delegate, or give, your request authority to other people. For
                    example, if Joe is the fiscal officer for an account but he doesn't actually
                    approve documents, he may delegate his approval authority to Jane. Both Joe and
                    Jane can now take actions on Joe’s action requests</para>
                <para>If Jane approves a document as Joe’s delegate, Joe's action request is
                    satisfied. If Joe approves the document, Jane's action request is satisfied.
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Combining Role Requests and Delegation</title>
                <para>You can combine a role request with a delegate. In fact, in the previous
                    example, the action request that is sent to Joe as a fiscal officer is really a
                    role request. The action request tree for that scenario is:</para>
                <figure><title>Delegation Tree Example</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/action_request_tree.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>This tree is three levels deep and shows a role delegating to a user. You can
                    also have a role delegate to another role.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Action Request Activation and Deactivation</title>
            <sect3>
                <title>Activation</title>
                <para>When action requests are created, they are in the Initialized state. They stay in
                    this state until KEW determines that they need to be Activated. When a request
                    becomes Activated, it appears in the user's Action List. </para>
                <para>When action requests are created, they can be set to ignore previous actions or not.<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>If <emphasis role="italic">Ignore Previous</emphasis> is true, the
                                activation process will not consider previous actions that the user has
                                taken. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>If <emphasis role="italic">Ignore Previous</emphasis> is false, the
                                activation process will consider previous actions by the user and may
                                even consider the action request satisfied by previous user actions.
                                (This is sometimes referred to as a request being "auto-approved.")
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>During request activation, if the Ignore Previous flag is false and KEW determines
                    that a previous action satisfies the current request, it will Deactivate the request
                    instead of Activating it. Activation begins at a root request, but Deactivation
                    begins at the request where KEW finds that a satisfying action has occurred if that
                    request is set to not ignore previous actions.</para>
                <note>
                    <para>Action request structures can be hierarchical. Activation of requests always
                        starts at the parent request and works down the tree, activating each level of the
                        tree in turn. </para>
                    <para>Roles can have an All Approve policy. All Approve means that all members of a role
                        must approve the docusment before the entire request is deactivated. (See
                        Deactivation below.)</para>
                </note>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Deactivation</title>
                <para>When a user takes action on a document, that action may start the deactivation
                    of other action requests on the document. For example, if Joe has a pending
                    request and he takes an Approve action on it, his request is deactivated.
                    Request deactivation changes the status of the request from Initialized or
                    Activated to Deactivated. </para>
                <para>If Joe’s action taken causes other action requests to be Deactivated, his
                    action taken is associated with all of the requests that it Deactivates. </para>
                <para>Unlike Activation, Deactivation always starts at the request that was
                    satisfied by the action taken. For example, if Joe is delegating to Jane and
                    Jane issues an Approve action on her request, Deactivation starts at Jane's
                    request. However, if Joe issues the Approve action, Deactivation starts at the
                    parent. </para>
                <figure><title>Delegation Tree Example: Deactivation</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/deactivation_flow.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>If there are no roles set to "All Approve" on an action request, one action
                    can Deactivate the entire request tree. This is because KEW works up and down
                    the tree, Deactivating requests as it goes.</para>
                <para>However, when there is an "All Approve" role, requests for all parties within
                    the role must be Deactivated before the parent role request is Deactivated. For
                    example, if we have an "All Approve" role request with three children requests,
                    when one of the users takes action, their request is Deactivated, but since
                    there are two other requests that still need to be satisfied, the Deactivation
                    cannot go back to the parent role request. When the last of the three users has
                    taken action, the parent role request is Deactivated.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Actions and Action Takens</title>
            <para>Actions are how a user interacts with KEW. Actions can be performed in response to
                an Action Request (such as an Approve action) or they can be user-initiated (such as
                the routing of a document). Most, but not all, actions create Action Takens. The
                Action Taken is recorded on the Route Log and associated with a satisfied action
                request, where appropriate.</para>
            <para>The KEW Action library contains these Actions, explained below:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Acknowledge </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Approve </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Blanket Approve </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Cancel </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Clear FYI </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Complete </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Create Document </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Disapprove </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Log Document </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Move Document </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Return to Previous Node </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Route Document </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Save </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Superuser Actions <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Superuser Approve Document </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Superuser Approve Node </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Superuser Approve Request </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Superuser Cancel </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Superuser Disapprove </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Acknowledge Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to satisfy an Acknowledge action request. When you take an
                    Acknowledge action, it usually means that you have examined the document.
                    Acknowledgement provides no real authority over the document; you can only take
                    the Acknowledge action on this document.</para>
                <para>When you take an Acknowledge action, KEW finds all pending acknowledge
                    requests for that document that are routed to you and Deactivates them. It then
                    records an Acknowledge Action Taken and associates it with the Deactivated
                    requests. You may take an Acknowledge action even if you have no Acknowledge
                    Action Requests.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Approve Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to satisfy an Approve or Complete action request. When you use
                    an Approve action, it means that you have looked at the document and approve
                    that transaction.</para>
                <para>When you use the Approve action, KEW Deactivates all pending approve or
                    complete requests that have been routed to you for this document. You may take
                    an Approve action even if you have no Approve or Complete action
                    requests.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Blanket Approve Action</title>
                <para>Use the Blanket Approve action to force a document to complete a set of action
                    requests. This allows certain users to "push" a document through its routing. To
                    take this action, you must have the appropriate KIM Permission (or be in the
                    Blanket Approve Group which is set in the Document Type, but that is a
                    deprecated feature). Unless you select a specific node (point in the document’s
                    routing path) when you take a Blanket Approve Action, KEW finds all pending
                    Approve or Complete requests at the current level in the request tree and
                    Deactivates them. It records a Blanket Approve Action Taken and associates it
                    with each of the Deactivated requests.</para>
                <para>Then, KEW sends Acknowledge action requests to each person whose action
                    request was satisfied by the Blanket Approve. It does this for all levels in the
                    request tree until it reaches the end point set in the Blanket Approve Action or
                    it reaches the end of the request tree.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Cancel Action</title>
                <para>Use this action when a document is no longer valid and you need to cancel it.
                    You must have a pending Approve or Complete action request on the document
                    before you can Cancel it. Cancelling a document is similar to Disapproving it
                    except that the Cancel action does not send out notifications.</para>
                <para>When you take a Cancel action, KEW finds all pending requests on the document
                    and Deactivates them. It records a Cancel Action Taken and associates it with
                    the Deactivated requests. Then it sets the document's status to CANCELLED and
                    the document is effectively dead.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Clear FYI Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to satisfy an FYI action request. You usually get an FYI just
                    to notify you about a document. You don’t need to take any action on an FYI
                    request, but if you want to remove that FYI and document from your Action List,
                    take the Clear FYI action.</para>
                <para>When you take the Clear FYI action KEW locates all pending FYI requests on
                    this document that are routed to you and Deactivates them. It then records an
                    FYI Action Taken. You must have a pending FYI request on a document to use the
                    Clear FYI action.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Complete Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to satisfy an Approve or Complete action request. When you use
                    a Complete, it means that you have looked at the document and completed any of
                    the necessary information on the document so it can proceed. Complete action
                    requests are typically created as the result of a Save action or in response to
                    an Exception Routing request.</para>
                <para>When you use the Complete action KEW finds all pending Approve or Complete
                    requests that are routed to you and Deactivates them. If the document is in the
                    Exception state, it changes it back to Enroute. It then records a Complete
                    Action Taken. You may take a Complete action even if you have no Complete or
                    Approve action requests.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Create Document Action</title>
                <para>This action creates a new document in KEW of the chosen Document Type. This
                    action does not record an Action Taken of any sort but simply begins a new
                    document and assigns a document ID to it. The document begins in Initiated
                    status. The Document type determines how the document is routed and what must be
                    done for it. For example, an expense report might be routed (sent) to two or
                    three different people for approval before it is paid.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Disapprove Action</title>
                <para>When you have an Approve action request, you use a Disapprove action if the
                    document does not meet the approval criteria. You must have a pending Approve or
                    Complete request on the document before you can Disapprove it. Disapproving a
                    document is similar to Cancelling it, except that Disapproval sends out
                    notifications.</para>
                <para>When you Disapprove a document, KEW finds all pending requests on the document
                    and Deactivates them. Next, it creates Acknowledge notification requests to all
                    users that had Approve or Complete action requests at the current node and all
                    previous nodes. It also sends an Acknowledge notification request to the
                    initiator of the document. Then the document's status is set to Disapproved and
                    the document is effectively dead.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Log Document Action</title>
                <para>This action simply enters a message on the document. It records an Action
                    Taken but it is never associated with any action requests. This action displays
                    a message on the document in the Route Log.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Move Document Action</title>
                <para>This action moves a document either backward in the route path or forward.
                    Moving the document backward works like the Return to Previous Node action and
                    moving the document forward works like a Blanket Approve action. The difference
                    between these is that the Action Taken is recorded as a Move action. </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Return to Previous Node Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to move a document to a previous node in the route. You must
                    have a pending Approve or Complete request on the document before you can use
                    this action.</para>
                <para>When you use this action, KEW Deactivates all pending requests on the document
                    and sets the current node on the document to the previous node that you
                    requested (this is called the target node). It records a Return to Previous Node
                    Action Taken and associates it with the Deactivated requests. Any requests on
                    nodes between the current node and the target node are removed, effectively
                    erasing them. KEW then sends the document through again to recreate requests on
                    the target node. This way a document is "returned" to a previous node, rolling
                    it back to its previous state at that point in the route.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Route Document Action</title>
                <para>Use the Route Document action to route an Initialized or Saved document to
                    other users. Only the initiator of the document can take this action unless the
                    user has an "Initiate Document" KIM permission (or initiator_must_route policy
                    is set to false in the Document Type, although this feature is deprecated). The
                    Action Taken for a Route Document action is Complete.</para>
                <para>When you use the Route Document action, it Deactivates all pending requests
                    for the initiator of the document and it associates a Complete Action Taken with
                    the Deactivated requests. The document’s state is then set to Enroute.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Save Document Action</title>
                <para>Use this action to put a newly created document in the Action List of the
                    document’s initiator. You can only use this action on a document in an Initiated
                    status. When you use this action, KEW creates and Activates a Complete action
                    request for the document’s initiator and then changes the document’s status to
                    Saved.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Actions </title>
                <para>Superuser actions let you move a document past workflow nodes where it may be
                    held up because another user is unavailable to take action on it or due to a
                    system problem. Superuser actions are an administrative tool and safety net.
                    Superusers are designated with a KIM Permission (or they are listed in the
                    Document Type, but this feature is deprecated). </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Using the Superuser Functions</title>
                <para>To use the Superuser functions, go to Document Search (it is a link in the
                    left menu) and click the Superuser Search link.</para>
                <para>Now, do a normal document search for the document on which you need to perform
                    a Superuser action. When you find the document, click the Document/Notification
                    Id link. If you are authorized to perform a Superuser action on this document,
                    this takes you to the Superuser page. Otherwise, KEW displays a message that you
                    are not authorized to take Superuser action on this document.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Approve Document Action</title>
                <para>This action fully approves a document, Deactivating all remaining routing
                    requests. KEW also records a Superuser Approve Action Taken and associates it
                    with the Deactivated requests. The document's state changes to Approved and the
                    document is scheduled for processing. The document status automatically changes
                    to Final when it goes into the Workflow Engine. </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Approve Node Action</title>
                <para>This action approves the document through all nodes up to (but not including)
                    a specified node. When the document gets to the specified node, requests are
                    created as usual. This action is exactly the same as Blanket Approve except that
                    no notification requests are created from the Superuser Approve Node
                    action.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Approve Request Action</title>
                <para>This action approves a single pending Approve or Complete action request. This
                    works the same way as a standard Approve action except that the Superuser is
                    acting in place of the responsible user.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Cancel Action</title>
                <para>This action cancels the document. This action works exactly the same way as
                    the standard Cancel action except that the Superuser does not need to have a
                    pending request to Cancel a document.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Disapprove Action</title>
                <para>This action disapproves the document. This action works the same way as the
                    standard Disapprove action except that the Superuser does not need to have a
                    pending request to perform the action. Also, on a Superuser disapprove, KEW does
                    not send notification requests.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Superuser Return to Previous Node Action</title>
                <para>This action returns the document to a previous node in the route path. This
                    action works exactly the same way as the standard Return to Previous Node action
                    except that the Superuser does not need to have a pending request to perform the
                    action.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>    
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Documents</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>eDocLite Overview</title>
            <para>eDocLite is a framework designed for rapid development and implementation within
                an existing Kuali Enterprise Workflow infrastructure. It allows for the development
                of simple web applications, their forms and routing configurations using XML. Users
                only have to enter data into the form and then submit it. Rules can be constructed
                so that the form is then routed to a specific user or KIM Group based on the data
                entered.</para>
            <para>Web pages called eDoc's are generated and are associated with a specific document
                type definition that provides the overall definition for how the document can be
                routed. Document types can also exist in hierarchies which provide storage of common
                information at various levels.</para>
            <para>The form uses an XSLT stylesheet to generate the html code. Certain workflow
                classes make helper data available to the stylesheet programmer and there are
                several features that can be 'plugged-in' to eDocLite to further enhance its
                usability in many situations.</para>
            <note>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Key Ideas</emphasis>:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rapid implementation and development solution for simpler documents
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Easily re-configured </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Easily manageable </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Entirely web-based from design/development and user perspectives
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>No java code required for developments; only XML with optional
                            javascript for client side editing (workflow handles execution) </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Some validation javascript is automatically generated like regular
                            expression editing and 'required field checking'. </para>
                    </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
            </note>    
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>eDocLite Lookup</title>
            <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">eDocLite Lookup</emphasis> screen to quickly find
                basic information about eDocLite documents and as the first step in creating a new
                eDocLite. </para>
            <figure><title>Workflow Channel: eDocLite Link</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/edoclite_link.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject></figure>
            <sect3>
                <title>Finding the eDocLite Lookup Screen</title>
                <para>You can go to the <emphasis role="bold">eDocLite Lookup</emphasis> by:<orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click the Main Menu tab </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Look in the Workflow section </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Click eDoc Lite </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>eDocLite Lookup</title>
                <figure><title>eDocLite Lookup</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/edoclite_lookup.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>On the eDocLite lookup page, users can search for an eDocLite document based
                    on several criteria:</para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>eDocLite Lookup Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.47*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Id</entry>
                                    <entry>The unique ID number assigned to each document.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the document type, which is specified in the
                                        Document Type attribute of an eDocLite.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Definition</entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the EDL XML definition.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Style</entry>
                                    <entry>The style specified in the EDL XML file is the style
                                        attribute of an eDocLite. Generally an EDL XML file has only
                                        one definition name which relates to one and only one style
                                        name.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active Indicator</entry>
                                    <entry>You have the choice of searching by the active status of
                                        an eDocLite. </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
                <para>You can use the above criteria to limit your search results. A search will
                    produce a list of one or more results that look similar to the following:</para>
                <figure><title>eDocLite Lookup: Search Results</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/search_results.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Clicking <emphasis role="bold">Create Document</emphasis> on any line takes
                    you to the eDocLite document screen where new documents can be created. The line
                    item you choose will result in that document being used as a template for the
                    new one you are creating. More information on this follows in the section called
                        <emphasis role="bold">Create New eDocLite Document</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>Clicking any underlined Id will take you to the <emphasis role="bold">eDocLite
                        Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that document.</para>
                <note><para>Exporting the output list to XML will give you the option of viewing the XML
                used to produce the list returned from the search.</para>
                    </note>
                    <para>Standard in KEW there is one eDocLite for electronic routing, and new
                    eDocLites can be added based on business requirements. Some of the functions
                    that eDocLites are used for in business include: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Applicant Monitoring </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>BLSC Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Course Change Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Grade Replacement Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Internship Contract </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Interview Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Mass Mailing Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Offer Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Program Plan Update </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>REGR Access Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Removal Of Incomplete </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Revenue Producing Activity </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>SUDS Request Document Type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Search Status </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Special Credit Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Student Trip </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>User Agreement </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Unit Change Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Vacancy Notice </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Vehicle Replacement </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Waiver Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>New Course Request </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>eDocLite Inquiry</title>
            <figure><title>eDocLite Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/edoclite_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The Inquiry screen displays the same information as is found on a line of the
                Lookup output, but this screen provides you with the export option. Exporting from
                the Inquiry screen produces a XML file of the source for the eDocLite
                document.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Create New eDocLite Document</title>
            <para>To create a new eDocLite document to be routed in KEW, click on <emphasis
                    role="bold">Create Document</emphasis> in the row for eDocLite type wanted. It
                will take users to different forms of eDocLites depending on the document function,
                but they all have three general parts:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Document header </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Document body </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Routing action and annotation, and note area </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Header</title>
                <para>The Document Header contains the following fields: <table frame="none">
                        <title>Document Header Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="3.08*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                    <entry>The name defined by the document creator of this type of
                                        eDocLite.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document Status</entry>
                                    <entry>The status of this document based on its routing
                                        status.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Create Date</entry>
                                    <entry>The date and time this document is created.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document ID</entry>
                                    <entry>The unique system generated ID for this document.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document body</title>
                <para>This portion of the document is where the user identifies the routing and
                    complete business function. </para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Document Body Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.92*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Title</entry>
                                    <entry>specifies the actions users are taking on the EDocLite
                                        forms, including <emphasis role="bold">editing</emphasis>
                                        and <emphasis role="bold">reviewing</emphasis>. Other
                                        general information can be stored here such as contact
                                        information, important notes, etc.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Form</entry>
                                    <entry>Renders form fields and input areas for the user to
                                        complete information required, depends upon the specific
                                        eDocLite requirements.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Routing Action and Annotation, and Note area</title>
                <para>This area is used to add annotation and choose action to be taken on this
                    eDocLite document. Annotation is the comments associated with the routing
                    process. You can add them to different nodes of the routing process and take
                    actions on an eDocLite by adding annotations. The annotation appears in the
                    route log of eDocLite as comments. Notes are the comments associated with this
                    specific eDocLite form and appear with the form and not in the route log. </para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Routing Action and Annotation, and Note Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.45*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Set annotation</entry>
                                    <entry>The area to add annotation.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Action buttons</entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>route: begins and continues routing the
                                                  eDocLite document.</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>save: saves the information currently on the
                                                  eDocLite document.</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>cancel: cancels the actions on this eDocLite
                                                  document, and the information on the form is not
                                                  saved.</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>create note</entry>
                                    <entry>Area where users can add notes and attach documents to
                                        this eDocLite form. This part keeps track of <emphasis
                                            role="bold">Author, Date and time</emphasis>, and the
                                            <emphasis role="bold">Note</emphasis> added. Users have
                                        the right to add, edit and delete the notes they
                                        create.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
                <para>The following is one example of an eDocLite form:</para>
                <para><inlinemediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/edoclite_form.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </inlinemediaobject></para>
                <note><para>Notes that have been added to an eDocLite document can be edited or
                    deleted.</para></note>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Extendable functions</title>
                <para>eDocLites are highly customizable. New eDocLites can be designed for new
                    business and functional requirements. The document header and routing annotation
                    and notes parts will be same or similar, the form will be different. </para>
                <para>eDocLites can be designed to include following functions:</para>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Restricted read/write rights</title>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Some fields in eDocLite can be set as <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >GlobalReadOnly</emphasis>. With this setting they are disabled
                                and can’t be edited by any user other than the author. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Some fields in eDocLite can be set as <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >ReadOnly</emphasis>, but users with rights can still edit them.
                                After the initiator writes them they are disabled and become locked
                                to some of the users in the routing process. But for users with
                                proper rights in certain nodes in the routing process, the fields
                                will become editable again. These users can take actions on them,
                                such as modify, add, and return to a former routing node.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Hidden fields</title>
                    <para>To accommodate some business requirements, certain fields and notes can be
                        hidden from certain nodes in the routing process. For instance, some
                        administrative notes on a course waiver request will be hidden from students
                        when s/he gets the eDocLite form in the final stage of the routing
                        process.</para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Preferences</title>
        <para>Workflow allows for users to individually configure certain aspects of the system. You
            should be able to access the User Preferences from the Main portal page:</para>
        <figure><title>Workflow Channel: User Preferences Link</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/select_user_preferences.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>After clicking the link you should be taken to Workflow Preferences screen:</para>
        <figure><title>Workflow Preferences</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/workflow_preferences.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>There are three configuration sections on this screen:</para>
        <sect2>
            <title>General Preferences</title>
            <note><para>Many of these preferences can have their system wide default values changed via
                configuration parameters. Look in the KEW technical documentation for information on
                how to override the default values.</para></note>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>User Preferences Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.14*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="2.41*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Name</entry>
                                <entry>Default Value</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Automatic Refresh Rate</entry>
                                <entry>15</entry>
                                <entry>How often your action list updates (minutes).</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Action List Page Size</entry>
                                <entry>10</entry>
                                <entry># of actions displayed on action list</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Email Notification</entry>
                                <entry>Immediate</entry>
                                <entry>When action items emails should be sent. Can be none,
                                    immediate, daily, weekly</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Receive Primary Delegation Emails</entry>
                                <entry>True</entry>
                                <entry>User will receive primary delegate emails</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Receive Secondary Delegation Emails</entry>
                                <entry>False</entry>
                                <entry>User will receive secondary delegate emails</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Delegator Filter</entry>
                                <entry>Secondary Delegators on Action List Page</entry>
                                <entry><para>Determines what is displayed on the action list page.  Options:</para>
                                    <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>Secondary Delegators on Action List Page</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>Secondary Delegators only on Filter Page</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Primary Delegate Filter</entry>
                                <entry>Primary Delegators on Action List Page</entry>
                                <entry><para>Determines what is displayed on the action list page. Options:</para> <itemizedlist>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>Primary Delegators on Action List Page</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                        <listitem>
                                            <para>Primary Delegators only on Filter Page</para>
                                        </listitem>
                                    </itemizedlist></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Fields Displayed in Action List Preferences</title>
            <para>These are the columns that will be displayed on the user’s action list
                page.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>User Preferences: Fields Displayed Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Name</entry>
                                <entry>Default Value</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Title</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>ActionRequested</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Initiator</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Delegator</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Date Created</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Date Approved</entry>
                                <entry>FALSE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Current Route Node(s)</entry>
                                <entry>FALSE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Workgroup Request</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Document Route Status</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Application Document Status</entry>
                                <entry>FALSE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Clear FYI</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Use Outbox</entry>
                                <entry>TRUE</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Document Route Status Colors for Action list Entries</title>
            <para>Each Document Route Status can be displayed with a certain color on the action
                list. This section allows you to configure which colors are used. By default, no
                colors are set.</para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Routing</title>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Please Note:</emphasis> The following secitons on routing and
            rules are written as they relate the legacy/traditional KNS workflow. A new concept of
            workflows, called PeopleFlows, and their use and maintenance is covered in a separate
            section.</para>
        <sect2>
            <title>Delegate Rules and Delegation Routing Rules</title>
            <para>Rice provides a quick and convenient way to obtain information on Delegation Rules
                through the <emphasis role="bold">Delegate Rule Lookup</emphasis>. This Lookup also
                lets you create new Delegation Rules using the <emphasis role="bold">create
                    new</emphasis> function and edit existing Delegation Rules.</para>
            <figure><title>Workflow Channel: Routing Rules Delegation Link</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/routing_rules_delegation.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>To access the <emphasis role="bold">Delegate Rule Lookup</emphasis> screen, click
                    <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rules Delegation</emphasis> on the Rice Main
                Menu.</para>
            <figure><title>Delegation Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/delegate_rule_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Use the <emphasis role="bold">Delegate Rule Lookup</emphasis> screen to find
                information about a Delegation Rule. You can also create a new Rule by clicking the
                create new button in the upper right corner of the screen. The create new function
                is described in the Routing Rule Creation section later in this document.</para>
            <para>When you do a search from the Delegate Rule Lookup screen, you can:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>View the Delegation Rule information returned by the search </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Edit a Delegation Rule </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Copy an existing Delegation Rule and create a new one based on that
                            copy </para>
                    </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>Information about the Lookup function is in the next section of this document. The
                other two functions are described in the Routing Rule Delegation Maintenance section
                later in this document.</para>
            <para>To find a Delegation Rule quickly, enter information in one or more of the fields
                on the Lookup screen, then click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button.
                If you are not familiar with the search fields, you can leave all of the fields
                blank and click the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button. The <emphasis
                    role="bold">Delegate Rule Lookup</emphasis> page then displays all of the
                Delegation Rule templates.</para>
            <para>The fields on this screen are described in the Routing Rule Delegation Maintenance
                section of this document.</para>
            <note><para><emphasis role="bold">Parent Rule Id</emphasis> is a unique identification number
                for a Rule Template; therefore, searching by the Parent Rule Id can be the fastest
                way to find a particular Rule.</para></note>
            <para>After you click the search button, Delegate Rule Lookup displays a list of Rules
                that looks similar to this:</para>
            <figure><title>Delegation Lookup: Results Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rules_list.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> on any row to go to the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Routing Rule Delegation</emphasis> document for that Rule. You can
                use this document to do maintenance on that Rule. This is discussed later in this
                document, in the Routing Rule Delegation Maintenance section.</para>
            <para>Click <emphasis role="bold">copy</emphasis> on any row to go to the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Routing Rule Delegation</emphasis> document with the information
                from that Rule copied into the document. This lets you add a new Delegation Rule
                based on that information. This is discussed later in this document in the Routing
                Rule Delegation Maintenance section.</para>
            <para>Click a <emphasis role="bold">Delegation Rule Id</emphasis> to go to the <emphasis
                    role="bold">Delegation Rule Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that Rule. This screen
                displays specific information about how this Rule is set up in Rice. This screen is
                discussed later in this document in the <emphasis role="bold">Delegation Rule
                    Inquiry</emphasis> section.</para>
            <para>Click a Parent Rule Id or a Name to go to the <emphasis role="bold">Rule
                    Inquiry</emphasis> screen, where you can see details about that Parent Rule ID.
                More information about this screen can be found in the Rule Inquiry section of this
                User Guide.</para>
            <para>Click a Rule Template to go to the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Template
                    Inquiry</emphasis> screen. More information about this screen can be found in
                the Rule Template Inquiry section of this User Guide.</para>
            <para>The standard export options apply to this list of search results. An explanation
                of the export options can be found in the Common Features and Functions section of
                this User Guide.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Delegation Rule Inquiry</title>
            <figure><title>Delegation Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/delegation_rule_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>This screen provides specific information on how a <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Rule</emphasis> works. From this screen, you can either click the <emphasis
                    role="bold">close</emphasis> button to return to the previous screen or you can
                export an XML version of this information.</para>
            <para>The fields on this screen are described in the Rule Maintenance section of this
                document.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Delegate Routing Rule Creation</title>
            <figure><title>Delegation Rule: Create New Screen</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/delegate_routing_rule_creation.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>To create a new Delegate Routing Rule, start by selecting a Parent Rule to
                associate with your new Delegate Rule:<orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Do a field lookup on the Select parent rule field.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>This displays the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Lookup</emphasis> screen
                            where you search in the Rules your institution has defined in Rice to
                            find the appropriate Parent Rule for your new Delegate Routing Rule.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When you have found the appropriate Parent Rule, click its return
                            value link to return to the Delegate Routing Rule Creation screen with
                            this Parent Rule.</para>
                        <figure><title>Delegate Routing Rule: Create New, Parent Selection</title>
                            <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                    <imagedata
                                        fileref="../images/delegate_routing_rule_creation2.png"
                                        scale="85"/>
                                </imageobject>
                            </mediaobject>
                        </figure>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Information from the Parent Rule you selected is now in the <emphasis
                                role="bold">Select Parent Responsibility to Delegate From</emphasis>
                            section of the <emphasis role="bold">Delegate Routing Rule
                                Creation</emphasis> screen.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">Select</emphasis> button for this
                            parent Rule.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Click the <emphasis role="bold">continue</emphasis> button.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Rice displays the <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rule
                                Delegation</emphasis> screen. Use this screen to enter information
                            for your new Rule. This is described in the <emphasis role="bold"
                                >Routing Rule Delegation Maintenance</emphasis> section
                            (next).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist></para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Routing Rule Delegation Maintenance</title>
            <para>You can use the <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rule Delegation</emphasis> document
                screen for both editing existing Delegation Rules and for adding new Delegation
                Rules to Rice. </para>
            <figure><title>Routing Rule Delegation: Overview</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/routing_rule_delegation.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <note><para>When Rice first displays the <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rule
                    Delegation</emphasis> screen, all of the tabs except the Notes and Attachments,
                Ad Hoc Recipients, and Route Log tabs, are expanded. They are all collapsed in the
                screen print above so you can see all of them.</para></note>
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Layout</title>
                <para>The Routing Rule Delegation screen you see when creating a new Rule has eight tabs:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Document Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Delegation Details </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Delegate Rule </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Persons </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Groups </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Notes and Attachments </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Route Log </para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Delegation Details, Delegate Rule,
                        Persons</emphasis>, and <emphasis role="bold">Groups</emphasis> tabs are
                    discussed in the sections that follow. The remaining four tabs are commonly used
                    throughout Rice and are described in the Common Features and Functions section
                    of the User Guide.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Delegation Details Tab</title>
                <para>The Delegation Details tab is where you associate a Parent Rule with a
                    Delegate Rule. It is also where you assign the Reviewer role.</para>
                <para>The Delegation Details screen is displayed differently, depending on whether
                    you are creating a new Rule or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when
                    creating a new Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rule Deleation: Details Section</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/delegation_details.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The information displayed is a copy of the information for the Parent Rule.
                    Descriptions of these fields are below. Change this information as needed, then
                    click the <emphasis role="bold">submit</emphasis> button to create this new
                    Rule.</para>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying a Rule looks similar to
                    this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/copying_rules.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>When you first see this version, the information in both columns is the same.
                    You can modify the information in the fields in the right column, but not the
                    left column. After changing the information appropriately in the right column,
                    click the submit button to save your changes to this Rule.</para>
                <para>The fields are the same in both versions of the screen:</para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Routing Rules Delegation Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Parent Rule Id</entry>
                                    <entry>Rule Id of the Parent Rule for this Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                    <entry>General description of this Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Reviewer</entry>
                                    <entry>The person responsible for reviewing a document in the
                                        routing process for this Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Type</entry>
                                    <entry>The Type of the Reviewer</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Action Request</entry>
                                    <entry><para>The type of Action this Reviewer can take. This may be:</para>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Complete</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Approve</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>FYI</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Delegate Rule tab</title>
                <para>The Delegate Rule tab is displayed differently, depending on whether you are
                    creating a new Rule or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when creating
                    a new Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Delegate Rule Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/delegate_rule.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Enter the appropriate information for your new Delegate Rule in these fields.
                    There are descriptions of each of these fields below.</para>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying a Rule looks similar to
                    this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rule Delegation: Delegate Rule Tab, Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/delegate_rule_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>When you first see this version, the information in both columns is the same.
                    You can modify the information in the fields in the right column, but not the
                    left column. After changing the information in the right column
                    appropriately.</para>
                <para>The fields are the same in both versions of the screen:</para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Routing Rule Delegation: Delegate Rule Tab Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                    <entry>The Document Type defines the routing definition and
                                        other properties for a set of documents. Each document is an
                                        instance of a Document Type and conducts the same type of
                                        business transaction as other instances of that Document
                                        Type.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Rule Template</entry>
                                    <entry>A Rule Template serves as a pattern or design for routing
                                        Rules.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Delegation Type</entry>
                                    <entry><para>Required. Options for Delegation Type are:</para>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para><emphasis role="bold">Primary</emphasis>: This
                                                  means that the delegator turns over full authority
                                                  to the delegate. The Action Requests for this
                                                  delegator only show up in the Action List of the
                                                  primary delegate. A primary delegate must be
                                                  registered in KEW to be in effect.</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para><emphasis role="bold">Secondary</emphasis>:
                                                  This means that the secondary delegate acts as a
                                                  temporary backup delegator who has the same
                                                  authority as the primary approver, or the
                                                  secondary delegate acts as the delegator if the
                                                  delegator is not available. Documents appear in
                                                  the Action Lists of both the delegator and the
                                                  secondary delegate. When either person acts on the
                                                  document, it disappears from both Action Lists. A
                                                  secondary delegate must be registered in KEW as
                                                  being in effect for a specific time
                                                  period(s).</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para><emphasis role="bold">Both</emphasis></para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry><para>he unique Name of the routing delegate Rule you are creating or editing.</para> 
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>You are not required to enter a Name, but if you don’t, Rice assigns a unique Name to the Rule.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                    <entry>The general description of the Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>From Date</entry>
                                    <entry>The start date of the routing Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>To Date</entry>
                                    <entry>The expiration date of the routing Rule</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Force Action</entry>
                                    <entry>This is a Yes or No flag. A checkmark means Yes, blank
                                        means No.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active</entry>
                                    <entry>A True/False flag to indicate whether this Routing
                                        Delegate Rule is active in Rice. If it is active, you can
                                        use it in Rice.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Persons tab</title>
                <para>Rice displays the <emphasis role="bold">Persons</emphasis> tab differently,
                    depending on whether you are creating a new Rule or editing/copying a Rule. This
                    tab lets you add people to the Rule and set the type of Action each person needs
                    to take under this Rule. The version of the Persons screen that you see when
                    creating a new Delegate Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Persons Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/persons_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Enter the appropriate information for the Persons section of your new Delegate
                    Rule in these fields. There are descriptions of each of these fields
                    below.</para>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying a Rule looks similar to
                    this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Persons tab, Copy/Edit View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/persons_tab_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Use the top portion of this tab to add a new Person to this Rule and set the
                    Action that Person needs to take and its Priority. Use the lower portion of this
                    tab to change existing values for this Rule. </para>
                <note><para>When you create a new person, you must click the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >add</emphasis> button when you have entered information in the three
                    required fields. </para></note>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Routing Rules Delegation: Persons Tab Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Person</entry>
                                    <entry>Required. An individual user who receives the document
                                        for the Action Requested.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Action Request</entry>
                                    <entry><para>Required. The type of Action this person needs to take. This Action may be one of these:</para><itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Complete</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Approve</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>FYI</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Priority</entry>
                                    <entry>Required. The priority associated with the Person in this
                                        Rule. One is the highest Priority.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Groups tab</title>
                <para>The Groups tab differently, depending on whether you are creating a new Rule
                    or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when creating a new Rule looks
                    similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Groups Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/groups_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Enter the appropriate information for the Groups section of your new Delegate
                    Rule in these fields. These fields are described below.</para>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying a Rule looks similar to
                    this:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Rules Delegation: Groups Tab, Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/groups_tab_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>Use the top portion of this tab to add a new Group. Use the lower portion to
                    change existing information for a Group. </para>
                <note><para>When you create a new group, you must click the <emphasis role="bold">add</emphasis> button
                        after you enter information in the required fields.</para></note>
                <para><table frame="none">
                    <title>Routing Rules Deleation: Groups Tab Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Namespace</entry>
                                <entry>The Namespace to which this Group will belong. A Namespace is
                                        a way to set both Permissions and Entity Attributes. Each
                                        Namespace instance is one level of Permissions and Entity
                                        Attributes and is one record in Rice.</entry>
                            </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry>The unique name of this Group</entry>
                                </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Action Request</entry>
                                <entry><para>Required. The type of Action this Group is expected to take.  The Action may be one of these:</para><itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Complete</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Approve</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>FYI</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Priority</entry>
                                <entry>Required. The priority associated with the Group in this
                                        Rule. One is the highest Priority.</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table></para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Rule Lookup</title>
            <para>The Rice system provides a quick and convenient way to obtain information on Rules
                through the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Lookup</emphasis> feature. This feature also
                provides an entry point to creating a new Rule through the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >create new</emphasis> function.</para>
           
            <figure><title>Workflow Channel: Routing Rules Link</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/routing_rules_link.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>To access the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Lookup</emphasis> screen click on
                    <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rules</emphasis> on the Rice <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Main Menu</emphasis>.</para>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Rule Lookup</emphasis> screen is used to view, edit or
                copy information about routing rules defined in Rice. It is also the starting point
                for creating a new rule using the <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rule Creation
                </emphasis>screen.</para>
            <figure><title>Routing Rules Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Click on the <emphasis role="bold">create new</emphasis> button to go to the
                Routing Rule Creation screen. The process for creating a new Routing Rule is
                discussed in the <emphasis role="bold">Routing Rule Creation</emphasis> section of
                this document.</para>
            <para>To limit your search results you can select one or more of the available search
                criteria. </para>
            <para>The fields on this screen are described in the <emphasis role="bold">Rule
            Maintenance</emphasis> section of this document.</para>
            <note>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Rule Id</emphasis> is a unique identification number for a
                    particular rule template; therefore, search by rule Id can produce the most accurate
                    search result. </para>
                <para>If you are not familiar with the search criteria provided above you can simply
                    click on the <emphasis role="bold">search</emphasis> button and the Rule Lookup page
                    will automatically provide a list of rule templates.</para>
            </note>
            <para>Rule Lookups return a list that looks similar to the following:</para>
            <figure><title>Routing Rules Lookup: Results Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_lookup_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Clicking <emphasis role="bold">edit</emphasis> on any line item takes you to the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance Document Type Document</emphasis> where
                you can perform maintenance on that rule. This is discussed later in this document
                in the Rule Maintenance section.</para>
            <para>Clicking <emphasis role="bold">copy</emphasis> on any line item takes you to the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance Document Type Document</emphasis> where
                you can add a new rule based upon the rule you are copying. This is discussed later
                in this document in the Rule Maintenance section.</para>
            <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Rule Id</emphasis> will take you to the Rule
                Inquiry screen for that specific rule. This is discussed later in this document in
                the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Inquiry</emphasis> section.</para>
            <para>Clicking a <emphasis role="bold">Document Type</emphasis> will take you to the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Document Type Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that specific
                rule. This is discussed in the <emphasis role="bold">Document Type
                    Inquiry</emphasis> section of the User Guide.</para>
            <para>The standard export options apply to this list. Explanation of the export options
                can be found in the <emphasis role="bold">Common Features and Functions</emphasis>
                section of the User Guide.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Rule Inquiry</title>
            <figure><title>Routing Rules Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>This screen provides specific information on how the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Rule</emphasis> is set up in Rice. The fields on this screen are described in
                the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance</emphasis> section of this
                document.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Routing Rule Creation</title>
            <figure><title>Routing Rules Creation</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/routing_rule_creation.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>When creating a new Routing Rule you start by entering the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >Document Type</emphasis> and the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Template</emphasis>
                you want associated with your new Rule, then click the continue button. This takes
                you to the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance Document Type Document</emphasis>
                described in the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance</emphasis> section that
                follows.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Routing Rule Creation Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                <entry>You can select a new document type by clicking on the field
                                    lookup button located at the right side of the <emphasis
                                        role="bold">Doc Type </emphasis>field. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Rule Template</entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>The name of the Rule Template with which this rule is
                                        associated. A Rule Template serves as a pattern or design
                                        for the routing rules and is a mechanism for providing
                                        configuration information to rules. </para>
                                    <para>You can select a new template by clicking on the field
                                        lookup button located at right side of the Rule Template
                                        field. </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Routing Report</title>
            <para>The routing report is a tool to check workflow routing. You select a rule template
                and enter any routing data required by the rule template. You can then view the
                workflow routing that would be assigned to such a document.</para>
            <figure><title>Workflow Channel: Routing report</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/sample_travel_app.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <sect3>
                <title>Using the Report</title>
                <para>In the default implementation of Rice you can find the link to the Routing
                    Report on the "Main" tab of the portal inside the "Workflow" pane. If for some
                    reason the link is not visible on the "Main" tab you can still directly navigate
                    to the Routing Report. To access the tool directly, replace the last part of the
                    Rice Portal URL (<emphasis role="bold">portal.jsp</emphasis>) with <emphasis
                        role="bold">kew/RoutingReport.do</emphasis> (for example, <emphasis
                        role="bold">http://my.kuali.host/kuali/portal.jsp</emphasis> would become
                        <emphasis role="bold"
                        >http://my.kuali.host/kuali/kew/RoutingReport.do)</emphasis>. The following
                    page is displayed:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Report: Template Selection</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/select_rule_template.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Select a Rule Template</title>
                <para>The first thing to do is select the rule template to use for the test from the
                    drop-down list. When you select a template the page will update to show the
                    routing data that you need to enter to run the test:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Report: Template Selection, Detail</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/select_rule_template2.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Enter Routing Data</title>
                <para>The data entry fields for the routing data use the standard controls described
                    in the Standard Buttons on Lookup Screens document. Here is the example with the
                    routing data:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Report: Routing Data Entry</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/routing_data_entry.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The specific information you need to enter is specific to the rule template
                    you selected. Once you have entered the information, click the button to display
                    the report:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Report: Route Log View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/view_route_log_report.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Report Contents</title>
                <para>The upper section of the report (labeled “ID: 0”) contains the basic document
                    information fields as if this was an actual document; several fields are blank
                    since there is no actual document.</para>
                <para>The lower section of the report (labeled “Pending Action Requests”) contains
                    the routing that the document would be given. Clicking the button on any action
                    displays more detail of the action:</para>
                <figure><title>Routing Report: Route Log View, Pending Action Requests</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/pending_action_requests.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Rule Maintenance</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance Document Type Document</emphasis>
                screen is used for both editing existing Rules and for adding new Rules to Rice. </para>
            <figure>
                <title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_maintenance_document_type_document.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <note>
                <para>When Rice presents the <emphasis role="bold">Rule Maintenance Document Type
                        Document</emphasis> screen all of the tabs except the Notes and Attachments, Ad
                        Hoc Recipients and Route Log are expanded.</para>
            </note>   
            <sect3>
                <title>Document Layout</title>
                <para>The Rule Maintenance Document Type Document screen you see when creating a new
                    rule is composed of seven tabs:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Document Overview </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Rule </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Persons </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Groups </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Notes and Attachments </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Ad Hoc Recipients </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Route Log </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>The screen you see when you are editing an existing Rule includes an
                    additional tab called <emphasis role="bold">Roles</emphasis>.</para>
                <para>The Rule, Persons, Groups and Roles tabs are unique and are discussed in the
                    sections that follow. The remaining four tabs are commonly used throughout Rice
                    and are described in the Common Features and Functions section of the User
                    Guide.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Rule tab</title>
                <para>The Rule tab is presented differently depending on whether you are creating a
                    new Rule, or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when creating a new
                    Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Rule Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Rule Tab, Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_tab_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Rule Tab Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Document Type</entry>
                                    <entry>The Document Type defines the routing definition and
                                        other properties for a set of documents. Each document is an
                                        instance of a Document Type and conducts the same type of
                                        business transaction as other instances of that Document
                                        Type.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Rule Template</entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the Rule Template with which this rule is
                                        associated. A Rule Template serves as a pattern or design
                                        for the routing rules and is a mechanism for providing
                                        configuration information to rules. </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry><para>The unique Name of the routing Name you are creating
                                            or editing.</para>
                                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Note: </emphasis>It is not required that you enter a Name, but if you don’t the system will assign a unique value.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                    <entry>The general description for the rule selected.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>From Date</entry>
                                    <entry>The start date of the routing rule.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>To Date</entry>
                                    <entry>The expiration date of the routing rule.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Force Action</entry>
                                    <entry>Force Action is used to control workflow routing by
                                        making the rule actions mandatory. This is a yes or no flag.
                                        A check means yes, blank means no. </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Active</entry>
                                    <entry>A true/false flag to indicate if Routing Rule is active
                                        in Rice can be applied or not.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Persons tab</title>
                <para>The Persons tab is presented differently depending on whether you are creating
                    a new Rule, or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when creating a new
                    Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Person Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Person Tab, Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/person_tab_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Person Tab
                            Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Person</entry>
                                    <entry>An individual user who receives the document for the
                                        Action Requested.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Action Request</entry>
                                    <entry><para>The type of action this person can take.</para>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Complete</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Approve</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>FYI</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Priority</entry>
                                    <entry>The priority associated with the person in this rule.
                                        Lower values mean higher priorities, with 1 being the
                                        highest priority.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Groups tab</title>
                <para>The Groups tab is presented differently depending on whether you are creating
                    a new Rule, or editing/copying a Rule. The version you see when creating a new
                    Rule looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Groups Tab</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/groups_tab.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The version you see when editing or copying looks similar to this:</para>
                <figure><title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Groups Tab, Edit/Copy View</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="../images/groups_tab_copy.png"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
                <para>The top portion of this tab is used to add a new Group while the lower portion
                    is used to change existing values. </para>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Rule Maintenance Document Type Document: Groups Tab
                            Attributes</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Namespace</entry>
                                    <entry>The Namespace to which this Group will belong. A
                                        Namespace is a way to scope both Permissions and Entity
                                        Attributes. Each Namespace instance is one level of scoping
                                        and is one record in the system.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry>The unique name of the Group.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Action Request</entry>
                                    <entry><para>The type of action this Group is expected to take.</para>
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Acknowledge</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Complete</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>Approve</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>FYI</para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Priority</entry>
                                    <entry>The priority associated with the Group in this rule. One
                                        being the highest.</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Rule Template Lookup</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Rules Template Lookup</emphasis> function is available
                from any screen with the field lookup button next to the Rule Template field. Simply
                click on the button and you will go a screen that looks like this.</para>
            <figure><title>Rule Template Lookup</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_template_lookup.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Rule Template Lookup</emphasis> page will automatically
                provide a complete list of the rule templates. You can reduce the number of items
                returned by your search by entering values in the fields, or if you are not sure or
                familiar with the key word(s) for the search criteria, simply click on the search
                button. </para>
            <figure><title>Rule Template Lookup: Results Example</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_template_results.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Clicking on the <emphasis role="bold">Id</emphasis> field will take you to the
                    <emphasis role="bold">Rule Template Inquiry</emphasis> screen for that
                particular Rule Template.</para>
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Rule Template Lookup Attributes</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Return Value</entry>
                                <entry>This is a link which will copy the Rule Template information
                                    back to the screen which you originated from.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Id</entry>
                                <entry>A unique Id number for a specific rule template.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Name</entry>
                                <entry>The name of the rule template.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>A general description of the rule template.</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Delegation Rule Template</entry>
                                <entry>The delegate rule template selected.</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Rule Template Inquiry</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">Rule Template Inquiry</emphasis> screen provides
                specific information about one particular <emphasis role="bold">Rule
                    Template</emphasis>.</para>
            <figure><title>Rule Template Inquiry</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="../images/rule_template_inquiry.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Clicking the export button will export a copy of the complete Rule Template in XML
                format.</para>
        </sect2>        
    </sect1>
</chapter>
