<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2012 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="client_application" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
    <title>Creating a Client Application</title>
    <para>Developing a Rice application is essentially no different than other J2EE applications.
        Any tool that can be used for creating J2EE apps can be used for a Rice app. Essentially
        Rice is a set of libraries that are used with your project (like many other libraries a J2EE
        app includes) and configured for your needs.</para>
    
    <para>The essential tools for developing a project are documented in the next section.</para>
    
    <section>
        <title>Development Tools</title>

        <section>
            <title>IDE (Integrated Development Environment)</title>
            <para>This is the tool you will use to developer the source code and resources for your
                project. It can be a simple text editor if you want, however it is recommended to
                use one of the Java IDE tools available. Of these Eclipse, Intellij, and NetBeans
                are the most popular in today’s market. Any of these will be fine for developing a
                Rice project. However, as we will learn about next, Rice provides its own tooling to
                help getting started with Eclipse. Eclipse is chosen due to its high use and that it
                is a free open source tool. The latest release is ‘Indigo’ and can be downloaded
                here: </para>

            <para>
                <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/eclipse-ide-java-ee-developers/indigosr1"
                    >http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/eclipse-ide-java-ee-developers/indigosr1</link>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Database</title>
            <para>Rice applications can use a MySql or Oracle database for persisting
                application data. Rice itself will use the database for supporting the various Rice modules
                (workflow, identity management, and so on). With each Rice distribution datasets are
                provided that can be used to create the initial database schema. You can choose to load the
                ‘bootstrap’ dataset, which provides the baseline data needed to run Rice, or the ‘demo’
                dataset which adds additional demo data (such as example KIM data and workflow doc types). 
                Although it is possible to provide a shared database for development, it is recommended for
                productivity reasons for each developer to have a local database installed. Both MySql and
                Oracle provide freely available databases for development. Currently Rice has been tested
                with the following versions:</para>
            
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">Oracle</emphasis>
                            <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Oracle Database 10g</para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Oracle Database 11g</para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Oracle Express Edition (XE)</para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist></para>
                        <para>Use the Oracle JDBC Driver to connect to these databases.</para>
                        <para>Ensure that the Oracle database you intend to use encodes character data in a UTF
                            variant by default. For Oracle XE, this entails downloading the "Universal" flavor
                            of the binary, which uses AL32UTF8.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">MySQL</emphasis><itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>MySQL 5.1.+</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                        <para>Use the MySQL Connector/J (5.1.+) to connect to MySQL databases.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            
            <para>Note for our chosen database we must also download the corresponding database driver. This
                is a jar file we will need to make available to our web container for connecting to the
                database.</para>
            
            <para>These supported databases can be downloaded with the following URLs.</para>
            
            <para>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>Locations for Database Software</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="4.11*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Software</entry>
                                <entry>Download Location</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Oracle Standard and Enterprise Editions </entry>
                                <entry><link
                                    xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html"
                                    >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/enterprise-edition/downloads/index.html</link></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Oracle Express Edition</entry>
                                <entry><link
                                    xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/express-edition/downloads/index.html"
                                    >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/express-edition/downloads/index.html</link></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Oracle JDBC DB Driver</entry>
                                <entry><link
                                    xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/features/jdbc/index-091264.html"
                                    >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/database/features/jdbc/index-091264.html</link></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>MySQL </entry>
                                <entry><link xlink:href="http://www.mysql.com/downloads/"
                                    >http://www.mysql.com/downloads/</link></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>MySQL Connector/J JDBC Driver</entry>
                                <entry><link xlink:href="http://www.mysql.com/products/connector/j/"
                                    >http://www.mysql.com/products/connector/j/</link></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>      
            </para>
            
            <para>Note for working with a MySql database the MySql Workbench (available for free
                download) is very useful and can save time for those new to MySql.  
            </para>
            
            <para>Once the database provider is installed, we can then load one of the provided datasets using the
                Kuali ImpEx tool. The ImpEx tool is a Kuali-developed application which is based on Apache
                Torque. It reads in database structure and data from XML files in a platform independent way
                and then creates the resulting database in either Oracle or MySQL. To use this tool we
                simply provide configuration about the location of the source dataset, along with
                connectivity information for our target database. This is done by creating a properties file
                named ‘impex-build.properties’ in the user home directory. Once the configuration is
                complete, we can invoke the tool using ant or maven and our database will be
                created.</para>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>JDK</title>
            <para>In order to support compilation of the application source
                code a JDK must be installed (Note this must be the JDK and not a Java Runtime Environment –
                JRE). Rice requires a JDK version of 1.6.x. Additionally, Rice has only been tested with the
                Sun JDK implementation. Therefore use of other implementations such as OpenJDK may have
                problems.</para>
            
            <para>For machines running Windows, JDK 6 can be downloaded at the
                following URL:</para>
            
            <para>
                <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html"
                    >http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index.html</link>
            </para>
            
            <para>If you are on a Mac, then Java 6 should already be installed if you are up to date with
            the latest updates from Apple.</para>
            
            <para>You will also want to set up your JAVA_HOME environment variable to point to the
                installation directory of your JDK. In both Windows and Mac environments, the java
                executable program should already be on your path. But if it is not, you will want to
                include JAVA_HOME/bin in your PATH environment variable.</para>
            
            <para>In order to verify that your JDK has been installed successfully, open a command prompt
            and type the following: </para>
            
            <programlisting>java -version</programlisting>
            <para>You should see output similar to the following:</para>
            <programlisting>java version "1.6.0_26"
Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.6.0_26-b03-383-11A511)
Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 20.1-b02-383, mixed mode)</programlisting>
            <para>If you receive an error indicating that the "java" command could not be found,
                please ensure that the java command is on your machine's <emphasis role="bold"
                    >PATH</emphasis> environment variable.</para>
        </section> 
        
        <section>
            <title>Maven</title>
            <para>Maven is the primary build tool used by the Kuali Rice project. Maven is
                based on a project object model (POM) that defines various standards and conventions
                surrounding the organization of a project. This facilitates a set of standard build
                goals and lifecycle phases (such as compile, test, package, etc.). Maven is
                particularly helpful in terms of dependency management. When building a Rice
                application using Maven, all of the dependent libraries will be pulled in
                automatically.</para>
            
            <para>It is not a required for Rice enabled applications to be Maven projects. Again, Rice
                is essentially a set of jars that can be used with an application. However using Maven
                simplifies the setup process greatly. For example applications not using Rice must pull
                in and manage all of the third party libraries that are needed by Rice. That has an impact
                not only on initial project setup, but also each time that application is upgraded to
                a new Rice version.</para>
            
            <para>To download version 3 of Maven, use the following link:</para>
            
            <para><link xlink:href="http://maven.apache.org/download.html"
                >http://maven.apache.org/download.html</link></para>
            
            <para>You will want to set your M2_HOME environment variable to point to the location
                where you unzipped Maven. You will additionally want to include M2_HOME/bin in your
                PATH environment variable so that maven can be executed from the command line without having
                to specify the full path.</para>
            
            <para>In order to verify that Maven has been installed successfully and is available on
                the path, open a command prompt and type the following:</para>
            <programlisting>mvn -version</programlisting>
            <para>You should see output like the following:</para>
            <programlisting>Apache Maven 3.0.3 (r1075438; 2011-02-28 10:31:09-0700)
Maven home: /usr/local/maven
Java version: 1.6.0_26, vendor: Apple Inc.
Java home: /System/Library/Java/JavaVirtualMachines/1.6.0.jdk/Contents/Home
Default locale: en_US, platform encoding: MacRoman
OS name: "mac os x", version: "10.7.2", arch: "x86_64", family: "mac"</programlisting>
            <para>If you receive an error indicating hat the "mvn" command could not be found,
                please ensure that the directory that includes the mvn executable (<emphasis
                    role="bold">M2_HOME/bin</emphasis>) is on your machine's <emphasis role="bold"
                        >PATH</emphasis> environment variable.</para>
            
        </section>    
        
        <section>
            <title>Servlet Container</title>
            
            <para>In order to run our Rice application we need have a servlet
                container. The servlet container serves the web requests for a J2EE application. There
                are many containers available for use, but Tomcat is most commonly used. Kuali Rice
                2.0 supports the following Tomcat version:</para>
            
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Tomcat 6 (Servlet API 2.5, JSP 2.1) </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Tomcat 7 (Servlet API 3.0, JSP 2.2) </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            
            <para>For downloading and install instructions visit the Apache Tomcat site:</para>
            <para><link xlink:href="http://tomcat.apache.org/">http://tomcat.apache.org/</link></para>
            
            <para>For development purposes you can also choose to use an embedded application
                container such as Jetty. The Rice project provides a sample Jetty Server that can be used
                for your project. The next section will cover this in more detail.</para>
            
        </section>
    </section> 
    
    <section><title>New Project Setup</title>
        
         <para>Now let’s look at creating a new Rice enabled
            project. To do this, we will use a tool from the Rice project that performs most of the
            initial bootstrapping. The tool is included within the Rice project therefore we need to
            start by downloading the Rice 2.0 release. The Rice distribution can be downloaded
            at:</para>
        <para>
            <link xlink:href="http://kuali.org/download"> http://kuali.org/download </link>
        </para>
        
        <para>Or the project may be checked out through Subversion with the following repository
        location:</para>
        
        <para>
            <link xlink:href="https://svn.kuali.org/repos/rice">
                https://svn.kuali.org/repos/rice</link>
        </para>
        
        <para>Note the full project must be checked out, not just the tool. The tool creates the initial artifacts
            by copying from the Rice working copy.</para>
        
        <para>The Rice project contents should be
            placed into a folder in the local file system. A standard practice is to create a top
            level directory named ‘java’, followed by a ‘projects’ directory, and then a directory
            named ‘rice’ that contains the actual project (‘/java/projects/rice’).</para>
        
        <para>The particular tool we will be using was written in Groovy, therefore we need to download
        the Groovy runtime. This can be downloaded at the following URL:</para>
        
        <para>
            <link xlink:href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/Download">
                http://groovy.codehaus.org/Download </link>
        </para> 
        
        <para>Install instructions are also available on the above site. For users of
            Windows, a Windows-Installer can be downloaded which will install Groovy and perform any
            necessary configuration (including add groovy to your path).</para>
        
        <para>Once groovy is installed we are ready to run the create project script. Start up a console (on Windows
            can use the PowerShell) and change into the directory that contains the Rice project (eg
            ‘/java/projects/rice’). From the root project folder, change into the scripts folder.
            This folder should contain a file named ‘createproject.groovy’.</para>
        
        <para>There are a few options supported by the create project script, but let’s start with the most basic
            way of running. The command we will give is:</para>
        
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name PROJECT_NAME</programlisting>
        
        <para>First we are invoking the groovy executable (this assumes
            groovy is on your path, if not the full path to the groovy executable needs to be
            specified). Groovy then expects the name of the script we want to run, which is
            ‘creatproject.groovy’. Next we specify the one required argument for the create project
            script which is the name for the project we want to create. Assuming we want to create a
            new project named ‘MyRiceApp’, the command would be the following:</para>
        
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name MyRiceApp</programlisting>
        
        <para>After typing the command hit enter to
        start the script. You should then see a prompt as follows:\</para>
        
        <programlisting> ================================================================== 
                                    WARNING 
         ================================================================== 
        This program will delete the following directory and replace it 
         with a new project: 
           /java/projects/MyRiceApp 
        It will also create or replace the
            following files in USER_HOME: 
            1) C:\Users\jkneal.ADS/kuali/main/dev/MyRiceApp-config.xml 
             2) C:\Users\jkneal.ADS/kuali/main/dev/rice.keystore   
         If this is not what you want, please supply more information: 
             usage: groovy createproject -name PROJECT_NAME [-pdir PROJECT_DIR] [-rdir
            RICE_DIR] [-mdir MAVEN_HOME]    
                Do you want to continue (yes/no)? </programlisting>
        
        <para>Type ‘yes’ and then enter to resume the program. You will then see logging output from
            the script about various files being created, the maven build, and finally should see
            printed instructions and how to complete the project setup. </para>
       
        <para>Notice we did not tell the script where to put our new project nor where to find the
            Rice project. This is because the script defaults to the project location of
            ‘/java/projects’. If we want our project to be generated in a different location, we can
            do so by passing the directory path with the ‘-pdir’ argument:</para>
            
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name MyRiceApp –pdir /home/myapps</programlisting>
        
        <para>The project directory given will be the parent for the project folder. The script will
        create another folder within this with the same name as the given project name.</para>
        
        <para>Similarly if our source Rice project is in another directory, we can specify that
        using the ‘-rdir’ argument:</para>
        
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name MyRiceApp –rdir /home/myapps/rice</programlisting>
            
        <para>Unlike this project directory argument, this does specify the full path to the
        project (nothing will be appended).</para>
        
        <para>Finally the create project script gives us a couple more options for the project
            generation. We can include the Rice sampleapp in our project by passing the –sampleapp
            flag:</para>
        
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name MyRiceApp –sampleapp</programlisting>
        
        <para>Having the various examples of the sampleapp can be very useful in particular if doing
        development with the KRAD framework.</para>
        
        <para>Lastly, we can have a project generated that is setup to go against a standalone Rice
        instance. To do this we pass the –standalone flag:</para>
        
        <programlisting>groovy createproject.groovy -name MyRiceApp –standalone</programlisting>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Project Structure and Configuration Files</title>
        <para>The result of running the create project script is a new maven based Rice client
            project. This includes the directory structures for building out your application, along
            with the necessary configuration files. Let’s start by looking the directories that were
            created. </para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Project Root (eg ‘/java/projects/myapp’) – This is the root folder that was created to
                    hold all the project contents. Within this folder you will find three sub-folders, a
                    ‘.classpath’, ‘.project’, ‘instructions.txt’, and ‘pom.xml’ file.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>.settings – This folder contains settings configuration for the Eclipse IDE</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>src – This folder is for the application source files and resources. Within this
                    folder is the standard maven directory breakdown:
                    
                  <itemizedlist>
                      <listitem><para>src/main/java – Contains Java source code</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para>src/main/resources – Contains resource files (XML and other resources)</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para>src/main/webapp – Contains the application web content (JSP, tags, images,
                          CSS, Script)</para></listitem>
                  </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem><para>target – This folder holds the build output such as generated classes and wars.</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>Along with the directories several files are created. These are as follows:</para>
        
        <table frame="none">
            <title>Generated Files</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.56*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>File</entry>
                        <entry>Description</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>.classpath</entry>
                        <entry>Eclipse file for managing the application classpath</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>.project</entry>
                        <entry>Eclipse project file</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>pom.xml</entry>
                        <entry>Maven Project File</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>{project}-RiceDataSourceSpringBeans.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Spring XML file containing Rice datasource configurations</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>{project}-RiceJTASpringBeans.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Spring XML file containing JTA transaction configuration</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>{project}-RiceSpringBeans.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Spring XML file containing the Rice module Configurers</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>SpringBeans.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Spring XML file for Application beans</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>{project}-SampleAppModuleBeans.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Spring XML file for Sample App beans (only created if –sampleapp option was given)</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>OJB-repository-sampleapp.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>OJB configuration file for the Sample App (only created if –sampleapp option was given)</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>META-INF/{project}-config.xml*</entry>
                        <entry>Default Rice configuration properties</entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>src/main/webapp/WEB-INF/web.xml</entry>
                        <entry>Standard web deployment descriptor for J2EE applications</entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        
        <note><para>All of these files are located within the src/main/resources directory </para></note>
        <para>In addition to the files created within the project, two files are created in the
            ‘{user home}/kuali/main/dev’ folder. These include:</para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>{project}-config.xml – Configuration file for application. This is where the settings
                for the database and other configurations are given.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>rice.keystore – Provides a secure key for consuming secured services running on a Rice
                server</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>  
              
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Configuring Your Rice Application</title>
        <para>Next we need to provide some configuration for our application that is custom to our
            environment (for example database connectivity). We can do this by modifying the
            properties available in {project}-config.xml (located in the /kuali/main/dev folder in
            user home).</para>
        <para>Although there are many configuration properties available for customization, the
        following are required for getting started:</para>
        
        <table frame="none">
            <title>Configuration Parameters</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.56*"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry>Parameter</entry>
                        <entry>Description</entry>
                        <entry>Example</entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.url</entry>
                        <entry>JDBC URL of database to connect to</entry>
                        <entry>jdbc:oracle:thin:@localhost:1521:XE
                            jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/kuldemo
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.username</entry>
                        <entry>User name for connecting to the server database</entry>
                        <entry>rice
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.password</entry>
                        <entry>Password for connecting to the server database</entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.ojb.platform</entry>
                        <entry>Name of OJB platform to use for the database</entry>
                        <entry>Oracle9i or MySQL
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.platform</entry>
                        <entry>Rice platform implementation for the database</entry>
                        <entry>org.kuali.rice.core.database.platform.OraclePlatform
                            org.kuali.rice.core.database.platform.MySQLPlatform                           
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>datasource.driver.name</entry>
                        <entry>JDBC driver for the database</entry>
                        <entry>oracle.jdbc.driver.OracleDriver
                            com.mysql.jdbc.Driver                       
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
               
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Importing into Eclipse</title>
        
        <para>Now we have our project setup and are ready to begin development. Note at this point
            the application is completely runnable. We could do a maven deploy, copy the generated
            war to our tomcat server, and start up the application. However we are going to first
            import our project to Eclipse so that we will be ready to develop further application
            code.</para>
        
        <para>Navigate to the Eclipse installation directory. There you should find an executable
            named ‘eclipse.exe’. Once this file is found double click to start the IDE. When Eclipse
            starts up for the first time it will ask you to choose a workspace. This is a directory
            that Eclipse place newly created projects and will also read current projects from. A
            standard within the community is to use ‘/java/projects’ for your working space. Note
            you can select the checkbox to use the directory as your default and Eclipse will not
            prompt on the next startup.</para>
        
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Eclipse Memory:</emphasis> It is generally needed and
            recommended to allocate additional JVM memory for the Eclipse runtime. This can be done
            by opening up the file named ‘eclipse.ini’ that exists in the root installation
            directory. At the end of the file you specify VM arguments as follows:</para>
        <programlisting>-vmargs
-Xms128m
-Xmx1024m
-XX:MaxPermSize=512m</programlisting>
       
        <para>The amount of memory allocated depends on the host machine. The above settings are for
            a machine with 4g of memory.</para>
     
     
        <para>When working with Eclipse for the first time, there are additional plugins you
                will likely want to get. None of these are required by Rice and depend on your
                institutional development environment and how you plan to create your project.
                However, most projects today use SVN or GIT for source code control. Therefore an
                additional Eclipse plugin is needed for communicating with the repository. Also if
                you have chosen to use Maven (or used the create project script) the Eclipse Maven
                plugin will be very useful as well.</para>
    
         <para>To bring a new project into eclipse, select the File-Import menu
         option. This should bring up a dialog as show in next figure.</para>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Eclipse Import</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                        fileref="../images/eclipse_import_existing_projects.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
            
         <para>For the import source select ‘Existing Projects info Workspace’. This should
         bring up a dialog that looks like the following figure. </para>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Eclipse Import Project Directory</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                        fileref="../images/eclipse_import_projects_directory.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <para>Here click the ‘Browse’ button to locate the directory for the project. After
            selecting the project location click the ‘Finish’ button. Eclipse will then import the
            project contents and you are ready to begin coding!</para>
        
    
    </section>

</chapter>
