<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<!--

    Copyright 2005-2012 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<chapter xml:id="TRG_KRAD" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>KRAD</title>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Overview</title>
        <para>New for Rice 2.0, the Kuali Rapid Application Development (KRAD) framework eases the
            development of enterprise web applications by providing reusable solutions and tooling
            that enable developers to build in a rapid and agile fashion.   KRAD is a complete
            framework for web developers that provides infrastructure in all the major areas of an
            application (client, business, and data), and integrates with other modules of the Rice
            middleware project.</para>
        <para>KRAD expands the Kuali development platform and will eventually replace the Kuali
            Nervous System (KNS).  KRAD supports the KNS document types - Lookups, Inquiries, and
            Maintenance pages - while it also provides more flexibility in user interface layouts,
            for example, beyond the "vertical" tab section and collection layouts typical of
            KNS-based applications.  In addition, KRAD eliminates the need for a transaction
            document type, as maintenance documents can now handle full transactional
            interactions.</para>
        <para>KRAD differs from KNS in some key ways:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The KNS look-and-feel was targetted at administrative users, KRAD enables rich
                    web applications targetted at a wide range of user types.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>KNS has little built-in rich user interface support whereas KRAD includes
                    this.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>KNS is Struts 1.x based whereas KRAD is Spring-MVC based.  </para>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">KRAD uses the following:</emphasis></para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Spring Beans and Expression Language </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Apache Tiles as the templating engine</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Fluid Skinning System for CSS</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>jQuery as the javascript library, including jQuery UI widgets</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>And other plugins providing functionality, such as AJAX</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <section>
            <title>Key KRAD Features</title>
            <para>Built upon a rich JQuery library of standards and Fluid Skinning System's (FSS)
                set of cascading style sheets, KRAD provides a set of rich user Interface
                components, such as the following.  Note that jQuery themes are widget-oriented,
                while the FSS provides support for whole pages and applications, so they are
                compatible with each other.</para>
            <para>The key KRAD User Interface Framework (UIF) components include, but are not
                limited to, the following:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Navigation objects:  Left menu and Horizontal tabs navigation</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Layout managers:  Grid, Box, Table and Stacked</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Widgets:  Light-box, Disclosure, Breadcrumb,  Date picker, Growl,
                            Direct inquiry, Inquiry,  QuickFinder, RichTable, Suggest, Tabs,
                            Tree</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Controls: Checkbox, Checkbox group, File, KIM Group, Hidden, Select,
                            TextArea, Text, User</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Containers: Group, Link group, Navigation group, Tab group, Tree
                            group</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Fields:  Input field, Field Group, Action, Ajax Action, Blank, Data,
                            Errors, Generic, Header, iFrame, Image, Label, Link, Lookup Input,
                            Message </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>View Types: Lookup, Inquiry, Maintenance, Transactional   </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>General Features:  Constraints (simple, valid characters, case, must
                            occurs, dependency, custom), Watermarks, Help summary &amp; description,
                            Messages (constraint, instructional, required, error, informational,
                            warning), Validation (client-side, dirty fields validation, exception
                            handling - incident page), Remote fields, Progressive Disclosure,  Audo
                            Code-name translation (auto-completion), Dialogs (questions and
                            prompts), Focus and anchoring handling, Tabbing order, Field queries,
                            Information properties, Hidden properties, Default Values, Disabled,
                            Alternate and Additional Display Properties,  Read-Only fields request
                            override, Attribute security and masking, Add/Delete line handling, Form
                            Edit Modes, Property editors, Property replacers, Component refresh,
                            Component Modifiers, Collection filters, Show/Hide inactive, EL Language
                            for XML Config, Support for all JS events, Integration with KIM and
                            KEW.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>For example, see the information below on KRAD's Input field, and how this field
                can be grouped with others of the constructs listed above to make for a richer UI
                experience than what was possible in KNS.</para>
            <para>An Input field enables user input. This means that this "grouped" field control
                will display an entry field for user input, and can optionally include instructions,
                a watermark, constraint text, a lookup widget, inquiry widget, and/or help widget,
                and includes a place for error messages associated with the field to appear. This
                could be considered the most complex of all fields, and additional information on
                this field can be found in the Developers' Guide.</para>
            <para>
                <figure>
                    <title>Input Field - Grouped</title>
                    <mediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata 
                                fileref="../images/KRAD-InputField2.png" align="left" scalefit="1" contentwidth="640"/>
                        </imageobject>
                    </mediaobject>
                </figure>
            </para>
            <para>The information below provides additional conceptual and relational information on
                the KRAD architecture, classes and user interface patterns that are supported
                "out-of-the-box.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Conceptual view</title>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>KRAD Conceptual View</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD-classes2.png" align="left" scalefit="1"/>
                </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>    
        </para>
        <para>For additional high-level views of information on the layout managers and fields, see
            the KRAD Users' Guide.  </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Relational View</title>
        <para>
            <figure>
                <title>KRAD Relational View</title> 
                <mediaobject>
                  <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="../images/KRAD-Relational-View.png"/>
                  </imageobject>
               </mediaobject>
            </figure>
         </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Data Dictionary</title>
        <para>(Need direction on what of the KNS information should be copied here and what other
            new information should be included.)  </para>
        <para>KRAD enhancements to the Data Dictionary include, but are not limited to, the
            following:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Simple Constraints, Min/Max</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Valid Characters Constraints</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Dependency Constraints</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Lookup Constraints</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Conditional Logic Constraints </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Occurrences Constraints - Collection size constraints</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Constraints on the client side</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Changing Error Messages</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Custom Constraints </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>In the earliest versions of the Kuali Nervous System, it was recognized that forcing
            developers to write Java-based rules to check if a required field was filled in or if it
            matched a date pattern was a hefty load of work that easily could be transferred to the
            data dictionary. </para>
        <para>Every AttributeDefinition defined for a property of a data object had the ability to
            be paired with a validation. For instance, let's take a generic date field from KFS's
            org/kuali/kfs/sys/businessobject/datadictionary/GenericAttributes.xml file.</para>
        <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Code snippet example follows:
                </emphasis></emphasis></para>
        <para>
            <programlisting>
1.  &lt;bean id="GenericAttributes-genericDate" parent="GenericAttributes-genericDate-parentBean"/>
2.  &lt;bean id="GenericAttributes-genericDate-parentBean" abstract="true" parent="AttributeDefinition">
3.    &lt;property name="name" value="genericDate"/>
4.    &lt;property name="forceUppercase" value="false"/>
5.    &lt;property name="label" value="Generic Date Style Attribute"/>
6.    &lt;property name="shortLabel" value="GenericDate"/>
7.    &lt;property name="maxLength" value="22"/>
8.    &lt;property name="validationPattern" ref="DateValidation"/>
9.    &lt;property name="control" ref="DateControl" />
10.   &lt;property name="formatterClass" value="org.kuali.rice.kns.web.format.DateFormatter"/>
11. &lt;/bean> 
           </programlisting>
        </para>
        <para>It's a simple enough example, but lines 7 and 8 pack quite a bit of power.  Together,
            they limit the length of the field to a size which can fit in the database (evidently
            twenty-two characters) and they add the DateValidation, which requires that any user
            input fits a certain pattern defined as a regular expression. Two lines of
            configuration, and the developer gets a fair amount of error checking. </para>
        <para>That's wonderful, of course, but it has limits.  For example, there's no way to only
            run constraints based on the values present in other attributes. There wasn't a general
            way to enforce a data type for a user input value. There wasn't a way to say, for
            instance, that one or another field was required - either a field was required or it
            wasn't. </para>
        <para>Such logic, not that much more complex, all required a Java-based rules solution. Much
            more complex logic is available than ever before. Not only that, but it can be enabled
            to work on the client side via JavaScript as well. </para>
        <para>Finally, for even more flexibility, the processors which act on the constraints have
            been pulled out into injectable classes - meaning that applications can override the
            logic for a constraint if needed. Furthermore, constraints need not act only on
            AttributeDefinitions; new interfaces have been developed which allow any configuration
            class to participate in being validated. Obviously, there's a lot of functionality to
            cover - from the classic constraints which continue on in the framework to the powerful
            constraints that the Kuali Student team contributed to KRAD. </para>
        <para>The information below includes an overview of the specific "built-in" KRAD constraints
            available to developers. We'll also cover the architecture of the constraint framework,
            with a special emphasis on how constraint logic may be overridden, how new constraints
            would be constructed, and how non-attributes could have Constraint logic built for
            them.</para>
        <para>Information on each of the KRAD-packaged constraints is below, followed by a look at
            the constraint architecture itself. </para>
        <section>
            <title>Simple Constraints, Min / Max</title>
            <para>As is covered in more detail in the Constraint Architecture section that follows
                this this documentation of the constraints packaged with KRAD, every constraint in
                KRAD implements the <emphasis role="italic"
                    >org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.Constraint</emphasis>
                interface. This interface is a simple marker interface. Children of that interface
                tend to define the data they would need from the configuration to figure out if the
                value put into the attribute is valid or not. </para>
            <para>For instance, in the <emphasis role="italic"
                    >GenericAttributes-genericDate</emphasis> example in the introduction section
                above, the maxLength property is set to 22. One would expect a length-based
                constraint to require a getMaxLength() method which could then be fed to the
                Constraint to find the maximum length. </para>
            <para>org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.SimpleConstraint defines
                what we might call a "nervous system classic" constraint. It is built from normal
                fields on AttributeDefinition - required; maxLength and minLength (the latter has
                been added as part of KRAD); exclusiveMin and exclusiveMax; and finally, minOccurs
                and maxOccurs, which will be covered in more detail below. </para>
            <para>The required constraint, of course, means that some value must be set for the
                attribute. The maxLength and minLength attributes typically apply to String data,
                which must be a certain size. Likewise, exclusiveMin and exclusiveMax apply to
                numeric data which must fit within some set range.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Valid Characters Constraints</title>
            <para>Another hold over from the Kuali Nervous System constraints,
                ValidCharactersConstraint exists to make sure that a String value matches against a
                regular expression. For instance, let's say that a KRAD application requires that
                all phone numbers must be in the form of (###) ###-#### (Evidently, the attribute
                does not yet accept international numbers...but as developers, we must rest assured
                that's coming, and is the requirement.) </para>
            <para>In the data dictionary for that attribute, the following could be set. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Code snippet example
            follows:</emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <para>
            <programlisting>1.  &lt;bean id="DataObject-phoneNumber" parent="AttributeDefinition">
2.    &lt;property name="name" value="phoneNumber" />
3.    &lt;property name="validCharactersConstraint">
4.      &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.ValidCharactersConstraint">
5.        &lt;property name="value" value="\(\d{3}\) \d{3}-\d{4}" />
6.      &lt;/bean>
7.    &lt;/property>
8.  &lt;/bean>            </programlisting>
            </para>
                
            <para>In lines 3 through 7, we set the validCharactersConstraint property on the
                AttributeDefinition, handing the bean we just created a regex which should match the
                phone number pattern which the requirements say all phone numbers should match. </para>
            <para>This regex is passed in as the value property to the ValidCharactersConstraint
                bean. A number of ValidCharacterConstraints are defined in <emphasis role="italic"
                    >org/kuali/rice/kns/bo/datadictionary/DataDictionaryBaseTypes.xml</emphasis>.
                Among those are "UrlPatternConstraint", "DatePatternConstraint",
                "CreditcardPatternConstraint", "NonWhitespacePatternConstraint",
                "IntegerPatternConstraint", "PhoneUSPatternConstraint", and "TimePatternConstraint",
                as a mere sampling. As of the time of this writing, the constraints only worked for
                javascript side validation. However, work was being done to build server side
                equivalencies of all of these patterns. </para>
            <para>Finally, note that the ValidCharactersConstraint has a second property, "jsValue".
                In most cases, Java's regular expression engine (ValidCharactersConstraint uses the
                built-in regular expression engine) will accept the same expressions as the
                JavaScript engine. That's good, because the same regular expression can be passed to
                the client and handled client side, as will be covered in more detail soon. </para>
            <para>The best idea is to keep validation regular expressions to the use of broadly
                supported features (outside of POSIX, which Java supports but which most JavaScript
                engines do not), and keep on eye on engine comparison pages such as
                http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_regular_expression_engines. The KRAD team
                is attempting to avoid differences, though, and create a single pattern for both
                JavaScript and Java. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Dependency Constraints</title>
            <para>Dependency constraints are used to define a set of PrerequisiteConstraint
                dependencies on an attribute. A PreRequisiteConstraint is simply used to denote that
                some other attribute be required. If the attribute is non-empty and has dependency
                constraints, each pre-requisite constraint attribute must also be non-empty. Note
                the prerequisite constraint is also used in the MustOccurConstraint. Unlike the
                MustOccurConstraint which requires that a minimum or maximum number of prerequisite
                constraints be satisfied, a dependency constraint requires that all pre-requisite
                constraints be satisfied. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">A code snippet example
                        follows:</emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <para>
                <programlisting>1.  &lt;bean id="DataObject-phoneNumber" parent="AttributeDefinition"&gt;
2.    &lt;property name="name" value="phoneNumber"/&gt;
3.    &lt;property name="dependencyConstraints"&gt;
4.      &lt;list&gt;
5.        &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint" p:attributePath="phoneExtension" /&gt;
6.      &lt;/list&gt;
7.    &lt;/property&gt;
8.  &lt;/bean&gt;</programlisting>
            </para>
        
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Lookup Constraints</title>
            <para>These are constraints on values returned from lookups into an attribute. As of the
                time of this writing, they're still in process of implementation. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Conditional Logic Constraints</title>
            <para>All of the constraints so far covered are static, in a fashion. Once declared,
                they will apply to their attributes no matter what. However, let's say that a
                constraint should only be tested when the attribute has a certain value. How could
                the constraint be turned off if that value isn't present and only be applied if the
                attribute has the given value? </para>
            <para>The final constraint to look at is <emphasis role="italic"
                    >org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.CaseConstraint</emphasis>,
                which will turn on and off child constraints if attributes match certain values. The
                classic example of using this is in an international address form. If the country
                code is the United States, then the state code should be filled in as well. If the
                country code is for Canada or Turkey, a province should be filled in. That would be
                done via a configuration like this.</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">A code snippet example
                        follows:</emphasis></emphasis>
            </para>
            <programlisting> 1. &lt;bean id="DataObject-countryCode" parent="AttributeDefinition">
 2.   &lt;property name="name" value="countryCode"/>
 3.   &lt;property name="caseConstraint">
 4.     &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.CaseConstraint">
 5.       &lt;property name="whenConstraint">
 6.         &lt;list>
 7.           &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.WhenConstraint">
 8.             &lt;property name="values">
 9.               &lt;list>
10.                 &lt;value>US&lt;/value>
11.               &lt;/list>
12.             &lt;/property>
13.             &lt;property name="constraint">
14.               &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint"p:attributePath="state" />
15.             &lt;/property>
16.           &lt;/bean>
17.           &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.WhenConstraint">
18.             &lt;property name="values">
19.               &lt;list>
20.                 &lt;value>CA&lt;/value>
21.                 &lt;value>TR&lt;/value>
22.               &lt;/list>
23.             &lt;/property>
24.             &lt;property name="constraint">
25.               &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint"p:attributePath="province"/>
26.             &lt;/property>
27.           &lt;/bean>
28.         &lt;/list>
29.       &lt;/property>
30.     &lt;/bean>
31.   &lt;/property>
32. &lt;/bean> </programlisting> 
            <para>Obviously, for such a powerful constraint, configuration becomes a bit more
                complex. A <emphasis role="italic">CaseConstraint</emphasis> has a List of <emphasis
                    role="italic">WhenConstraints</emphasis>. <emphasis role="italic"
                    >WhenConstraints</emphasis> match values to constraints that should be run when
                the attribute's value matches the <emphasis role="italic"
                >WhenConstraint</emphasis>'s values. Here, values are hard coded (lines 8 through 12
                and lines 18 through 23) but they need not be. If the values are in other
                attributes, a List of valuePaths can be specified. </para>
            <para>A <emphasis role="italic">WhenConstraint</emphasis> also has one child constraint
                to match. In both of the <emphasis role="italic">WhenConstraints</emphasis> above, a
                    <emphasis role="italic">PrerequisiteConstraint</emphasis> is used to make sure
                that another attribute - either state or province - is non-empty (lines 14 and 25).
                Any Constraint could be used as the child of the <emphasis role="italic"
                    >WhenConstraint</emphasis> - a SimpleConstraint, another CaseConstraint, and so
                on. The ability to turn on and off constraints such can lead to very powerful
                validations being built directly in the DataDictionary. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Ocurrences Constraints</title>
            <para>An occurrence constraint states that for a given attribute to be valid, a certain
                number of prerequisite conditions must be matched. A prerequisite condition simply
                means that another attribute with a specified attribute path is non-empty (so
                Strings must have some text in them; Collections must have at least one member; or
                the attribute must otherwise not be null). These constraints thus handle situations
                where one or more of a number of fields are required. </para>
            <para>An occurrence constraint is specified via the MustOccurConstraint constraint.
                Let's say that an application requires either a phone number, an e-mail address, or
                a time for showing up be specified as contact information. The following example
                sets up that validation in the data dictionary, adding the error to the phone number
                attribute (though the same constraint could be copied to the other attributes just
                as easily).</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">A code snippet example follows:
                    </emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <programlisting>1.   &lt;bean id="DataObject-phoneNumber" parent="DataObjectEntry">
2.     &lt;property name="objectClass" value="edu.sampleu.contact.ContactInformation" />
3.     &lt;property name="mustOccurConstraints">
4.       &lt;list>
5.         &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.MustOccurConstraint">
6.           &lt;property name="min" value="1" />
7.           &lt;property name="max" value="3"/>
8.           &lt;property name="prerequisiteConstraints">
9.             &lt;list>
10.              &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint"p:attributePath="phoneNumber"/>
11.              &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint"p:attributePath="emailAddress"/>
12.              &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint"p:attributePath="showUpTime"/>
13.            &lt;/list>
14.          &lt;/property>
15.        &lt;/bean>
16.      &lt;/list>
17.    &lt;/property>
18.  &lt;/bean>            </programlisting> 
            <para>Lines 1 and 2 surprising show that this constraint has been set at the
                DataObjectEntry level, not that of the AttributeDefinition. While
                MustOccurConstraints can be set in pretty much the same way on AttributeDefinitions,
                since several attributes are involved, it makes more sense to have the validation at
                a higher level. At the time of this writing, MustOccurConstraint is the only
                validation which can be set at the DataObjectLevel. </para>
            <para>The min and max properties of lines 6 and 7 tell the constraint how many of the
                following properties must be present and the maximum number of filled in properties
                we expect. Here, the min is 1 - so at least one of the properties must be filled in
                - and the max is 3, so if all three are filled in, the validation will still work
                fine. If there was a desire to only have one attribute filled in, the max could have
                been set to 1. </para>
            <para>The MustOccurConstraint has a list of prerequisiteConstraints - lines 8 through 14
                - which describe which attributes are grouped by this constraint. </para>
            <para>A MustOccurConstraint can also have a list of child MustOccurConstraints. Why
                would such a thing be desirable? Because it provides a way to set up nested
                validations. Let's say that, instead of specifying a show up time, we had an address
                which needed to be filled in. If that was the case, we'd need every field of the
                address - street, city, state, and zip filled in - for the constraint to pass. In
                that case, we would have left min and max at 1 and 3 respectively; but instead of
                line 12, we would have specified a value for the property mustOccurConstraints at
                line 15, and added a list of constraints asking for all the address attributes to be
                filled in. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Collection Size Constraints</title>
            <para>Another common rule situation is when a collection is the child of a data object
                or document, and for that data object or document to be valid, a certain number of
                elements must be available in the collection. For instance, on an Add Course
                Document, one would expect the "courses" collection to have at least one course in
                it and to be less than the total number of courses a student is allowed to take in a
                semester or quarter. Therefore in the data dictionary entry for the data object, one
                adds a constraint as follows,</para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">A code snippet example follows:
                    </emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <programlisting> 1. &lt;bean name="AddCourseDocument" parent="BusinessObjectEntry">
 2.   ...
 3.   &lt;property name="collections">
 4.     &lt;list>
 5.       &lt;bean parent="CollectionDefinition" p:name="courses" p:label="Courses">
 6.         &lt;property name="minOccurs" value="1" />
 7.         &lt;property name="maxOccurs" value="74" />
 8.       &lt;/bean>
 9.     &lt;/list>
10.   &lt;/property>
11.   ...
12. &lt;/bean> </programlisting> 
            <para>Evidently, some students can take up to seventy four classes. Busy student.
                CollectionSizeConstraint is handled as a special type of SimpleConstraint (though
                only for use with CollectionDefinitions). Simply set the minOccurs and maxOccurs for
                the attribute and there will be an error if the collection size falls outside those
                limits. Naturally, either the minOccurs or maxOccurs can be left out for collections
                which should be unbounded in either lower or upper size limit.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Constraints on the client side</title>
            <para>One of the tasks that org.kuali.rice.kns.uif.field.AttributeField does in its
                Finalization stage is to convert constraints to JavaScript. For all of the following
                constraints, AttributeField automatically will push the Constraint to the client
                side: </para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Exclusive Minimum and Inclusive Maximum constraints </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>ValidCharactersConstraint </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>CaseConstraint </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>DependencyConstraint </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>MustOccursConstraint </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>PreRequisiteConstraint </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>When the user attempts to take action on the page, this level of Constraints will
                kick in - meaning that feedback comes much more quickly. These constraints will
                always be called when buttons such as save, submit, or approve - buttons where
                business logic would typically be evaluated - are clicked. They will also occur on
                onBlur's for most fields. </para>
            <para>There are, however, certain constraints which apply to multiple fields:
                CaseConstraints and PreRequisiteConstraints, to name two instances. Which onBlur
                issues the error among all of those fields? Generally, KRAD attempts to not give an
                error until the user has gone past a point where she or he could have prevented said
                error. For instance, if oneField has a DependencyConstraint on two other fields, but
                those two other fields render later and lower on the page, then KRAD will associate
                the validation with the last, bottom-most field of those the constraint applies to.
                In an interesting corollary, KRAD will issue an error on the onFocus event for a
                field which has already been visited if an error occurs with that field. </para>
            <para>Of course, the constraints are still run just the same on the server side once the
                page has been submitted; that way, if the user has scripting turned off, the
                constraints are still run and user input data gets validated. </para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Changing Error Messages</title>
            <para>All of the covered constraints are associated with standard error messages. For
                instance, if a "required" constraint has been violated, the user will get the
                following message: </para>
            <para>
            <programlisting> 
            Phone Number is a required field. 
            </programlisting> 
            </para>
            <para>This has taken the label from the attribute which violated the constraint and
                formatted that into the standard error.required message in the
                KR-ApplicationResources.properties file. </para>
            <para>With most of the constraints, the message can be overridden on the constraint, by
                specifying the "labelKey" property. For instance, a configuration like this: </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Code snippet example
                        follows:</emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <para>
            <programlisting>1.  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.MustOccurConstraint">
2.    &lt;property name="min" value="1" />
3.    &lt;property name="max" value="3" />
4.    &lt;property name="labelKey" value="error.must.be.able.to.track.down" /> </programlisting>     
            </para>    
            <para>Instead of using the standard message, the error message that is shown will be the
                message associated with the "error.must.be.able.to.track.down" key. This allows for
                a great deal more flexibility in what message gets displayed - though, the classic
                messages will still show up as they always did if nothing else is specified.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Constraint Architecture (building a custom constraint)</title>
            <para>The constraints that come standard with KRAD provide a lot of power through
                configuration.  For example, validating user input will be easier than ever. And the
                constraint sub-system of KRAD was built with the realization that even more
                constraints will be added in the future. Because of that, there needs to be an easy
                way for Kuali application developers or even future versions of Rice to add new
                constraints into the system. And so, there is. </para>
            <para>A constraint is a marker interface which is implemented by any Constraint bean
                (Java). These Constraint beans are purely configuration - they only hold what regex
                should be parsed against, if a field is required or not: basic information. The
                Constraint, in turn, is passed to an implementation of
                org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.ConstraintProcessor. </para>
            <para>Note that implementations of ConstraintProcessors can be genericized with both the
                type of value that the processor expects and the type of Constraint that the
                processor will work on. Most ConstraintProcessor implementations only genericize the
                Constraint, accepting any Object as a value to validate. </para>
            <para>ConstraintProcessors have four methods: </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>First, the getName() method returns the name that the constraint processor
                        holds. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The getConstraintType() method returns the implementation of Constraint
                        that this processor has the business logic for. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The isOptional() method returns a boolean: true if the processor can be
                        turned off in certain situations by another piece of code, false otherwise. </para>
                    <para>The only constraint which is currently optional is the
                        ExistenceConstraint; it is turned off by passing a false in the
                        doOptionalProcessing parameter of
                        DictionaryValidationService#processConstraints. </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The final method is the one that contains the ConstraintProcessor's
                        business logic: process. Process takes in DictionaryValidationResult, a
                        value of some type, the Constraint information to apply to the value, and an
                        AttributeValueReader if the value needs yet to be read; it returns an
                        instance of
                        org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.result.ProcessorResult. </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>ProcessorResults typically wrap instances of
                org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.result.ConstraintValidationResult. A
                ConstraintValidationResult encapsulates a number of possible outcomes for the
                validation, all generated by
                org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.result.DictionaryValidationResult. </para>
            <para>DictionaryValidationResult's addError method, for example, returns a
                ConstraintValidationResult which contains an error about a constraint being broken.
                Likewise, DictionaryValidationResult's addSuccess method indicates that the result
                of the constraint test was positive - the value passed the constraint. </para>
            <para>The other outcomes that DictionaryValidationResult can generate is addWarning -
                which gives an informative message that something is wrong with the attribute's
                value but which will not "fail"; addSkipped, which says that the value could not be
                tested and therefore the validation was not run; and finally addNoConstraint, which
                means that the constraint was configured in such way as to not run for the given
                value or at all. </para>
            <para>DictionaryValidationResults wrap ConstraintValidationResults in a way which
                provides easy access to these results in the data dictionary. These
                ConstraintValidationResults are passed back to KRAD wrapped within the
                ProcessorResults; the ProcessorResults then ensures that proper logic - whether that
                be the display of a message, the stopping of logic, or - if everything passed -
                carrying on with the transaction - occurs. </para>
            <para>That covers ConstraintProcessors. Now on to how they are called from within an
                application.   An implementation of
                org.kuali.rice.kns.service.DictionaryValidationService is responsible for checking
                all of the attributes which are passed in as part of a request into a KRAD form. The
                configuration of the default implementation of DictionaryValidationService has all
                of the ConstraintProcessors for KRAD passed into it.  See the following code
                snippets.  For example, if we assume the following 5 lines of code, </para>
            <para>
            <programlisting> 3.	  &lt;property name="collectionConstraintProcessors">
 4.	    &lt;list>
 5.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.CollectionSizeConstraintProcessor"/>
 6.		&lt;/list>
 7.	  &lt;/property> </programlisting> 
            </para>
            <para>Lines 3 through 7 above are the collectionConstraintProcessors - constraints which
                apply to collections. Here is where CollectionSizeConstraint - the constraint that
                handles the maxOccurs and minOccurs constraint attributes - goes. </para>
            <para>In line 5, the CollectionSizeConstraintProcessor is injected in.
                DictionaryValidationServiceImpl then matches the active Constraints on an attribute
                with the ConstraintProcessors passed in, and runs the logic against the constrained
                attribute. If the ConstraintProcessor acts only on a single attribute, it is passed
                into the elementConstraintProcessor property.</para>
            <para>ConstraintProcessors are supplied to engines which validate against constraints -
                DictionaryValidationServiceImpl, for instance - via ConstraintProviders.  Different
                implementations of the <emphasis role="italic"
                    >org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.provider.ConstraintProvider</emphasis>
                interface can exist; their job is to map an implementation of Constrainable (a
                simple interface all Constraints implement) to constraint processors, as can be seen
                in lines 29-79 below.  </para>
            <para>The usefulness of ConstraintProviders can be seen in the example. Lines 31-64
                shows the mapping for the AttributeDefinitionConstraintProvider - constraints which
                can be run against an attribute definition. Lines 65-77 shows that only one
                constraint - the MustOccurConstraint - can be run for
                ObjectDictionaryEntryConstraintProviders, meaning this is the sole constraint
                supported by data dictionary entries for entire data objects. </para>
            <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="underline">Code snippet example
            follows:</emphasis></emphasis></para>
            <para>
            <programlisting> 1. &lt;bean id="dictionaryValidationService" class="org.kuali.rice.kns.service.impl.DictionaryValidationServiceImpl">
      ...
      contents trimmed
      ...
 2.   &lt;!-- Collection constraint processors are classes that determine if a feature of a collection of objects satisfies some constraint --> 
 3.	  &lt;property name="collectionConstraintProcessors">
 4.	    &lt;list>
 5.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.CollectionSizeConstraintProcessor"/>
 6.		&lt;/list>
 7.	  &lt;/property>
 8.	  &lt;!-- Element constraint processors are classes that determine if a passed value is valid for a specific constraint at the individual object or object attribute level -->
 9.	  &lt;property name="elementConstraintProcessors">
10.     &lt;list>
11.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.CaseConstraintProcessor" 
12.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
13.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.ExistenceConstraintProcessor"/>
14.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.DataTypeConstraintProcessor"
15.				parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
16.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.RangeConstraintProcessor"
17.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
18.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.LengthConstraintProcessor"
19.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
20.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.ValidCharactersConstraintProcessor"
21.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
22.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.PrerequisiteConstraintProcessor"
23.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
24.		  &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.processor.MustOccurConstraintProcessor"
25.		        parent="mandatoryElementConstraintProcessor"/>
26.	    &lt;/list>
27.   &lt;/property>
28.	  &lt;!-- Constraint providers are classes that map specific constraint types to a constraint resolver, which takes a constrainable definition -->
29.	  &lt;property name="constraintProviders">
30.	    &lt;list>
31.	      &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.provider.AttributeDefinitionConstraintProvider">
32.		    &lt;!-- 
33.		        individual constraint resolvers can be injected as a map keyed by constraint type as string, or the default 
34.	            resolvers can be instantiated into the map by adding 'init-method="init"' to the bean declaration above
35.	        -->
36.	        &lt;property name="resolverMap">
37.			  &lt;map>
38.			    &lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.CaseConstraint">
39.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationCaseConstraintResolver"/>
40.				&lt;/entry>
41.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.ExistenceConstraint">
42.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationDefinitionConstraintResolver"/>
43.				&lt;/entry>
44.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.DataTypeConstraint">
45.	              &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationDefinitionConstraintResolver"/>
46.				&lt;/entry>
47.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.LengthConstraint">
48.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationDefinitionConstraintResolver"/>
49.				&lt;/entry>
50.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.ValidCharactersConstraint">
51.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationValidCharactersConstraintResolver"/>
52.				&lt;/entry>
53.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.PrerequisiteConstraint">
54.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationPrerequisiteConstraintsResolver"/>
55.				&lt;/entry>
56.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.MustOccurConstraint">
57.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationMustOccurConstraintsResolver"/>
58.				&lt;/entry>
59.				&lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.CollectionSizeConstraint">
60.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationDefinitionConstraintResolver"/>
61.				&lt;/entry>
62.	          &lt;/map>
63.	        &lt;/property>
64.	      &lt;/bean>
65.       &lt;bean class="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.provider.ObjectDictionaryEntryConstraintProvider">
66.         &lt;!-- 
67.			    individual constraint resolvers can be injected as a map keyed by constraint type as string, or the default 
68.			    resolvers can be instantiated into the map by adding 'init-method="init"' to the bean declaration above
69.			-->
70.	        &lt;property name="resolverMap">
71.			  &lt;map>
72.			    &lt;entry key="org.kuali.rice.kns.datadictionary.validation.constraint.MustOccurConstraint">
73.				  &lt;ref bean="dictionaryValidationMustOccurConstraintsResolver"/>
74.				&lt;/entry>
75.			  &lt;/map>
76.			&lt;/property>
77.		  &lt;/bean>
78.	    &lt;/list>
79.	  &lt;/property>
80. &lt;/bean> </programlisting> 
            </para>
            <para>Other ConstraintProviders packed into Rice at the time of this writing are
                CollectionDefinitionConstraintProvider - constraints which work for collection
                definitions; and ComplexAttributeDefinitionConstraintProvider, which supports
                constraints for "ComplexAttributeDefinitions" - data dictionary entries for
                attributes on one DataObject which are represented by another data object.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Business Objects? </title>
        <para>(Need direction on what of the KNS information should be copied here and what new
            information should be included or if this section is not needed.)</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>KRAD Class Libraries?</title>
        <para>(Need direction on what new information should be included here or if this section is
            not needed.)</para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Installing and Configuring KRAD</title>
        <para>Before developing with KRAD and after installing and configuring Rice, here are the
            additional steps you'll need to follow to configure KRAD before starting to develop an
            application.</para>
        <para>This information below assumes you already have Rice installed and configured for your
            database. Below are the additional tasks required to configure KRAD. For more
            information, see the KRAD Installation Guide and KRAD javadocs. </para>
        <para>(TBD - Revise the section heads below as needed and then populate with info.  Include
            instructions for setting up a Rice project, include assumptions for what is already done
            and not covered in the instructions, such as setting up all else needed for development
            environment - what are pre-reqs, what are co-reqs, etc..)</para>
        <section>
            <title>Configure Rice without KRAD (KNS Only)</title>
            <para>In some cases it may be desirable to only use the KNS without KRAD. For example if you're timelines push a conversion to KRAD out into the future, you may
            see some benefits with startup performance and with memory usage.</para>
            <para>You can override the kradApplicationModuleConfiguration bean to not include any of the files in the UIF folder. That is, you only need to include these files:</para>
            <programlisting>
&lt;property name="dataDictionaryPackages">
&lt;list>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/AdHocRoutePerson.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/AdHocRouteWorkgroup.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/Attachment.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/AttributeReferenceDummy.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/AttributeReferenceElements.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/BusinessObjectAttributeEntry.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/DataDictionaryBaseTypes.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/DocumentHeader.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/Note.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/NoteType.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;value>classpath:org/kuali/rice/krad/bo/datadictionary/PessimisticLock.xml&lt;/value>
&lt;/list>
&lt;/property>
            </programlisting>
            <para>Likewise, this can be done for the baselinePackages property on the dataDictionaryService bean.</para>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating the KRAD database tables / connections to data?</title>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>KRAD Configurer and RiceConfigurer?</title>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring Spring and MVC?</title>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Module Configuration  Loading Data Dictionary and OJB Files?</title>
            <para/>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Other KRAD Configuration Parameters?</title>
            <para/>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Building application pages using KRAD</title>
        <para>This information assumes you've already installed Rice.  Once Rice is installed and
            set up, you can use KRAD to build applications.   You can use the code snippet templates
            covered below, and you can look through the codebase itself or the sample application to
            see the code snippets for each of the KRAD features, and then copy/paste them to use in
            your developing application.</para>
        <section>
            <title>KRAD Templates</title>
            <para>Live templates contain predefined code fragments. You can use them to insert
                frequently-used or custom code constructs into your source code file quickly,
                efficiently, and accurately. </para>
            <section>
                <title>Loading the KRAD Templates</title>
                <para>The following have been tested in the IntelliJ IDE.</para>
                <para>Download the KRAD Templates File and place into the following location:
                    (ACTION/TO-DO -- Need to specify the link where we will maintain this
                    long-term!)</para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Windows: &lt;your home directory>\.&lt;product name>&lt;version
                                number>\config\templates </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Linux: ~\.&lt;product name>&lt;version number>\config\templates
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>MacOS: ~/Library/Preferences/&lt;product name>&lt;version
                                number>/templates</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Using Templates</title>
                <para>While in an XML file, type the template abbreviation and then the space key.
                    The completion key (setup as space) can be changed if desired by going to
                    settings-live templates. Your cursor will then be inserted into the location
                    specified by the template (marked with the $END$ variable).</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Available KRAD Templates</title>
                <para>
                    <table frame="none">
                        <title>Available KRAD Templates</title>
                        <tgroup cols="3">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="4.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry> Abbreviation </entry>
                                <entry> Description </entry>
                                <entry> Code </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>@</entry>
                                <entry>Inserts the expression placeholders</entry>
                                <entry>@{$END}</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>action  </entry>
                                <entry>Generates an action field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="ActionField" p:actionLabel="$END$"
                                    p:methodToCall=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>alink</entry>
                                    <entry>Generates an action link field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="ActionLinkField" p:actionLabel="$END$"
                                    p:methodToCall=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>be</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a bean tag</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="$END$"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>cc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a checkbox control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="CheckboxControl"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>cgc</entry>
                                    <entry>Generate a checkbox group control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="control"> &lt;bean
                                    parent="CheckboxGroupControl"/> &lt;/property> &lt;property
                                    name="optionsFinder"> &lt;bean class="$END$"/>
                                    &lt;/property></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>dc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a date control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="DateControl" p:size="$END$"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>fc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a file control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="FileControl" p:size="$END$"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>fg</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a field group</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="FieldGroup" p:label="$END$"> &lt;property
                                    name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>fi</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a field inquiry</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="fieldInquiry.dataObjectClassName"
                                    value="$END$ $CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="fieldInquiry.inquiryParameters" value=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>fl</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a field lookup</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="fieldLookup.dataObjectClassName" value="$END$
                                    $CLASS$"/> &lt;property name="fieldLookup.fieldConversions"
                                    value=""/> &lt;property name="fieldLookup.lookupParameters"
                                    value=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>fs</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a field suggest</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="fieldSuggest.render" value="true"/>
                                    &lt;property
                                    name="fieldSuggest.suggestQuery.dataObjectClassName"
                                    value="$END$ $CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="fieldSuggest.sourcePropertyName" value=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>group</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a group</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="Group" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list>
                                    &lt;/list> &lt;/property> &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>hfg</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a field group with horizontal layout</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="HorizontalFieldGroup" p:label="$END$">
                                    &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>image</entry>
                                <entry>Generates an image field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="ImageField" p:label="$END$" p:altText=""
                                    p:source="@#ConfigProperties['krad.externalizable.images.url']"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>input</entry>
                                <entry>Generates an input field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="InputField" p:propertyName="$END$" p:label="">
                                    &lt;property name="control"> &lt;/property> &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>link</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a link field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="LinkField" p:linkLabel="$END$"
                                    p:hrefText=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>mess</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a message field</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="MessageField" p:messageText="$END$"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>page</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a page</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="Page" p:title=""> &lt;property
                                    name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>prop</entry>
                                <entry>Inserts a property tag </entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="$END$" value=""/> </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>rc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a radio group control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="control"> &lt;bean
                                    parent="RadioGroupControl"/> &lt;/property> &lt;property
                                    name="optionsFinder"> &lt;bean class="$END$"/>
                                    &lt;/property></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>sc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a select control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;property name="control"> &lt;bean parent="SelectControl"/>
                                    &lt;/property> &lt;property name="optionsFinder"> &lt;bean
                                    class="$END$"/> &lt;/property></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>section</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a section group</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="GroupSection" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list>
                                    &lt;/list> &lt;/property> &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>sstack</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a collection group section with stacked layout</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="CollectionGroupSection"
                                    p:layoutManager.numberOfColumns="" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property
                                    name="collectionObjectClass" value="$CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="propertyName" value=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.summaryTitle" value="" /> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.summaryFields" value="" /> &lt;property
                                    name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>stable</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a collection group section with table layout</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="CollectionGroupSectionTableLayout"
                                    p:layoutManager.numberOfColumns="" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property
                                    name="collectionObjectClass" value="$CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="propertyName" value=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.sequencePropertyName" value=""/>
                                    &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>stack</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a collection group with stacked layout</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="CollectionGroup"
                                    p:layoutManager.numberOfColumns="" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property
                                    name="collectionObjectClass" value="$CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="propertyName" value=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.summaryTitle" value="" /> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.summaryFields" value="" /> &lt;property
                                    name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>table</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a collection group with table layout</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="CollectionGroupTableLayout"
                                    p:layoutManager.numberOfColumns="" p:title=""
                                    p:instructionalText=""> &lt;property
                                    name="collectionObjectClass" value="$CLASS$"/> &lt;property
                                    name="propertyName" value=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="layoutManager.sequencePropertyName" value=""/>
                                    &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list> &lt;/property>
                                    &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>tac</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a text area control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="TextAreaControl" p:rows="$END$"
                                    p:cols=""/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>tc</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a text control</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean parent="TextControl" p:size="$END$"/></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>view</entry>
                                <entry>Generates a view</entry>
                                <entry>&lt;bean id="$END$" parent="FormView"> &lt;property name="title"
                                    value=""/> &lt;property name="navigation"> &lt;ref bean=""/>
                                    &lt;/property> &lt;property name="items"> &lt;list> &lt;/list>
                                    &lt;/property> &lt;property name="additionalCssFiles" ref=""/>
                                    &lt;property name="additionalJsFiles" ref=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="viewHelperServiceClassName" value=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="defaultBindingObjectPath" vaue=""/> &lt;property
                                    name="formClass" value=""/> &lt;/bean></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry/>
                                <entry/>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                      </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Creating your own Templates</title>
                <para>See <link xlink:href="http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/webhelp/live-templates.html">
                    http://www.jetbrains.com/idea/webhelp/live-templates.html</link>
                </para>
                <para>Please post back and share!</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Converting KNS pages to KRAD</title>
        <para/>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>(other? E/R diagrams?, binding paths?, pointer to javadocs?)</title>
        <para/>
    </section>
</chapter>
