<!--

    Copyright 2005-2011 The Kuali Foundation

    Licensed under the Educational Community License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.opensource.org/licenses/ecl2.php

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.

-->
<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?> 
<chapter xml:id="TRG_KIM" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>KIM</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Terminology</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Principal</title>
            <para>A principal represents an entity that can authenticate. In essence, you can think
                of a principal as an "account" or as an entity's authentication credentials. A
                principal has an ID that is used to uniquely identify it. It also has a name that
                represents the principal's username and is typically what is entered when
                authenticating. All principals are associated with one and only one entity.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Entity</title>
            <para>An entity represents a person or system. Additionally, other "types" of entities
                can be defined in KIM. Information like name, phone number, etc. is associated with
                an entity. While an entity will typically have a single principal associated with
                it, it is possible for an entity to have more than one principal or even no
                principals at all (in the case where the entity does not actually
                authenticate).</para>
            <para>Entities have numerous attributes associated with them, including:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Names </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Addresses </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Phone Numbers </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Email Addresses </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Entity Type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Affiliations </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Employment Information </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>External Identifiers </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Privacy Preferences </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Group</title>
            <para>A group is a collection of principals. You can create a group using both direct
                principal assignment and nested group membership. All groups are uniquely identified
                by a namespace code plus a name. A principal or group is a "member" of a group if it
                is either directly assigned to the group or indirectly assigned (through a nested
                group membership). A principal or group is a "direct" member of another group only
                if it is directly assigned as a member of the group, and not through a nested group
                assignment.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Permission</title>
            <para>A permission is the ability to perform an action. All permissions have a
                permission template. Both permissions and permission templates are uniquely
                identified by a namespace code plus a name. The permission template defines the
                coarse-grained permission and specifies what additional permission details need to
                be collected on permissions that use that template. For example, a permission
                template might have a name of "Initiate Document," which requires a permission
                detail specifying the document type that can be initiated. A permission created from
                the "Initiate Document" template would define the name of the specific Document Type
                that can be initiated as a permission detail.</para>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">isAuthorized</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold"
                    >isAuthorizedByTemplateName</emphasis> operations on the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >PermissionService</emphasis> are used to execute authorization checks
                for a principal against a permission. Permissions are always assigned to roles
                (never directly to a principal or group). A particular principal will be authorized
                for a given permission if the principal is assigned to a role that has been granted
                the permission.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Responsibility</title>
            <para>A responsibility represents an action that a principal is requested to take. This
                is used for defining workflow actions (such as approve, acknowledge, FYI) for which
                the principal is responsible. Responsibilities form the basis of the workflow engine
                routing process.</para>
            <para>A responsibility is very similar to a permission in a couple of ways. First,
                responsibilities are always granted to a role, never assigned directly to a
                principal or group. Furthermore, similar to permissions, a role has a responsibility
                template. The responsibility template specifies what additional responsibility
                details need to be defined when the responsibility is created.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Role</title>
            <para>You grant permissions and responsibilities to roles. Roles have a membership
                consisting of principals, groups, and/or other roles. As a member of a role, the
                associated principal has all permissions and responsibilities that have been granted
                to that role.</para>
            <para>You can specify a qualification to any membership assignment on the role, which is
                extra information about that particular member of the role. For example, a person
                may have the role of "Dean" but that can be further qualified by the school they are
                the dean of, such as "Computer Science." You can pass qualifications as part of
                authorization checks to restrict the subset of roles to check.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Reference Information</title>
            <para>There are several collections of reference information managed within KIM:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Address type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Affiliation type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Citizenship status </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Email type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Employment status </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Employment type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Entity name type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Entity type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>External identifier type </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Phone number type </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Configuration Parameters</title>
                <table frame="none">
                    <title>KIM Configuration Parameters</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Configuration Parameter</entry>
                                <entry>Description</entry>
                                <entry>Default value</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                          <row>
                                <entry>kim.mode</entry>
                                <entry>The mode that KIM will run in; choices are "local",
                                    "embedded", or "remote".</entry>
                                <entry>local</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>kim.soapExposedService.jaxws.security</entry>
                                <entry>Determines if KIM services published on the service bus will
                                    be secured</entry>
                                <entry>true</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>kim.url</entry>
                                <entry>The base URL of KIM services and pages.</entry>
                                <entry>${application.url}/kim</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Services</title>
        <para>KIM provides 3 main service APIs with which client applications should interact. These are:<itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold"
                            >org.kuali.rice.kim.api.role.RoleManagementService</emphasis>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">org.kuali.rice.kim.service.PersonService</emphasis>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>These services act as client-side facades to the underlying KIM services and provide
            important features such as caching. It is always recommended that applications invoke
            these services instead of the individual services that they façade in order to take
            advantage of these additional features.</para>
        <para>In the next few sections we will look in-depth at these services. However, for more
            details, please see the javadocs for these services and the services they delegate
            to.</para>
        <sect2>
            <title>Using the Services</title>
            <para>All KIM clients should retrieve service instances using the KIM service locator
                class <emphasis role="bold">KimApiServiceLocator</emphasis>. This class contains static
                methods to retrieve the appropriate Spring bean for the service. An example of
                retrieving the <emphasis role="bold">IdentityService</emphasis> service
                is:</para>
            <programlisting>IdentityService idmSvc = KimApiServiceLocator.getIdentityService();</programlisting>
            <para>You would use a similar mechanism for retrieving references to the other KIM
                services.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>IdentityManagementService</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">IdentityManagementService</emphasis> is the service the
                client applications will interact with most frequently. This service delegates
                operations to these underlying KIM services:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">IdentityService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">IdentityUpdateService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">GroupService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">GroupUpdateService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">PermissionService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">PermissionUpdateService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">ResponsibilityService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">ResponsibilityUpdateService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para><emphasis role="bold">AuthenticationService</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">IdentityManagementService</emphasis> aggregates the
                service methods from all it’s underlying services into a single service contract
                which client applications interact with.</para>
            <para>Additionally, it also provides caching on top of these services to help increase
                the performance of service calls for the client application. To this end, the
                identity <emphasis role="bold">IdentityManagementService</emphasis> is actually
                deployed and resides within the client application and is not generally called over
                a remote interface (such as a web service).</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Principal Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve the principal ID for a user, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >getPrincipalByPrincipalName</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>KimPrincipalInfo info = idmSvc.getPrincipalByPrincipalName(principalName);</programlisting>
                <para>Note that KIM, by default, stores principal names in lower case; the PRNCPL_NM
                    column of KRIM_PRNCPL_T must store values in lower case. If your institution’s
                    existing identity systems do not handle lowercase principal names, then there
                    are three points to override that setting:</para>
                <para>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold"
                                    >org.kuali.rice.kim.impl.identity.IdentityServiceImpl</emphasis>
                                method <emphasis role="bold">getPrincipalByPrincipalName</emphasis>
                                lowercases the principal name sent in; depending on how principals
                                were integrated into the system it may not need to. Note that
                                    <emphasis role="bold">IdentityServiceImpl</emphasis> method
                                    <emphasis role="bold"
                                    >getPrincipalByPrincipalNameAndPassword</emphasis> does not
                                lowercase the principal name automatically.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold"
                                    >org.kuali.rice.kim.lookup.PersonLookableHelperServiceImpl</emphasis>
                                method <emphasis role="bold">getSearchResults</emphasis> also
                                automatically lowercases any principal name sent in; that behavior
                                may also need to be changed</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Finally, the file <emphasis role="bold">{Rice
                                    home}/impl/src/main/resources/org/kuali/rice/kim/bo/datadictionary/KimBaseBeans.xml</emphasis>
                                hold the data dictionary attribute templates for principal name as
                                    <emphasis role="bold">KimBaseBeans-principalName</emphasis>. The
                                    <emphasis role="bold">forceUppercase</emphasis> attribute is set
                                to false by default, but perhaps should be overridden to true, to
                                force uppercase principal names.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>
                </para>
                <para>Once these three points have been overridden, you’ll be able to use uppercase
                    principal names.</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Entity Default Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve the default information for an entity, use one of the
                getEntityDefaultInfo methods:</para>
                <programlisting>KimEntityDefaultInfo infoByEntityId = idmSvc.getEntityDefaultInfo(entityId);

KimEntityDefaultInfo infoByPrincipalId = idmSvc.getEntityDefaultInfoByPrincipalId(principalId);
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Reference Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve information about a type or status code, use the getter for that
                    type. </para>
                <para>Types in KIM are:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Address type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Affiliation type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Citizenship status </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Email type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Employment status </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Employment type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Entity name type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Entity type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>External identifier type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Phone type </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>For instance, to retrieve information on an address type code:</para>
                <programlisting>AddressTypeInfo info = idmSvc.getAddressType(code);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Group Membership Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve a list of all groups in which a particular user is a member, use
                    the <emphasis role="bold">getGroupsForPrincipal</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;GroupInfo> groups = idmSvc.getGroupsForPrincipal(principalId);</programlisting>
                <para>To determine if a user is a member of a particular group, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">isMemberOfGroup</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>if (idmSvc.isMemberOfGroup(principalId, groupId)) {
    // Do something special
}</programlisting>
                <para>To get a list of all members of a group, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >getMemberPrincipalIds</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;String> members = idmSvc.getMemberPrincipalIds(groupId);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Group Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve information about a group, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >getGroupInfo</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold"
                        >getGroupInfoByName</emphasis> methods, depending on whether you know the
                    group’s ID or name:</para>
                <programlisting>GroupInfo info = idmSvc.getGroupInfo(groupId);
GroupInfo info = idmSvc.getGroupInfoByName(groupName);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Checking Permission</title>
                <para>To determine if a user has been granted a permission, without considering role
                    qualifications, use the <emphasis role="bold">hasPermission</emphasis>
                    method:</para>
                <programlisting>if (idmSvc.hasPermission(principalId, namespaceCode, permissionName,
 permissionDetails)) {
    // Do the action
}
</programlisting>
                <para>To determine if a user has been granted a permission, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">isAuthorized</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>if (idmSvc.isAuthorized(principalId, namespaceCode, permissionName,
 permissionDetails, qualification)) {
    // Do the action
}
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Permission Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve a list of principals granted a permission (including any
                    delegates), use the <emphasis role="bold">getPermissionAssignees</emphasis>
                    method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;PermissionAssigneeInfo> people = idmSvc.getPermissionAssignees(namespaceCode,
 permissionName, permissionDetails, qualification);
</programlisting>
                <para>To retrieve a list of permissions granted to a principal, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">getAuthorizedPermissions</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;KimPermissionInfo> perms = idmSvc.getAuthorizedPermissions(principalId,
 namespaceCode, permissionName, permissionDetails, qualification);
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Checking Responsibility</title>
                <para>To determine if a user has a responsibility, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >hasResponsibility</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>if (idmSvc.hasResponsibility(principalId, namespaceCode, responsibilityName, qualification, permissionDetails)) {
    // Do the action

}
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Responsibility Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve a list of roles associated with a responsibility, use the
                        <emphasis role="bold">getRoleIdsForResponsibility</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;String> roleIds = idmSvc.getRoleIdsForResponsibility(responsibility, qualification);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Checking Authentication</title>
                <para>The <emphasis role="bold">AuthenticationService</emphasis> and related methods
                    on the <emphasis role="bold">IdentityManagementService</emphasis> are somewhat
                    different than the other services. The <emphasis role="bold"
                        >AuthenticationService</emphasis> is not typically deployed remotely (unlike
                    the <emphasis role="bold">IdentityService</emphasis>, <emphasis role="bold"
                        >GroupService</emphasis>, etc.).</para>
                <para>Instead, the role of this service is simply to extract the authenticated
                    user’s principal name from the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >HttpServletRequest</emphasis> and inform the client-side development
                    framework (typically, the KNS) about this information. KIM itself does not
                    implement full authentication services, but rather relies on other
                    implementations (such as CAS or Shibboleth) to provide this
                    functionality.</para>
                <para>The client application can then establish a local session to store the
                    information about the principal that authenticated. This will typically be used
                    in subsequent calls to the KIM services, such as making authorization checks for
                    the principal.</para>
                <para>The reference implementation of the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >AuthenticationService</emphasis> simply extracts the REMOTE_USER parameter
                    from the request and presents that as the principal name. This is often
                    sufficient for many authentication providers that are available. However, if
                    necessary this reference implementation can be overridden.</para>
                <para>There is only a single method on the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >IdentityManagementService</emphasis> related to authentication.</para>
                <programlisting>String principalName = idmSvc.getAuthenticatedPrincipalName(request);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>RoleManagementService</title>
            <para>In KIM, Roles are used as a way to associate principals, groups and other roles
                with permissions and responsibilities. It is therefore not a common or recommended
                practice to query for whether or not a principal is a member of a Role for the
                purposes of logic in a client application. It is recommended to use permissions and
                the <emphasis role="bold">isAuthorized</emphasis> check to perform this sort of
                logic.</para>
            <para>However, in some cases, querying for this information may be desirable. Or, in
                even more common cases, one may want to use an API to add or remove members from a
                Role. These kinds of operations are the responsibility of the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >RoleManagementService</emphasis>. Like the <emphasis role="bold"
                    >IdentityManagementService</emphasis>, this service is a façade which provides
                caching and delegates to underlying services. Specifically, it delegates to:<itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>RoleService </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Checking Role Assignment</title>
                <para>To determine if a role is assigned to a principal, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">principalHasRole</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>if (rmSvc.principalHasRole(principalId, roleIds, qualifications)) {
    // Do something
}</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Role Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve information on a role, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >getRole</emphasis> or <emphasis role="bold">getRoleByName</emphasis>
                    method:</para>
                <programlisting>KimRoleInfo info = rmSvc.getRole(roleId);
KimRoleInfo info = rmSvc.getRoleByName(namespaceCode, roleName);             </programlisting>
                <para>To retrieve the list of principal IDs assigned to a role, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">getRoleMemberPrincipalIds</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>Collection&lt;String> principals = rmSvc.getRoleMemberPrincipalIds(namespaceCode, roleName, qualifications);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Updating Role Membership</title>
                <para>To assign a principal to a role, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >assignPrincipalToRole</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>rmSvc.assignPrincipalToRole(principalId, namespaceCode, roleName, qualifications);</programlisting>
                <para>To remove a principal from a role, use the <emphasis role="bold"
                        >removePrincipalFromRole</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>rmSvc.removePrincipalFromRole(principalId, namespaceCode, roleName, qualifications);</programlisting>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Person Service</title>
            <para>The <emphasis role="bold">PersonService</emphasis> is used to aggregate <emphasis
                    role="bold">Entity</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold">Principal</emphasis>
                data into a data structure called a <emphasis role="bold">Person</emphasis>. A
                person is essentially a flattened collection of the various attributes on an entity
                (name, address, principal id, principal name, etc). This is intended to allow client
                applications to more easily interact with the data in the underlying KIM data model
                for entities and principals. </para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Retrieving Personal Information</title>
                <para>To retrieve information on a person by principal ID, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">getPerson</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>Person person = perSvc.getPerson(principalId);</programlisting>
                <para>To retrieve information on a person by principal name, use the <emphasis
                        role="bold">getPersonByPrincipalName</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>Person person = perSvc.getPersonByPrincipalName(principalName);</programlisting>
                <para>In order to search for people by a given set of criteria you can use the
                        <emphasis role="bold">findPeople</emphasis> method:</para>
                <programlisting>List&lt;? extends Person> people = perSvc.getPersonByPrincipalName(criteria);</programlisting>
                <para>In this case, criteria is a <emphasis role="bold">java.util.Map&lt;String,
                        String></emphasis> which contains key-value pairs. The key is the name of
                    the Person property to search on, while the value is the value to search
                    for.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>KIM Types</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Implementing Custom KIM Types</title>
            <para>KIM uses types to add additional attributes to objects (currently, groups and
                roles) and to affect their behavior.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Basic Service Requirements</title>
                <para>All custom type services must implement a sub-interface of <emphasis
                        role="bold">org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.KimTypeService</emphasis>
                    based on the type of custom type being created.</para>
                <para>Your custom type service class should extend the appropriate subclass of
                        <emphasis role="bold"
                        >org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.impl.KimTypeServiceBase</emphasis> and
                    only override the methods necessary to implement your custom behavior. Use the
                    methods in these classes as the basis for your custom code.</para>
                <programlisting>public class MyTypeService extends KimTypeServiceBase
 implements KimTypeService {
    // Do something


}
</programlisting>                
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method getAttributeDefinitions</title>
                <para>This method retrieves the map of attribute definitions related to a type. The
                    map is keyed on the sort code of the attribute definition.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method getUniqueAttributes</title>
                <para>This method retrieves the list of attribute names related to a type that
                    uniquely defines the principal. For any given principal, there should be only
                    one assignment (for example, a role assignment or type assignment) that contains
                    the particular set of values for these attributes.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method getWorkflowDocumentTypeName</title>
                <para>This method returns the name of the workflow document type that will be used
                    for the role qualifiers when you route objects with this type. If no special
                    document type is needed, this method must return null.</para>
                <para>Parameters: None</para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method getWorkflowRoutingAttributes</title>
                <para>This method returns the names of attributes that need to be passed to workflow
                    for route processing.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">routeLevel</emphasis> – The routing
                                level</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method validateAttributes</title>
                <para>This method performs validation on the attributes of an object. The default
                    implementation ensures that the values fit within type and length constraints
                    and, if there is a look-up table for the values, that the value exists and is
                    active. If null is returned or the map is empty, no validation errors were
                    detected.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">attributes</emphasis> – The attributes on
                                the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method validateAttributesAgainstExisting</title>
                <para>This method performs validation on the attributes of an object. The default
                    implementation does not do any checking but simply returns an empty map. If null
                    is returned or the map is empty, no validation errors were detected.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">newAttributes</emphasis> – The new
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">oldAttributes</emphasis> – The old
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method validateUniqueAttributes</title>
                <para>This method performs validation on the unique attributes of an object. The
                    default implementation ensures that the principal does not have another
                    assignment that duplicates the new values. If null is returned or the map is
                    empty, no validation errors were detected.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">newAttributes</emphasis> – The new
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">oldAttributes</emphasis> – The old
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Method validateUnmodifiableAttributes</title>
                <para>This method performs validation on the unique attributes of an object. The
                    default implementation ensures that these values are not being changed. If null
                    is returned or the map is empty, no validation errors were detected.</para>
                <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">kimTypeId</emphasis> – The ID of the KIM
                                type </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">newAttributes</emphasis> – The new
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">oldAttributes</emphasis> – The old
                                attributes on the object </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Group Type Service</title>
            <para>Classes that customize the handling of group qualifiers must implement <emphasis
                    role="bold">org.kuali.rice.kim.framework.group.GroupTypeService</emphasis>.
                This document contains a brief description of the methods specific to group types.
                Please refer to the Implementing Custom KIM Types document for information on
                methods common to all custom type services. Please also refer to the API javadocs
                for more details on the methods described here.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Java Class Information</title>
                <para>Your custom type service class should extend
                    org.kuali.rice.kns.kim.group.GroupTypeServiceBase and only
                    override the methods necessary to implement your custom behavior. Use the
                    methods in this class as the basis for your custom code.</para>
                <programlisting>public class MyGroupTypeService extends KimGroupTypeServiceBase
 implements KimGroupTypeService {

    // Do something
}
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Methods Specific to Group Types</title>
                <para>There are no methods specific to group types.</para>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Permission Type Service</title>
            <para>Classes that customize the handling of permission qualifiers and implement custom
                permission checks must implement
                org.kuali.rice.kim.api.permission.KimPermissionTypeService. This document contains
                a brief description of the methods specific to permission types. Please refer to the
                Implementing Custom KIM Types document for information on methods common to all
                custom type services. Please also refer to the API javadocs for more details on the
                methods described here.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Java Class Information</title>
                <para>Your custom permission type service class should extend <emphasis role="bold"
                        >org.kuali.rice.kns.kim.permission.PermissionTypeServiceBase</emphasis>
                    and only override the methods necessary to implement your custom behavior. Use
                    the methods in this class as the basis for your custom code.</para>
                <programlisting>public class MyPermissionionTypeService extends KimPermissionTypeServiceBase
 implements KimPermissionTypeService {
    // Do something
}</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Methods Specific to Permission Types</title>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method getMatchingPermissions</title>
                    <para>This method is called to find the permission assignments that are
                        applicable for the request. The implementation of this method must not
                        modify the parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">requestedDetails</emphasis> – The
                                    details in the request </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">permissionsList</emphasis> – The list of
                                    permissions to check </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method performPermissionMatches</title>
                    <para>This method is called by <emphasis role="bold"
                            >getMatchingPermissions</emphasis> to find the matching permissions. You
                        can override this method to customize the way that matches are made without
                        replicating the rest of the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >getMatchingPermissions</emphasis> method. The implementation of this
                        method must not modify the parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">requestedDetails</emphasis> – The
                                    details in the request </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">permissionsList</emphasis> – The list of
                                    permissions to check </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Responsibility Type Service</title>
            <para>Classes that customize the handling of responsibility qualifiers and implement
                custom responsibility checks must implement <emphasis role="bold"
                    >org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.KimResponsibilityTypeService</emphasis>.
                This document contains a brief description of the methods specific to responsibility
                types. Please refer to the Implementing Custom KIM Types document for information on
                methods common to all custom type services. Please also refer to the API javadocs
                for more details on the methods described here.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Java Class Information</title>
                <para>Your custom permission type service class should extend <emphasis role="bold"
                        >org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.impl.KimResponsibilityTypeServiceBase</emphasis>
                    and only override the methods necessary to implement your custom behavior. Use
                    the methods in this class as the basis for your custom code.</para>
                <programlisting>public class MyResponsibilityTypeService extends KimResponsibilityTypeServiceBase
 implements KimResponsibilityTypeService {

    // Do something
}
</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Methods Specific to Responsibility Types</title>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method getMatchingResponsibilities</title>
                    <para>This method is called to find the responsibility assignments that are
                        applicable for the request. The implementation of this method must not
                        modify the parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">requestedDetails</emphasis> – The
                                    details in the request </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">responsibilitiesList</emphasis> – The
                                    list of responsibilities to check </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method performResponsibilityMatches</title>
                    <para>This method is called by <emphasis role="bold"
                            >getMatchingResponsibilities</emphasis> to find the matching
                        responsibilities. This method can be overridden to customize the way that
                        matches are made without replicating the rest of the <emphasis role="bold"
                            >getMatchingResponsibilities</emphasis> method. The implementation of
                        this method must not modify the parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">requestedDetails</emphasis> – The
                                    details in the request </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">responsibilitiesList</emphasis> – The
                                    list of responsibilities to check </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>KIM Role Type Service</title>
            <para>Classes that customize the handling of role qualifiers and implement custom role
                membership must implement <emphasis role="bold"
                    >org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.KimRoleTypeService</emphasis>. This document
                contains a brief description of the methods specific to role types. Please refer to
                the Implementing Custom KIM Types document for information on methods common to all
                custom type services. Please also refer to the KIM API documentation for more
                details on the methods described here.</para>
            <sect3>
                <title>Java Class Information</title>
                <para>Your custom type service class should extend one of the following classes (all
                    in the package <emphasis role="bold"
                        >org.kuali.rice.kim.service.support.impl</emphasis>):<itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">KimDerivedRoleTypeServiceBase</emphasis> –
                                Roles with derived membership </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold"
                                    >PrincipalDerivedRoleTypeServiceImpl</emphasis> – Derived roles
                                with only principals as members </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para><emphasis role="bold">KimRoleTypeServiceBase</emphasis> – Basic
                                role implementation </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist></para>
                <para>Only override the methods necessary to implement your custom behavior. Use the
                    methods in these classes as the basis for your custom code.</para>
                <programlisting>public class MyRoleTypeService extends KimPrincipalDerivedRoleTypeServiceImpl
 implements KimRoleTypeService {
    // Do something


}</programlisting>
            </sect3>
            <sect3>
                <title>Methods Specific to Role Types</title>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method convertQualificationAttributesToRequired</title>
                    <para>This method converts qualifier attributes based on the needs of the role.
                        For example, a role that is based on campus might convert the
                        organization-based attributes <emphasis role="bold"
                            >“chart=BL,org=PSY”</emphasis> into the attribute <emphasis role="bold"
                            >“campus=BLOOMINGTON”</emphasis>. The implementation of this method must
                        not modify the parameter in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualificationAttributes</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifier attributes to convert</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method convertQualificationForMemberRoles</title>
                    <para>This method converts qualifier attributes for use by roles that are a
                        member of the role. The implementation of this method must not modify the
                        parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">namespaceCode</emphasis> – The name
                                    space code for this role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleName</emphasis> – The name for this
                                    role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">memberRoleNamespaceCode</emphasis> – The
                                    name space code for the member role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">memberRoleName</emphasis> – The name for
                                    the member role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualification</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the role assignment </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method doesRoleQualifierMatchQualification</title>
                    <para>This method returns <emphasis role="italic">true</emphasis> if the
                        qualifications applied to a role assignment match the qualifiers applied to
                        a role, <emphasis role="italic">false</emphasis> if they don’t match. The
                        implementation of this method must not modify the parameters in any
                        way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualification</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the role assignment </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleQualifier</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the role </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method doRoleQualifiersMatchQualification</title>
                    <para>This method finds the subset of member roles where the qualifications
                        applied to a role assignment match the qualifiers applied to a role. The
                        implementation of this method must not modify the parameters in any way. </para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualification</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the role assignment </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleMemberList</emphasis> – The role
                                    members to check </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method getRoleMembersFromApplicationRole</title>
                    <para>This method returns the list of role members based on an application role.
                        The implementation of this method must not modify the parameters in any
                        way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">namespaceCode</emphasis> – The name
                                    space code for the application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleName</emphasis> – The name for the
                                    application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualification</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the search </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method hasApplicationRole</title>
                    <para>This method returns <emphasis role="italic">true</emphasis> if the given
                        principal has this application role, <emphasis role="italic"
                            >false</emphasis> if not. The implementation of this method must not
                        modify the parameters in any way.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">principalId</emphasis> – The ID of the
                                    principal </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">groupIds</emphasis> – The complete list
                                    of groups in which the principal belongs </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">namespaceCode</emphasis> – The name
                                    space code for the application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleName</emphasis> – The name for the
                                    application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">qualification</emphasis> – The
                                    qualifiers applied to the search </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method isApplicationRoleType</title>
                    <para>This method returns <emphasis role="italic">true</emphasis> if the role as
                        an application role, <emphasis role="italic">false</emphasis> if not. This
                        means that the application defines the members of the role, not KIM.</para>
                    <para>Parameters: None</para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method principalInactivated</title>
                    <para>The Role Service calls this method when a principal is inactivated. This
                        allows an application role to perform any necessary clean up.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">principalId</emphasis> – The ID of the
                                    principal </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">namespaceCode</emphasis> – The name
                                    space code for the application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleName</emphasis> – The name for the
                                    application role </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method sortRoleMembers</title>
                    <para>This method sorts a list of roles being returned by <emphasis role="bold"
                            >RoleService.getRoleMembers</emphasis>. The list passed as a parameter
                        may be modified and returned rather than generating a new list. If the order
                        of the members is not meaningful, the parameter may simply be
                        returned.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleMembers</emphasis> – The list of
                                    role members to sort</para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
                <sect4>
                    <title>Method shouldCacheRoleMembershipResults</title>
                    <para><emphasis role="bold">RoleManagementService</emphasis> caches information
                        about role membership, based on the assumption that most roles are fairly
                        stable in terms of membership. Returning true from this method allows
                            <emphasis role="bold">RoleManagementService</emphasis> to cache the
                        results of membership calls (specifically <emphasis role="bold"
                            >principalHasRole</emphasis> and <emphasis role="bold"
                            >getRoleMembers</emphasis>). Returning false prevents caching. Roles
                        with highly volatile membership sets should return false from this method,
                        so that all membership changes are taken into consideration during
                        permission and responsibility calls.</para>
                    <para>Parameters:<itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">namespaceCode</emphasis> – The namespace
                                    code of the role which is being tested for allowing of
                                    membership information caching. </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">roleName</emphasis> – The name of the
                                    role which is being tested for allowing of membership
                                    information caching. </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
                </sect4>
            </sect3>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>KIM Database Tables</title>
        <sect2>
            <title>Table Name Prefixes</title>
            <para>The KIM tables in the Rice database are prefixed by KRIM, which stands for
                    <emphasis role="bold">K</emphasis>uali <emphasis role="bold">R</emphasis>ice
                    <emphasis role="bold">I</emphasis>dentity <emphasis role="bold"
                >M</emphasis>anagement.</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>Unmapped LAST_UPDT_DT Columns</title>
            <para>Many of the KIM tables have an additional column called LAST_UPDTD_DT (of type
                DATE in Oracle, DATETIME in MySQL) that isn't mapped at the ORM layer. Using this
                column is entirely optional, and it is unmapped by design. Its purpose is to aid
                implementers with tracking changes, and with doing data synchronization or extracts
                against KIM tables. The following sample PL/SQL script (Oracle only) adds to all the
                tables that contain LAST_UPDATED_DT an insert and update trigger to populate
                it:</para>
            <programlisting>DECLARE
    CURSOR tables IS
        SELECT table_name
            FROM user_tab_columns
            WHERE column_name = 'LAST_UPDATE_DT'
            AND data_type LIKE 'DATE%'
            ORDER BY 1;
BEGIN
    FOR rec IN tables LOOP
        EXECUTE IMMEDIATE 'CREATE OR REPLACE TRIGGER '||LOWER( SUBSTR( rec.table_name, 1, 27) )||'_tr BEFORE INSERT OR UPDATE ON '
            ||LOWER( rec.table_name )||' FOR EACH ROW BEGIN :new.last_update_ts := SYSDATE; END;';
    END LOOP;

END;
/
</programlisting>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
</chapter>
